<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Onoreto</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://steviepoppe.net/</id><updated>2017-09-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Going Abroad as a Research Student</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2017/09/going-abroad-as-a-research-student/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-19T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2017-09-19:blog/2017/09/going-abroad-as-a-research-student/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I’ve posted my last blog, and while I’ve had some ideas on new posts, I had to prioritize schoolwork, including finishing my graduation thesis and preparing my cultural exchange. Courtesy of my university I received the opportunity to study and live in Tokyo for a year and half at Chuo University with MEXT scholarship, as part of my Master degree in Japanese Studies. I’m writing this small blogpost exactly a week after arriving in Tokyo, in order to talk a bit about my university, my first impressions of my surroundings, and my personal experience with the application process for my scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Japan"></category><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Chuo"></category></entry><entry><title>Travels: One Week of Andalusia</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2017/07/travels-one-week-of-andalusia/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-06T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-07-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2017-07-06:blog/2017/07/travels-one-week-of-andalusia/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Having finished the final exams for my undergraduate degree in Japan Studies, me and my girlfriend decided to spend some time off by visiting a friend doing an internship in Seville, Spain. We used our time there to get a glimpse of beautiful Andalusia and were not disappointed by the stunning beauty of it’s architecture and nature, it’s fascinating history and last but not least, it’s wonderful culinary traditions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Travels"></category><category term="Spain"></category><category term="Andalusia"></category><category term="Granada"></category><category term="Cordoba"></category><category term="Sevilla"></category></entry><entry><title>New Song: IROHA 【いろは歌】</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2017/03/new-song-iroha-uta/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2017-03-12:blog/2017/03/new-song-iroha-uta/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;During my class on the classical Japanese language (&lt;em&gt;kobun&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;古文&lt;/span&gt;) last semester, I was introduced to a well known, Heian era poem named &lt;strong&gt;Iroha&lt;/strong&gt;, famous for using all characters of the Japanese syllabary exactly once&lt;sup id="fnref-1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn-1"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attributed to &lt;em&gt;Kūkai&lt;/em&gt;, founder of Japan’s Esoteric sect of Buddhism, the highly allusionary meaning of the poem stuck with me (also, I had to be able to recite it for my exam), and thus I wrote a short melody to help me memorize it properly. After my exam period, I spent some time getting acquainted with electronic music composition and expanded the melody into a proper song.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Music"></category><category term="Composing"></category></entry><entry><title>織田信長とアルベール一世：我々の国民の共有している歴史</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/12/oda-nobunaga-to-aruberu-issei/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-12-01:blog/2016/12/oda-nobunaga-to-aruberu-issei/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;私は先週、ブリュッセルで行われた日本語のスピーチコンテストに参加して、「ベルギー・日本友好１５０周年」のために歴史的なスピーチを発表する機会をいただきました。すると、参加者の他者が非常に高いレベルにあったし、質疑応答もやや恥ずかしくなっても、何とか第三位に入賞しました。このブログのエントリーは私が書いたスピーチの原稿です。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japan"></category><category term="History"></category><category term="Belgium"></category><category term="Speech"></category></entry><entry><title>Oda Nobunaga and King Albert - The shared history of our nations’ people</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/11/oda-nobunaga-and-king-albert-the-shared-history-of-our-nations-people/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-11-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-11-28:blog/2016/11/oda-nobunaga-and-king-albert-the-shared-history-of-our-nations-people/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;For this year’s Japanese Speech Contest in Brussels, I had the pleasure to prepare and hold a speech in honor of Belgium and Japan’s 150th year of mutual friendship. Despite some hickups and an incredibly high level amongst the other candidates (meeting all these excellent Japanese learners was both an extremely humbling experience as well as a perfect motivation booster for the coming years) I was awarded 3rd prize. This blog contains my speech’s English translation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japan"></category><category term="History"></category><category term="Belgium"></category><category term="Speech"></category></entry><entry><title>Japan Cultural Festival in Antwerp 2016</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/11/japan-cultural-festival-in-antwerp-2016/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-11-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-11-13:blog/2016/11/japan-cultural-festival-in-antwerp-2016/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This weekend the NHK Culture Center and the Embassy of Japan in Belgium organized the 30th edition of the Japan Cultural Festival, held in Antwerp in celebration of 150 years of friendship between our two nations. Together with a few classmates and upperclass students I had the honor and pleasure of joining this event’s staff of interpreter volunteers, spending my last 3 days assisting two incredible (and incredibly kind) artists convey their works to a large crowd of highly interested Japan aficionados.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japan"></category><category term="Belgium"></category><category term="Culture"></category><category term="Volunteering"></category><category term="Interpreting"></category></entry><entry><title>Writing a Musical?</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/writing-a-musical/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-10-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-24:blog/2016/10/writing-a-musical/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I cooperated with several other students at my music academy to write the music for a small local musical called “&lt;strong&gt;Dating&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;a musical for the highly educated&lt;/em&gt;” (a supposedly ironic, yet pretentious title I’m less than fond of, honestly). Being slightly unsatisfied with the end-result of my own compositions, I’ve since started rearranging them. I intend to describe the process in this little blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Music"></category><category term="Composing"></category><category term="Musical"></category></entry><entry><title>Narrating Newspapers: Weekly Vlogging as a Japanese 練習</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/narrating-newspapers-weekly-vlogging-as-a-japanese-renshu/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-10-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-17:blog/2016/10/narrating-newspapers-weekly-vlogging-as-a-japanese-renshu/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;In order to up my Japanese pronunciation and become more fluent in Japanese text recitation, I’ve started somewhat of a new hobby: vlogging in Japanese. I’ll (hopefully) publish weekly videos of myself narrating a newly posted newsarticle published on one of the mainstream Japanese newspaper websites, using a classic streaming-style set-up so any potential viewer can read along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, I’ve found it a fun exercise to try and translate the article as well as create subtitles (maybe I should try fansubbing some anime or drama one of these days, if I ever find the time, that is~).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Vlog"></category><category term="Video"></category></entry><entry><title>Anki Add-on: Japanese translations for Korean vocabulary</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/anki-add-on-japanese-translations-for-korean-vocabulary/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-10-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-15:blog/2016/10/anki-add-on-japanese-translations-for-korean-vocabulary/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;As anyone browsing my blog might have guessed, I’m pretty fond of using Anki for assisting in vocab acquisition, and thus use it for Korean vocabulary as well, using both existing sets and my own based on our textbooks&lt;sup id="fnref-1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn-1"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Having a broad base in Japanese, I thought it would be more efficient having a link between the two languages in my flashcards. In order to assist myself and other learners of both Japanese and Korean, I wrote an Anki add-on that adds Japanese translations of Korean expressions. &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Korean"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry><entry><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 4: Making the switch - J-J definitions in your vocab cards</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-4-making-the-switch-j-j-definitions-in-your-vocab-cards/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-10-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-02:blog/2016/10/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-4-making-the-switch-j-j-definitions-in-your-vocab-cards/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;You’ve been studying Japanese for a while now and reached a level of Japanese adequate enough to understand (simple) texts. Drilling new vocabulary has become a daily routine so entangled in your lifestyle you barely notice anymore. If you were to describe your current level of proficiency, you’d proudly present yourself as an intermediate level learner. Sounds familiar? Let’s take it a notch further by adding Japanese definitions&lt;sup id="fnref-1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn-1"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to our ankisets and reduce our dependency on English definition crutches!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry><entry><title>Travels: a week in Transylvania</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-24:blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;With the academic school year rapidly approaching, my girlfriend and I decided on a short last-minute trip out and booked ourselves cheap tickets to Romania. We spent the week traveling through the historic region of Transylvania, commonly associated with vampire folklore, and situated between the imposing Carpathian mountains. A rich history, ranging from a feudal agricultural culture to a post-war communist regime and more recently the shift to a capitalist mode of production, leaves plenty of marks in its culture, architecture and national mentality, and offers so much more than just touristic amusement. This short blog covers our itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Romania"></category><category term="Transylvania"></category><category term="Travels"></category></entry><entry><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 3: contextualize your vocab cards with example sentences</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-3-contextualize-your-vocab-cards-with-example-sentences/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-17:blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-3-contextualize-your-vocab-cards-with-example-sentences/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;One of the common pitfalls of learning Japanese vocabulary through ankicards is memorizing them loose of context. Perhaps you’ve found yourself in a situation having no particular problems recalling vocabulary whilst reviewing your anki cards, but less so when confronted with real-life situations. If that sounds familar, one way to counter this common problem would be to install an additional Anki add-on, and bring our vocab cards to a next level by adding Japanese example sentences and their translations. This blog offers an easy step-by-step tutorial on setting this up. Additionally, for those who’ve followed my previous tutorial, I add some extra code to combine the example sentence functions with the instant-import features of the firefox plug-in Rikaisama.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry><entry><title>Waarom Japanologie?</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/waarom-japanologie/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-14:blog/2016/09/waarom-japanologie/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;!-- PELICAN_START_SUMMARY --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoals velen in mijn richting ontstond mijn interesse in Japan al op jonge leeftijd onder invloed van het zogenaamde &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cool_Japan"&gt;Cool Japan&lt;/a&gt;: de verspreiding en globalisatie van Japanse popcultuur (muziek, televisie, games, enzovoort) die toen geleidelijk aan al doorsijpelde in onze nationale media. Het zou zelfs een interesse worden die zodanig groeide dat ik er jaren later mijn studiekeuze door liet beïnvloeden. Vaak krijg ik bij vermelding daarvan echter nog, zoals mijn klasgenoten ongetwijfeld kunnen beamen, een hoop verbaasde blikken toegesmeten en dé klassieke hamvraag voorgeschoteld: &lt;strong&gt;Waarom nu juist Japanologie&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japanologie"></category><category term="KU Leuven"></category></entry><entry><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 2: an efficient vocab mining set-up with Anki and Rikaisama</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-08:blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rikaichan&lt;/strong&gt;, and it’s Chrome variant &lt;strong&gt;Rikaikun&lt;/strong&gt;, have already been widely established as incredibly helpful tools for reading Japanese online. Nevertheless, one major function remained missing still: a seamless integration with Anki for efficient vocabulary mining. A recent extension of the original Rikaichan, aptly named &lt;strong&gt;Rikaisama&lt;/strong&gt; (it’s a &lt;em&gt;pun&lt;/em&gt;!), adds several new features including communication with the Anki API, &lt;em&gt;Sanseido Web Dictionary&lt;/em&gt;‘s J-J dictionary definitions, access to &lt;em&gt;J-Pod101&lt;/em&gt;‘s&lt;sup id="fnref-1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn-1"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; audiofiles, and several more&lt;sup id="fnref-2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn-2"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Concretely, this means audio playback of tens of thousands of words and expressions as well as easy integration of new vocab into Anki. Despite these incredibly useful features, Rikaisama remains fairly unknown and unblogged about. To counter that, this blog serves as a brief tutorial on setting up a Rikaisama/Anki environment as well as demonstrating some useful real-life appliances.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Rikaisama"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry><entry><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki (effectively) (in an academic context)</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-07:blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Those who know me might accuse me of preaching the memorization tool &lt;strong&gt;Anki&lt;/strong&gt; as the best thing that’s ever happened to studying, and they wouldn’t be that far off. Over the past year I’ve extensively integrated this software in my studies, with (to me personally) remarkable results in both productivity and academic grades. There are however, some pitfalls for the casual user to take heed of, and getting the full benefit of your time requires cultivating a proper mindset. As I mention Anki a great deal on this site, I decided on writing my own &lt;del&gt;&lt;em&gt;short&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/del&gt; guide on setting up and using Anki, as well as describe how I personally integrate it into my studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry><entry><title>Parsing Japanese Text in Markdown-Python for Stylizing and Semantic Purposes</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/parsing-japanese-text-in-markdown-python-for-stylizing-and-semantic-purposes/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-06T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-06:blog/2016/09/parsing-japanese-text-in-markdown-python-for-stylizing-and-semantic-purposes/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Due to my studies I (will) often use Japanese in my blog. As I gave some thought to typography and readability, I found the default appearance of Japanese text to be in stark contrast with the rest of my design.&lt;sup id="fnref-1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn-1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; To target specifically Japanese text, I wrote a small Markdown-Python extension for use in static blog generators as Jekyll and Pelican (or pretty much anything that utilizes Markdown-Python to parse Markdown in HTML) and embed such text in a span with the language attribute set to Japanese. The added, and probably more important bonus, aside from styling and semantic reasons, is that this method counters the negative effects of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Han_unification"&gt;Han unification&lt;/a&gt; in so-called CJK-languages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="markdown"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="fonts"></category></entry><entry><title>Visiting a Japanese Elementary School - An (Awkward) Experience to Remember</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-28:blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I, alongside several other second year Japanology students at my university, participated in a small “tell an interesting story” speech contest organised by Kobe University. This week we were informed the videorecordings of these had been uploaded on the contest’s website and were available for all to watch&lt;sup id="fnref-1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn-1"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. My story is a classic “awkward Japanese language mix-up” anecdote on a visit to a Japanese elementary school in Brussels, which I’ll touch upon in this post, alongside the embedded video. (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;日本の方、あまりよくないんですけど、もしよかったら見てみてくださいね！&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Video"></category><category term="KU Leuven"></category></entry><entry><title>Travels: an Icelandic Winter</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/travels-an-icelandic-winter/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-08-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-27:blog/2016/08/travels-an-icelandic-winter/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;After a long, stressful first semester exam-period, I spent my brief time off traveling to two completely opposite places I’ve been wanting to visit for a very long time: &lt;strong&gt;Rome, Italy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;: one of the coldest winter destinations I could imagine, but a place of stunning natural beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past years, Iceland has gained somewhat of a reputation for its hipster population and excellent music scene (both true), but its true strength remains in its wild, barren landscapes: sceneries that often came over very alien to me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is our brief itinerary through this beautiful country, with plenty of eye-candy to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Travels"></category><category term="Iceland"></category></entry><entry><title>Travels: Romance in Rome</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/travels-romance-in-rome/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-08-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-26:blog/2016/08/travels-romance-in-rome/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;After a long, stressful first semester exam-period, I spent my brief time off traveling to two completely opposite places I’ve been wanting to visit for a very long time: &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt; and the historic city of &lt;strong&gt;Rome, Italy&lt;/strong&gt;, cradle of one of the greatest civilisations ever. As a kind of early valentine, my girlfriend and I decided on this 4-day city trip to recharge our batteries and spent some much needed time together; looking back, it really did turn out a city that could only be described as a living, breathing open-air museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is our brief itinerary through this charming city, with plenty of photographs to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Travels"></category><category term="Rome"></category><category term="Italy"></category></entry><entry><title>Pelican Plugin: CSS-only footnote pop-up</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/pelican-plugin-css-only-footnote-pop-up/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-08-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-25:blog/2016/08/pelican-plugin-css-only-footnote-pop-up/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a classic staple in any writer’s toolbox and allows them to, in an unobtrusive way, citate sources or display additional information not directly related to the original argument. Yet I feel online footnotes, through the way they’re often implemented imitating printed media footnotes, come over quite counterintuitive by forcing the interested reader to disrupt his reading flow, and by failing to make use of today’s extensive webdesign posibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I royally use footnotes in my markdown writing workflow&lt;sup id="fnref-1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn-1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I figured I’d get acquainted with the Pelican documentation a bit and write a small unobtrusive CSS pop-up plugin to display these on hover for those devices that support it.&lt;sup id="fnref-2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn-2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Pelican"></category><category term="Markdown"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Footnotes"></category></entry><entry><title>Travels: roadtrip through the Deep South</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/travels-roadtrip-through-the-deep-south/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-24:blog/2016/08/travels-roadtrip-through-the-deep-south/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, me and a couple of friends decided on a summer roadtrip throughout the Deep South, the most southern states of the USA. As we have a shared history of playing in bands or writing music together, we thought it cool to purchase some second-hand instruments and travel through the most musically relevant of the USA states. This short blog covers our 3-week itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Travels"></category><category term="USA"></category><category term="Deep South"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World - About This Blog</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/hello-world-about-this-blog/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-23:blog/2016/08/hello-world-about-this-blog/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;!-- PELICAN_START_SUMMARY --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking on maintaining a blog for a while now and had already stacked up a pile of writings ready to post. A long summer break allowed me enough free time to sit down and get started on the technicalities; a process a bit more complicated as initially expected but worth it in the long run. This blog serves not as a tutorial on making one with Pelican (I’ll get to that eventually), but as a brief log on my reasoning and thought process during creation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pelican"></category><category term="blog"></category><category term="github"></category></entry></feed>