<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Onoreto</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/</link><description>@Stevie Poppe</description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>Narrating Newspapers: Vlogging as a Japanese 練習</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/narrating-newspapers-vlogging-as-a-japanese-lian-xi/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;In order to up my Japanese pronunciation and become more fluent in Japanese text recitation, I’ve started somewhat of a new hobby: vlogging in Japanese. I’ll (hopefully) publish weekly videos of myself narrating a newly posted newsarticle published on one of the mainstream Japanese newspaper websites, using a classic streaming-style set-up so any potential viewer can read along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, I’ve found it a fun exercise to try and translate the article as well as create subtitles (maybe I should try fansubbing some anime or drama one of these days, if I ever find the time, that is~).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-17:blog/2016/10/narrating-newspapers-vlogging-as-a-japanese-lian-xi/</guid><category>Japanese</category><category>Vlog</category><category>Video</category></item><item><title>Travels: a week in Transylvania</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;With the academic school year rapidly approaching, my girlfriend and I decided on a short last-minute trip out and booked ourselves cheap tickets to Romania. We spent the week traveling through the historic region of Transylvania, commonly associated with vampire folklore, and situated between the imposing Carpathian mountains. A rich history, ranging from a feudal agricultural culture to a post-war communist regime and more recently the shift to a capitalist mode of production, leaves plenty of marks in its culture, architecture and national mentality, and offers so much more than just touristic amusement. This short blog covers our itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-24:blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/</guid><category>Romania</category><category>Transylvania</category><category>Travels</category></item><item><title>Visiting a Japanese Elementary School - An (Awkward) Experience to Remember</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I, alongside several other second year Japanology students at my university, participated in a small “tell an interesting story” speech contest organised by Kansai University. This week we were informed the videorecordings of these had been uploaded on the contest’s website and were available for all to watch&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. My story is a classic “awkward Japanese language mix-up” anecdote on a visit to a Japanese elementary school in Brussels, which I’ll touch upon in this post, alongside the embedded video. (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;日本の方、あまりよくないんですけど、もしよかったら見てみてくださいね！&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-28:blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</guid><category>Japanese</category><category>Video</category><category>KU Leuven</category></item><item><title>Travels: roadtrip through the Deep South</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/travels-roadtrip-through-the-deep-south/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, me and a couple of friends decided on a summer roadtrip throughout the Deep South, the most southern states of the USA. As we have a shared history of playing in bands or writing music together, we thought it cool to purchase some second-hand instruments and travel through the most musically relevant of the USA states. This short blog covers our 3-week itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-24:blog/2016/08/travels-roadtrip-through-the-deep-south/</guid><category>Travels</category><category>USA</category><category>Deep South</category></item></channel></rss>