<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Onoreto</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://steviepoppe.net/</id><updated>2016-11-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Japan Cultural Festival in Antwerp 2016</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/11/japan-cultural-festival-in-antwerp-2016/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-11-13:blog/2016/11/japan-cultural-festival-in-antwerp-2016/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This weekend the NHK Culture Center and the Embassy of Japan in Belgium organized the 30th edition of the Japan Cultural Festival, held in Antwerp in celebration of 150 years of friendship between our two nations. Together with a few classmates and upperclass students I had the honor and pleasure of joining this event’s staff of interpreter volunteers, spending my last 3 days assisting two incredible (and incredibly kind) artists convey their works to a large crowd of highly interested Japan aficionados.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japan"></category><category term="Belgium"></category><category term="Culture"></category><category term="Volunteering"></category><category term="Interpreting"></category></entry><entry><title>Writing a Musical?</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/writing-a-musical/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-24:blog/2016/10/writing-a-musical/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I cooperated with several other students at my music academy to write the music for a small local musical called “&lt;strong&gt;Dating&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;a musical for the highly educated&lt;/em&gt;” (a supposedly ironic, yet pretentious title I’m less than fond of, honestly). Being slightly unsatisfied with the end-result of my own compositions, I’ve since started rearranging them. I intend to describe the process in this little blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Music"></category><category term="Composing"></category><category term="Musical"></category></entry><entry><title>Narrating Newspapers: Weekly Vlogging as a Japanese 練習</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/narrating-newspapers-weekly-vlogging-as-a-japanese-lian-xi/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-17:blog/2016/10/narrating-newspapers-weekly-vlogging-as-a-japanese-lian-xi/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;In order to up my Japanese pronunciation and become more fluent in Japanese text recitation, I’ve started somewhat of a new hobby: vlogging in Japanese. I’ll (hopefully) publish weekly videos of myself narrating a newly posted newsarticle published on one of the mainstream Japanese newspaper websites, using a classic streaming-style set-up so any potential viewer can read along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, I’ve found it a fun exercise to try and translate the article as well as create subtitles (maybe I should try fansubbing some anime or drama one of these days, if I ever find the time, that is~).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Vlog"></category><category term="Video"></category></entry><entry><title>Travels: a week in Transylvania</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-24:blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;With the academic school year rapidly approaching, my girlfriend and I decided on a short last-minute trip out and booked ourselves cheap tickets to Romania. We spent the week traveling through the historic region of Transylvania, commonly associated with vampire folklore, and situated between the imposing Carpathian mountains. A rich history, ranging from a feudal agricultural culture to a post-war communist regime and more recently the shift to a capitalist mode of production, leaves plenty of marks in its culture, architecture and national mentality, and offers so much more than just touristic amusement. This short blog covers our itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Romania"></category><category term="Transylvania"></category><category term="Travels"></category></entry><entry><title>Visiting a Japanese Elementary School - An (Awkward) Experience to Remember</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-28:blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I, alongside several other second year Japanology students at my university, participated in a small “tell an interesting story” speech contest organised by Kobe University. This week we were informed the videorecordings of these had been uploaded on the contest’s website and were available for all to watch&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. My story is a classic “awkward Japanese language mix-up” anecdote on a visit to a Japanese elementary school in Brussels, which I’ll touch upon in this post, alongside the embedded video. (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;日本の方、あまりよくないんですけど、もしよかったら見てみてくださいね！&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Video"></category><category term="KU Leuven"></category></entry><entry><title>Travels: an Icelandic Winter</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/travels-an-icelandic-winter/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-27:blog/2016/08/travels-an-icelandic-winter/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;After a long, stressful first semester exam-period, I spent my brief time off traveling to two completely opposite places I’ve been wanting to visit for a very long time: &lt;strong&gt;Rome, Italy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;: one of the coldest winter destinations I could imagine, but a place of stunning natural beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past years, Iceland has gained somewhat of a reputation for its hipster population and excellent music scene (both true), but its true strength remains in its wild, barren landscapes: sceneries that often came over very alien to me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is our brief itinerary through this beautiful country, with plenty of eye-candy to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Travels"></category><category term="Iceland"></category></entry><entry><title>Travels: Romance in Rome</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/travels-romance-in-rome/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-26:blog/2016/08/travels-romance-in-rome/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;After a long, stressful first semester exam-period, I spent my brief time off traveling to two completely opposite places I’ve been wanting to visit for a very long time: &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt; and the historic city of &lt;strong&gt;Rome, Italy&lt;/strong&gt;, cradle of one of the greatest civilisations ever. As a kind of early valentine, my girlfriend and I decided on this 4-day city trip to recharge our batteries and spent some much needed time together; looking back, it really did turn out a city that could only be described as a living, breathing open-air museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is our brief itinerary through this charming city, with plenty of photographs to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Travels"></category><category term="Rome"></category><category term="Italy"></category></entry><entry><title>Travels: roadtrip through the Deep South</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/travels-roadtrip-through-the-deep-south/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-24:blog/2016/08/travels-roadtrip-through-the-deep-south/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, me and a couple of friends decided on a summer roadtrip throughout the Deep South, the most southern states of the USA. As we have a shared history of playing in bands or writing music together, we thought it cool to purchase some second-hand instruments and travel through the most musically relevant of the USA states. This short blog covers our 3-week itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Travels"></category><category term="USA"></category><category term="Deep South"></category></entry></feed>