<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Onoreto - Personal</title><link>http://localhost:8000/</link><description>| Onereto</description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>Travels: Two Weeks in Mainland China (Changsha, Yunnan, Xi'an)</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2019/09/travels-two-weeks-in-mainland-china-changsha-yunnan-xian/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;Friday, 16 August 2019, approximately 2PM and approximately 2 hours of sleep. Calling that day a somewhat surreal and emotionally taxing day, might, in retrospect, be putting it mildly. I had just spent the night proofreading my graduate thesis for the thousandth time, buried in anxiety that a minor typo in a footnote still buried somewhere on the tenth page of my appendix would destroy my chances of graduation. Within the timespan of barely an hour, I retrieved the print copies of said thesis at a local print shop, handed them in at my university, shared a cup of coffee with some of my classmates—by now, my good friends—at &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; local coffeehouse hangout, checked my watch, and rushed towards the train-station. I had a flight to China to catch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the unwarranted stress, my five years as both undergraduate and graduate student at KU Leuven—enrolling at this university must have been the single most transformative decision I have ever taken—were now definitely at an end. To ‘celebrate’, I would now partake in a graduation trip to mainland China, accompanied by some of my closest friends while living in Japan. Both literally and figuratively a graduation trip, this trip was simultaneously a finale to my student life at KU Leuven, to my period of living in Japan, and to my youth in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A finale written by a director of slice-of-life situational comedy, that is; while contemplating all the above at the airport, a stoic voice announced that my flight was canceled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial plan was to take the plane to Hong Kong, spend the afternoon hanging out with a friend in Tsim Sha Tsui, and take a late evening train straight to Changsha, my initial destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, after my initial flight was canceled and making my connection in time seemed increasingly unlikely, I received a new itinerary to Changsha through connecting flights in the Netherlands and Shanghai. I would have to wait approximately seven more hours in the airport of Amsterdam, but I’ve had worse experiences and I could just take a nap after checking in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or so I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of hours afterwards I was informed that my flight to Shanghai was canceled. Instead, I was offered a direct flight to Changsha from Frankfurt, Germany the next day as well as a free stay in a nearby hotel. Oh well. Heading towards …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2019-09-10:/blog/2019/09/travels-two-weeks-in-mainland-china-changsha-yunnan-xian/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>China</category></item><item><title>Travels: Hong Kong &amp; Macau</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2019/05/travels-hong-kong-macau/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;At the end of my third semester in Japan, I took use of an extended school holiday &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; my last remaining months in Japan to plan a short trip to Taiwan and Hong Kong. During my stay I’ve had the pleasure to acquaint people from both regions and took this as the perfect excuse for some last minute sightseeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the most important trade and financial hubs in Asia and one of the most densely populated regions in the world; Hong Kong (香港) has a distinct international feel. While historically undeniably Chinese, Hong Kong was conceded by the Qing Dinasty to British rule after the First Opium War and remained a British colony until 1997, with brief control under the Japanese Empire during the Second World War. The majority of Hong Kong’s population have Cantonese ancestry and Cantonese remains the region’s main language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Hong Kong, like Macau, has some political independence under Deng Xiaoping’s “one country, two systems” principle (一国两制), both Macau and Hong Kong are officially part of The People’s Republic of China under the statute of Special Administrative Region. This in turn does lead to occasional political tensions concerning the extent to which mainland China should be allowed governance over Hong Kong. Living in Japan with mutual friends from mainland China, Hong Kong and Taiwan, I’ve had the opportunity to get a more nuanced take on both sides, but I feel this particular blog is not the appropriate platform for such a topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I spent the first half of my last-minute trip (around Taipei) mostly by myself, the second half of my trip (Hong Kong and Macao) was mostly spend with company and as a leisure trip to charge our batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a Hong Kong Airline flight from Taipei to Hong Kong International Airport (a short flight but possibly the most comfortable I’ve flown so far) and arrived at my hotel early in the evening. Similar to the &lt;em&gt;EasyCard&lt;/em&gt; in Taiwan and &lt;em&gt;Pasmo&lt;/em&gt; in Japan, I bought a RFID metro card, the Octopus Card, in Hong Kong. Rather than a card, this one was designed a cute bear key-chain, again applicable as general payment method in most convenient stores and some restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hong-kong"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#hong-kong"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ginza-square"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#ginza-square"&gt;Ginza Square&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stayed at Harbour Plaza Resort City in &lt;strong&gt;Kingswood&lt;/strong&gt;, close to Ginza Square. While this place looks …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2019-05-10:/blog/2019/05/travels-hong-kong-macau/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Hong Kong</category><category>Macau</category></item><item><title>Travels: Taiwan</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2019/05/travels-taiwan/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;At the end of my third semester in Japan, I took use of an extended school holiday &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; my last remaining months in Japan to plan a short trip to Taiwan and Hong Kong. During my stay I’ve had the pleasure to acquaint people from both regions and took this as the perfect excuse for some last minute sightseeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Island of Taiwan (governed since 1945 by the Republic of China, 中華民國) is an East Asian state located southwest of the Japanese Okinawan islands. Dutch colonization and consequent annexation by the Qing dynasty in the 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, as well as annexation and five decades of rule by by the Empire of Japan after the Sino-Japanese war of 1894-1895, have had a drastic impact on Taiwan’s demography, and presently the Taiwanese indigenous people make up only 2% of the population. Taiwan’s political status and its relation to mainland China, as well as domestic opinions on Japan, remains controversial topics. Nevertheless, the ease of entry for foreign visitors, as well as Taiwan’s scenic beauty and vibrant cultural scene have made Taiwan a popular destination for both mainland Chinese and Japanese nationals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due budget and time restraints I spent just two nights in Taiwan: centered around Taipei with one day trip to some of the more famous spots amongst Japanese tourists. I took an early flight from Tokyo’s &lt;strong&gt;Haneda Airport&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport&lt;/strong&gt; and arrived in Taipei Airport around noon. Preliminary preparations including currency exchange and the purchase of EasyCard RFID smart-card (with student discount) for the Taipei Metro transit system. Like Pasmo and Suica cards in Japan this card is widely accepted in convenience stores and retail outlets as well so I ended up using this as my primary means of payment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-1-taipei"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#day-1-taipei"&gt;Day 1: Taipei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a brisk short train ride I arrived at Taipei Station and experienced Taipei’s outside air and surroundings for the first time. It was by all means a beautiful, sunny day, but due the time of the year quite humid as well and I realized I’m not particularly good at dealing with tropical temperatures. Luckily my hostel, located near the National Taiwan Museum and Peace Park, was but a short walk from the station. On my way, I was struck by the amount of palm trees and the widespread use of motorcycles. I thought …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2019-05-07:/blog/2019/05/travels-taiwan/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Taiwan</category></item><item><title>Study-trip around Fukushima with Chuo FLP Seminar: Fukushima Hope tour</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2018/09/study-trip-around-fukushima-with-chuo-flp-seminar-fukushima-hope-tour/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;At the start of the new academic year in Japan, early April, I joined a music circle and formed several bands with other members of the circle. During the summer break, one of my band’s members invited me to join his class’ study trip to Fukushima; gaining first hand experience at methods Fukushima’s civilians are employing to revitalize Fukushima’s tourist industry after the 2011 earthquake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third largest prefecture in Japan, Fukushima is a northeastern region popular amongst Japanese not just as winter resort, but for its Japanese sake, food and many natural hot springs. Historically, Fukushima is known for it’s role in the last feudal Samurai war, the 1868 Bosshin War. Today however, the region remains heavily associated with the 2011 earthquake and subsequent nuclear disaster. An earthquake on 11 March 2011 led to a tsunami disabling most of the Fukushima Daiichi Nuclear Power Plant (located on the Pacific Ocean coastline of central Fukushima) and subsequent nuclear meltdowns due insufficient cooling. Despite strong criticism on government-level handling of the situation, much has been done on a local scale to restore Fukushima to its former level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A system quite common to Japan and less so where I’m from is the zemi system (derived from the seminar system in Germany); classes of around 10 students working together with the professor in interactive ways about a specific topic the professor is interested in. Usually groups become quite tight and occasionally join the professor for some food and drinks at night, as well as go on study trips (read: glorified city-trips). Earlier this year I had the opportunity of joining my German professor and three other students from KU Leuven studying in Japan for such a study-trip in Matsumoto, but this was my first opportunity doing in a full Japanese context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I was not part of the class, my friend and band-mate mentioned that that shouldn’t deter me from joining; in fact due the topic in question, input from a non-Japanese student would actually be highly appreciated, or so he assured me. Taught by Dr. Prof. Hosono (細野教授), the class itself (FLP, or Faculty-Linkage Program) is open for students of different academic backgrounds and often focuses on international issues. This semester, students worked on city-planning in disaster-struck areas (まちづくり) with a case-study of tourism in Fukushima.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center noshadow"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/32899526487/in/album-72157708568624144/" title="School"&gt;&lt;img alt="School" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/32899526487_bd1541218d_z.jpg" style="height:480px; width:500px;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The students worked around the concept of …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2018-09-27:/blog/2018/09/study-trip-around-fukushima-with-chuo-flp-seminar-fukushima-hope-tour/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Study-trip around Matsumoto</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2018/05/study-trip-around-matsumoto/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;Last April, I had the pleasure to my professor from KU Leuven on a study-trip to Matsumoto, accompanied by several KU Leuven schoolmates also present in Japan, as well as a Japanese historian and professor at Matsumoto’s Shinshū University, and his seminar students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our study-trip, we would first visit the &lt;strong&gt;Old System Matsumoto High School Museum&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Kyūsei Matsumoto kōkō kinenkan&lt;/em&gt; 旧制松本高校記念館) and received a guided tour to a tunnel in &lt;strong&gt;Satoyama&lt;/strong&gt;, said to be dug out by forced laborers during the last few months of the Pacific War. Later on we would visit &lt;strong&gt;Shinshū University&lt;/strong&gt; and hold an impromptu seminar on the topics covered that day, before the obligatory &lt;em&gt;nomikai&lt;/em&gt; (飲み会). On our second day, we would join our professor in the morning for brief breakfast and recap, before spending the rest of the day visiting the center of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A historic castle town and city in Nagano Prefecture, &lt;strong&gt;Matsumoto&lt;/strong&gt; is known as a popular destination for those looking to visit the mountain scenery or traditional hot spring resorts located around the &lt;strong&gt;Northern Japan Alps&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Matsumoto Castle&lt;/strong&gt; in particular is a well-known attraction due to its reputation as one of the most beautiful castles in Japan. Matsumoto is the birthplace of famous artist Yayoi Kusama, and in more recent history, Matsumoto has also attracted attention for having being targeted by doomsday cult Aum Shinrikyo in 1994, leading to eight deaths by a Sarin gas terror attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met up with a junior student of KU Leuven studying in Tokyo (&lt;em&gt;kohai&lt;/em&gt;, 後輩) for our highway bus from Shinjuku to Matsumoto, were we met up with a good friend and KU Leuven classmate of mine studying in Kyushu University. Our first evening was fairly uneventful as it was too late to explore the city. We ended up joining one of the Shinshū University students for some snacks and a few drinks in a Japanese-style bar, mostly catching up on life, before calling it a day and heading towards our hostel, close to Matsumoto Castle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="matsumoto-high-school-museum"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#matsumoto-high-school-museum"&gt;Matsumoto High School Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having met up with our professor and a KU Leuven PhD student currently doing research in Kobe University, we joined the Shinshū University group on a bus ride to our first destination, the &lt;strong&gt;Matsumoto High School Museum&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located in an impressive forest park, &lt;strong&gt;Agatonomori Park&lt;/strong&gt; (あがたの森公園), the museum is set in the historical Matsumoto High School, a Taisho-era …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2018-05-21:/blog/2018/05/study-trip-around-matsumoto/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Travels: Golden Week at Okinawa</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2018/04/travels-golden-week-at-okinawa/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;During this year’s golden week in Japan, I joined several of my friends for a short trip to Okinawa Island, the main island of the Okinawa prefecture. Due its pleasant tropic weather and beautiful beaches at this time of the year, Okinawa is one of the more popular destinations during Golden Week, and for us too a good occasion to finally visit Japan’s tropics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of 47 of Japan’s prefectures, Okinawa consists of over 100 small islands located between the island of Taiwan and Kyushu. Historically, the Okinawan Islands were home to the Ryukyu Kingdom and despite strong pressure from both Japan and China maintained a certain degree of sovereignty until complete annexation during the Meiji Restoration in the late 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. For this reason, Okinawa does feel culturally distinct to the rest of Japan even today and, based on my conversation with Okinawans, it appears many Okinawans take pride in their identity as being Okinawan first, over a national pride of being Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due’s Okinawa tragic role in the Pacific War (with war casualties accounting for over a quarter of its civilian population) as well as its subsequent U.S. occupation until 1972, there is a certain animosity amongst Okinawans against both the United States and the Japanese government. That animosity is further fueled by the continuous role of Okinawa as location for U.S. military bases, hosting approximately half of US military personnel in Japan. News stories of harassment by US military, as well as rising concerns over pollution, have led to a strong politically active base and frequent protests held against the Japanese government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more positive side, Okinawa is considered a tropical paradise and attracts tourists both Japanese and foreign. Okinawa’s population is often mentioned in international news as having long record-spanning lifespans and living healthy lifestyles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took a short local flight from Narita airport to Naha, the capital of Okinawa, followed by a convenient monorail ride directly to the city. Although we hoped to explore some of the nearby islands for scuba diving, we arrived during the rainy season and limited our activities to the main Okinawan Island. Our first days would be spent around the city of Nago, on the northern part of the island, while we’d spent the remaining days around the capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nago"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#nago"&gt;Nago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent the first night in a …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2018-04-27:/blog/2018/04/travels-golden-week-at-okinawa/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Travels: South Korea</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2018/04/travels-south-korea/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;As an undergraduate student at my Belgian university, I took several courses related to the Korean language and Korean history, which in turn made me quite eager to visit the country, given that I’d be living relatively close for the next year and a half. During my first semester studying in Japan, I was fortunate enough to make several good friends from South Korea. One of them had already left Japan by the end of the semester, and two of friends still remaining took the academic break in March as an opportunity to return to Seoul for several weeks, inviting me as well: an excellent way of celebrating the successful completion of my first semester in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Korea, officially known as the Republic of Korea, is an East Asian country east of Japan. Despite being sandwiched in-between China and Japan, the Korean Peninsula historically did well to repel repeated attempts of invasion and form an own distinct culture. With evidence of Korean settlements (confederacies) going back many centuries BC, and after hosting three major kingdoms (&lt;em&gt;Baekje&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Silla&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Goguryeo&lt;/em&gt;) as well as smaller confederacies for seven centuries, the peninsula first reached unification in the 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, leading to new peaks in cultural development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent history, Japan’s victory in the 1905 Russo-Japanese War led to Japanese occupation, with official annexation in 1910; until Japan’s defeat in the Second World War. The Korean Peninsula subsequently suffered the effects of the Cold War in an ideological proxy war between the North and the South. Although an armistice has been reached, the conflict remains far from solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topics of Japanese occupation and war crimes remain highly sensitive and are strong political weapons amongst nationalists in both countries. Nevertheless, the steady growth of Republic of Korea’s worldwide soft power (韓流 / 한류, the Hallyu Wave) has warmed the younger Japanese generations to renewed relations with the Republic of Korea. Studying the Korean language is rapidly gaining traction, and many Japanese citizens visit the Republic of Korea for tourism or as exchange students. Likewise, under influence of decades of Japanese soft power (“Cool Japan”), Japan is an increasingly popular destination for Korean tourists and exchange students.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When first planning my trip, I intended a fairly active trip covering Seoul, Sokcho and Busan, with a day-trip to Gapyeong. Right before departure however, my friends warned me …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2018-04-05:/blog/2018/04/travels-south-korea/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Korea</category></item><item><title>Going Abroad as a Research Student</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2017/09/going-abroad-as-a-research-student/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I’ve posted my last blog, and while I’ve had some ideas on new posts, I had to prioritize schoolwork, including finishing my graduation thesis and preparing my cultural exchange. Courtesy of my university I received the opportunity to study and live in Tokyo for a year and half at Chuo University with MEXT scholarship, as part of my Master degree in Japanese Studies. I’m writing this small blog post exactly a week after arriving in Tokyo, in order to talk a bit about my university, my first impressions of my surroundings, and my personal experience with the application process for my scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="chuo-universty"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#chuo-universty"&gt;Chuo Universty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chuo University (中央大学) is a private-run university with several campuses spread throughout Tokyo, and containing a plethora of faculties, graduate schools and researchers. It’s mostly known for its legal studies, dating back to the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, and has many well known alumni ranging from economics and politics (including former Prime Minister Toshiki Kaifu) to arts and letters (including popular director Makoto Shinkai of &lt;em&gt;Kimi no Na wa&lt;/em&gt; 君の名は。 fame).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m studying at the largest campus, Tama Campus, which is located in Hachioji: a city in the western portion of Tokyo, and about an hour by public transport to more central parts of Tokyo such as Shinjuku. As a research student I have some liberty in the classes I can take up; they’re either thematically similar to master classes of Japanese Studies at Leuven, or support the global understanding necessary to write my master thesis. Thus I’ll mostly be taking classes from the Graduate School of Letters (specifically the Socio-Informatics course) and Graduate School of Policy Studies, as well as an introduction to Japanese Law from the Graduate School of Law. If time permits, I hope to continue my Korean studies as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/36534953573/in/album-72157686137772481/" title="Tama Campus"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tama Campus" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4348/36534953573_df9869ea32_k.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty overwhelmed by the size of the campus. It has eleven main buildings, along with a variety of student facilities for after-school activities such as clubs (クラブ) and circles (サークル), sport rooms, several restaurants, etc. I haven’t gotten the hang of it yet and I’m sure I’ll get lost &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; over the next year and a half. I’m pleased to see these amount of facilities available however, and I really look forward to the start of this school semester (21th of September). Although …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2017-09-19:/blog/2017/09/going-abroad-as-a-research-student/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Japan</category><category>Blog</category><category>Chuo</category></item><item><title>Travels: One Week of Andalusia</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2017/07/travels-one-week-of-andalusia/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Having finished the final exams for my undergraduate degree in Japan Studies, we decided to spend some time off by visiting a close friend doing an internship in Seville, Spain. We used our time there to get a glimpse of beautiful Andalusia and were not disappointed by the stunning beauty of its architecture and nature, its fascinating history and, importantly, its wonderful culinary traditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andalusia, an autonomous region at the most southward point of Spain, has had due to it’s geographical location - a gateway between Europe and Africa - strong ties with various cultures such as the Phoenicians, Greeks, Romans, Byzantines, Jews and the Muslim Moors. These cultural influences have, of course, left a strong mark on the development of Andalusia, both in its national identity and through cultural markers such as architecture, music, dance, and cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our friend let us stay in her apartment in Nervion, the shopping district of Seville, approximately 20 minutes by foot from the historical center. Taking her apartment as starting point, we arranged most of our activities around Seville and nearby regions. It was quite a pleasant surprise to be located only a short walk from one of the more appraised &lt;em&gt;tapa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; restaurants in Sevilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/35374810940/in/album-72157683544111201/" title="Tapas"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tapas" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4256/35374810940_814fd8d149_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent most of our time in Seville, but used a local carpooling service for two day-trips, to Granada and Ronda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="seville"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#seville"&gt;Seville&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/35630910381/in/album-72157683544111201/" title="Sevilla Street"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sevilla Street" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4125/35630910381_0fdf11d88c_b.jpg" style="height:500px;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seville, the capital of Andalusia and Spain’s 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; largest city, flourished in trade during the middle ages and thus has a well-developed and maintained city center. Amongst our highlights there was the 15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century &lt;strong&gt;Cathedral of Seville&lt;/strong&gt;, the third largest church in the world, built over a late twelfth century mosque. It contains the remains of the historical controversial figure Christopher Columbus. The area around the cathedral (commonly known as the &lt;strong&gt;Jewish Quarter&lt;/strong&gt;) is considered the historical center of Seville and is a delight to stroll through with it’s small cobblestone streets and variety of boutiques and restaurants. Our friend introduced us to a small but crowded bar with late-night flamenco performances, a sure marker of the vibrant nightlife in Seville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/35593087592/in/album-72157683544111201/" title="Seville Cathedral"&gt;&lt;img alt="Seville Cathedral" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4097/35593087592_87eceffb24_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To us, the most impressive site was &lt;strong&gt;Réal Alcázar&lt;/strong&gt;, UNESCO World Heritage Site and palace built in Moorish architectural style across the 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; to 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. It has recently gained new fame as setting of Dorne in the hit-series Game of Thrones. During our trip, we …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2017-07-06:/blog/2017/07/travels-one-week-of-andalusia/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Spain</category><category>Andalusia</category><category>Granada</category><category>Cordoba</category><category>Sevilla</category></item><item><title>New Song: IROHA 【いろは歌】</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2017/03/new-song-iroha-uta/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;During a course on classical Japanese (&lt;em&gt;kobun&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;古文&lt;/span&gt;) last semester, we were introduced to a particularly well-known Heian-era poem titled &lt;strong&gt;Iroha&lt;/strong&gt; – famous for using all characters of the Japanese syllabary exactly once&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attributed to &lt;em&gt;Kūkai&lt;/em&gt; (founder of the Japanese Esoteric sect of Buddhism), the layered meaning of the poem (and the fact we had to be able to recite it for my exam) struck a chord with me. I wrote a short melody to help me memorize it properly and, after my exam period, spent some time getting acquainted with electronic music composition in order to further expand upon that melody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="_1"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#_1"&gt;&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;いろは歌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xh7Nx-8-RZg" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="640"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I begin most of my compositions by playing the piano. I tried to create an otherwordly, esoteric vibe through constant shifts in modulation and relying on ninths and dissonance in the melody. Once I had my base backing track done, I spread the different lines across piano, pan drum and some ambient pads, wrote a sparse drum-track using chimes, woodblocks and taiko and practically drowned the whole in reverb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vocalist’s thin, airy voice works especially well for the kind of setting I hoped to express. The second half in particular used heavily distorted samples of her voice in an attempt to &lt;em&gt;derail&lt;/em&gt; and build up tension in similar fashion (hopefully) to the original poem. It also allowed me to become better acquainted with filters and techniques commonly used in electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several authors debated a hidden message in the original Man’yō-gana version of the text, by putting together the last syllable of each line, which could be read as &lt;em&gt;toka [toga] nakute shisu&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;咎無くて死す&lt;/span&gt;, ‘die without sin’). I tried to incorporate this in the song as some form of hidden message, using distorted whispers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="[background]" class="fcenter" src="http://localhost:8000/images/music/full_bg_smaller.jpg" title="[background]"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the YouTube video I created a wallpaper using a photograph I once took at the grave of Tokugawa Ieyasu in Nikko. At the time of the picture, a typhoon rapidly approached our region and due to heavy rainfall, we were practically alone. Nonetheless, the storm’s influence on the ancient cryptomeria forest and the bronze urn of Tokugawa Ieyasu left for a breathtaking and very humbling sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a bit of editing and used several free Japanese calligraphy fonts to display the contents of the poem. I found the english translation, by Esoteric Buddhist specialist Prof. Dr. Ryūichi Abe, to be particularly poetic and fitting for the kind …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2017-03-12:/blog/2017/03/new-song-iroha-uta/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Music</category><category>Composing</category></item><item><title>Japan Cultural Festival in Antwerp 2016</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2016/11/japan-cultural-festival-in-antwerp-2016/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="poster" class="border right" src="http://localhost:8000/images/tsuuyaku/poster.jpg" title="poster"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend the NHK Culture Center and the Embassy of Japan in Belgium organized the 30&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; edition of the Japan Cultural Festival, held in Antwerp in celebration of 150 years of friendship between our two nations. Together with a few classmates and upper class students I had the honor and pleasure of joining this event’s staff of interpreter volunteers, spending my last 3 days assisting two incredible (and incredibly kind) artists convey their works to a large crowd of highly interested Japan aficionados.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The festival included a wide variety of exhibitions, demonstrations and performances related to Japanese artistry: dances, drum performances, calligraphy, clothing, tea ceremonies, etc. During the festival I was responsible for a stand on artistic calligraphy and a Japanese embroidery technique called &lt;em&gt;sashiko&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;刺し子&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, two fields of artistry I had no prior experience in and thus learned a lot about through my interpreting those 3 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interpreting as barely just a third year student was quite an experience. The amount of technical terms related to embroidery processionally made it pretty difficult to accurately translate everything in real time but I think I somehow managed to convey the overall meaning most of the time. Something that quite surprised me was how engrossed I got in my interpreting as well as the group sense we fostered. I felt a certain sense of pride every time guests complimented on our booth’s exhibitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that surprised me was the high interest in these art forms I originally thought maybe to be too specific to draw large crowds. Both days of the event were highly visited and left us drowned in work to the point we barely had time to eat a snack at noon. At the end everyone was exhausted, but it was definitely a good kind of exhaustion, and spending the evening together having dinner in the city center of my hometown made it all the more a pleasant memory!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="festival3" class="border fcenter" src="http://localhost:8000/images/tsuuyaku/festival3.jpg" title="festival3"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:center; font-size: 85%;"&gt;(me and the two artists, Hashimoto Shiori and Chiharu Minato, at our booth)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="festival1" class="border fcenter" src="http://localhost:8000/images/tsuuyaku/festival1.jpg" title="festival1"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:center; font-size: 85%;"&gt;(The opening ceremony was extremely formal, but I was pleased to occasionally perceive a little joke in the Japanese speeches that didn’t translate well in Dutch)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="festival2" class="border fcenter" src="http://localhost:8000/images/tsuuyaku/festival2.jpg" title="festival2"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:center; font-size: 85%;"&gt;(Alas, due to a dead cellphone battery I wasn’t able to take a lot of pictures of the events.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2016-11-13:/blog/2016/11/japan-cultural-festival-in-antwerp-2016/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Japan</category><category>Belgium</category><category>Culture</category><category>Volunteering</category><category>Interpreting</category></item><item><title>Writing a Musical?</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2016/10/writing-a-musical/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I cooperated with several other students at my music academy to write the music for a small local musical called “&lt;strong&gt;Dating&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;a musical for the highly educated&lt;/em&gt;” (a supposedly ironic, yet pretentious title I’m less than fond of, honestly). Being slightly unsatisfied with the end-result of my own compositions, I’ve since started rearranging them. I intend to describe the process in this little blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-idea"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-idea"&gt;The Idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the wings of our arrangement teacher, we collaborated with the Word &amp;amp; Song division of our music academy and the Kontich Orchestra. The W&amp;amp;S division provided the actors, came up with a general concept and devised a tentative track list as well as additional background information we were to use as guidelines in our compositions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We held frequent meetings with the Kontich Orchestra for rehearsals, further fine tuning, and to get a better feel of each musician’s capacities and the sound of their instrument. In the end, due time limits, I only contributed two songs but I’m happy to have been part of the project despite the in my opinion somewhat pretentious premise. The following flyer was distributed around town:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="folder" class="border fcenter" src="http://localhost:8000/images/musical/folder.jpg" title="folder"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-story"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-story"&gt;The Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Dating&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;a musical for the highly educated&lt;/em&gt;” involves a group of supposedly less than highly educated adults from out of town who’ve met up for a double date using a popular dating site. A couple of teenagers, obsessed with selfies and being young (the average age of the writing team was about 50 years by the way) take note of this and decide to ruin their fun by pretending to be each others date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere near the end, things get heated up so much that a member of the audience, using classic “&lt;em&gt;breaking the fourth wall&lt;/em&gt;“&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; techniques, calls the musical to an abrupt end by spouting some idealistic wishes on the concepts of love and relationships. At this stage, &lt;strong&gt;Bacchus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Cupido&lt;/strong&gt; make their entrance in a rather absurd fashion and save the day by convincing the audience that yes, it’s important to believe in love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I just wrote the music! I take no part in this plot!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-songs"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-songs"&gt;The Songs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-banana-caves"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-banana-caves"&gt;The Banana Caves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song is played right at the start of the second half of the musical. As the cast enters the bar and spends a while having a few drinks too many before breaking out into dance, my …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2016-10-24:/blog/2016/10/writing-a-musical/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Music</category><category>Composing</category><category>Musical</category></item><item><title>Narrating Newspapers: Weekly Vlogging as a Japanese 練習</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2016/10/narrating-newspapers-weekly-vlogging-as-a-japanese-renshu/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: currently on hold due my upcoming exams. Priorities!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to up my Japanese pronunciation and become more fluent in Japanese text recitation, I’ve tried getting acquainted with vlogging in Japanese. I’ll (hopefully) publish weekly videos of myself narrating a newly posted news article published on one of the mainstream Japanese newspaper websites, using a classic streaming-style set-up so any potential viewer can read along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, I’ve found it a fun exercise to try and translate the article as well as create subtitles (maybe I should try fan-subbing some anime or drama one of these days, if I ever find the time, that is~).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this will become a weekly thing I won’t be posting new blog-articles for every single video I do, but feel free to follow me on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PoppeStevie"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or subscribe to my &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-wW8gg1lGVn99X9ue6_eVA"&gt;YT channel&lt;/a&gt;. For now it’s limited to these narrations and (&lt;em&gt;wip&lt;/em&gt;) music, but actually I’ve always wanted to try actual vlogging and/or podcasts.... Maybe it’ll happen one day (when I’m studying abroadかな～).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="videos"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#videos"&gt;Videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="week-9"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#week-9"&gt;Week 9: &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;殺人未遂容疑&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Mainichi Shumbun article is another one related to JR. A guy tried to push two people of train platforms in Osaka and is now wanted for double attempted homicide. The original article can be found on &lt;em&gt;Mainichi Shimbun&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="http://mainichi.jp/articles/20161212/k00/00m/040/075000c#"&gt;線路に６３歳女性突き落とす　男逃走　大阪&lt;/a&gt;). As usual I’ve included English subtitles. &lt;em&gt;(22/11/16)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qknMcYiQ2tk" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="640"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="week-8-jr"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#week-8-jr"&gt;Week 8: &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;ＪＲ山手線&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week’s article is on a small accident on the JR Yamata line caused by a overheated cellphone charger. The original article can be found on &lt;em&gt;Mainichi Shimbun&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="http://mainichi.jp/articles/20161205/k00/00m/040/029000c"&gt;ＪＲ山手線 車内で携帯充電器が発煙&lt;/a&gt;). As usual I’ve included English subtitles. &lt;em&gt;(22/11/16)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O6KXLcDbeRY" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="640"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="week-7"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#week-7"&gt;Week 7: &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;織田信長とアルベール一世&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due the Brussels Japanese Speech Contest this weekend I didn’t record any news articles, but instead uploaded a recording of my speech entry. I’ve posted the original speech in Japanese, as well as an English translation on these blogs: &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/12/oda-nobunaga-to-aruberu-issei/"&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/11/oda-nobunaga-and-king-albert-the-shared-history-of-our-nations-people/"&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;em&gt;(27/11/16)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cHx3xUfM_DY" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="640"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="week-6-ptsd"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#week-6-ptsd"&gt;Week 6: &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;ＰＴＳＤ治療&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one’s an article on a possible treatment to PTSD. The original article can be found on &lt;em&gt;Asahi Shimbun&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.asahi.com/articles/ASJCM5GVTJCMULBJ00D.html"&gt;恐怖の記憶、書き換える技術開発　ＰＴＳＤ治療に効果か&lt;/a&gt;). As usual I’ve included English subtitles. &lt;em&gt;(22/11/16)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K7rAC7NcusY" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="640"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="week-5"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#week-5"&gt;Week 5: &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;トランプ氏&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I’m reading a Nikkei article on Trump’s first public interview since his election as President of the USA. The original article can be found on &lt;em&gt;Sankei News&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.nikkei.com/article/DGXLASGM14H0L_U6A111C1EAF000/?dg=1"&gt;&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;トランプ氏、&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;&lt;ruby&gt;&lt;rb&gt;犯罪歴 …&lt;/rb&gt;&lt;/ruby&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2016-10-17:/blog/2016/10/narrating-newspapers-weekly-vlogging-as-a-japanese-renshu/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Vlog</category><category>Video</category></item><item><title>Travels: a week in Transylvania</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;With the academic school year rapidly approaching, we decided on a short last-minute trip abroad and booked tickets to Romania. We spent spent a week,traveling through the historic region of Transylvania, commonly associated with vampire folklore, and situated between the imposing Carpathian mountains. A rich history, ranging from a feudal agricultural culture to a post-war communist regime and following shift to a capitalist mode of production, leaves a very layered culture represented in all aspects from architecture to national mentality. This short blog covers our itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, Transylvania, a traditionally more agricultural region, has been conquered by plenty of nations, including the Roman Empire, Bulgaria, Hungary, the Ottoman Empire and the Austro-Hungarian Empire until it’s disintegration following the first world war. Transylvania, as the rest of Romania, played an important role in European politics throughout the Interwar period, but suffered greatly through the second world war and the subsequent communist regime (1947 - 1989). The 1989 revolutions brought an end to Romanian Communist leader Ceausescu’s repressive regime&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and led to the implementation of the free market as well as a 2007 accession to the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of the people are ethnically Romanian, but there’s a sizable Hungarian and Roma population as well. Especially the Romani people, an ethnic minority originating from northwestern India and historically serving as slaves in Romania, undergo plenty of discrimination both in Romania and throughout Europe, thus leaving them segregated and socially vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As “poor college students” without driver licenses, we relied heavily on public transport. Luckily, Romania has an excellent public transport system both within cities as throughout the country. Thus commuting through the city felt as easy as at home. Unfortunately, due to time issues, we had to cut several important destinations (such as Sighisoara) out of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bucharest"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#bucharest"&gt;Bucharest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Bucharest’s Otopeni airport on the 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of September and after a brief stroll through town headed to Gara de Nord train station for a train to Sinaia. As a West-European citizen, the contrasts were a bit surprising. Balkan and Latin architectural influences contradict strongly with the tight, functional soviet designs,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and even the more touristic access able historical center underwent heavy decay and is now mostly covered in graffiti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29865697296/in/album-72157673147829801/" title="Decayed building"&gt;&lt;img alt="Decayed building" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8129/29865697296_916f618502.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="center border" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29606361880/in/album-72157673147829801/" title="Constructivist architecture"&gt;&lt;img alt="Constructivist architecture" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8492/29606361880_02850fb836.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sinaia"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#sinaia"&gt;Sinaia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sinaia is a quaint little town about an hour and …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2016-09-24:/blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Romania</category><category>Transylvania</category><category>Travels</category></item><item><title>Visiting a Japanese Elementary School - An (Awkward) Experience to Remember</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year us second year Japanese Students were invited to participate in an international speech contest (theme: “tell an interesting story”), organized by Kobe University. Just this week we were informed that the video-recordings of those entries had been uploaded to the contest’s website and were available for all to watch.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; My story is a classic “awkward Japanese language mix-up” anecdote from a school trip to a Japanese elementary school in Brussels, which I’ll touch upon in this post, alongside the embedded video. (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;日本の方、あまり自信がないのですが、もしよろしければ是非ともご覧ください！&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: I just found out that I somehow managed to win first prize out of all the foreign contestants!! This is so cool to hear! Thanks for the cookies, Kobe University! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cookies" class="fcenter" src="http://localhost:8000/images/kobe_cookies.jpg" title="cookies"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-video"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-video"&gt;The Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="video"&gt;
&lt;video class="video-js vjs-default-skin" controls="" data-setup="{}" id="pelican-installation" poster="/static/screencasts/pelican-installation.png" preload="auto"&gt;
&lt;source src="http://www.speech-data.jp/chotto/media/2015F_sub/f2015037s.mp4" type="video/mp4"/&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video, along with my participation entry, is available at &lt;a href="http://www.speech-data.jp/chotto/2015F_sub/2015037.html"&gt;speech-data.jp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-story"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-story"&gt;The story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story isn’t that interesting and a bit embarrassing, but here goes anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cookies" class="right border" src="http://localhost:8000/images/omoshiroi/brabo.jpg" title="cookies"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As second year students Japanese Studies, our class participated in an excursion to a Japanese elementary school in Brussels: a fun opportunity to practice our language skills as well as have some fun playing games and learn about cultural differences and customs. The event even warranted a small post on the &lt;strong&gt;JSB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; section on &lt;a href="http://blogs.yahoo.co.jp/jsbbxl/55269213.html"&gt;yahoo.co.jp&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In advance of this trip, we split our class in several groups, each preparing a presentation or activity related to our country. Several students in our group live in Antwerp, thus we thought it fun to hold a small presentation on the famous Antwerp folklore story of &lt;em&gt;Druon Antigoon&lt;/em&gt;, an evil giant guarding a bridge and exacting an exorbitant toll of those wishing to cross. Failing to cross meant &lt;em&gt;getting your hand chopped off&lt;/em&gt; and thrown into the river.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; A tad morbid, but it worked well with a popular Belgian children’s game we thought fun to teach them, and in addition, there’s some really nice chocolate treats based on this tale we wanted to distribute afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-game"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-game"&gt;The game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is a variation of a classic tag game called “&lt;em&gt;schipper, mag ik over varen?&lt;/em&gt;” (Eng: “&lt;em&gt;Skipper, may I cross?&lt;/em&gt;”) and usually played on a school’s courtyard or in a larger PE classroom. To play, the territory gets divided into two and the students line up on either side. One or two volunteers play the role of “skipper” or “boatman” and line up in the middle (I …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2016-08-28:/blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Video</category><category>KU Leuven</category></item><item><title>Travels: an Icelandic Winter</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2016/08/travels-an-icelandic-winter/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;After a long, stressful first semester exam-period, I spent my brief time off traveling to two completely opposite places I’ve been wanting to visit for a very long time: &lt;strong&gt;Rome, Italy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;: one of the coldest winter destinations I could imagine, but a place of stunning natural beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past years, Iceland has gained somewhat of a reputation for its hipster trends and excellent music scene (both true), but its biggest attraction to me personally remains its wild, barren landscapes: sceneries that appeared downright alien at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is our brief itinerary through this beautiful country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iceland, a volcanically active island close to the Arctic Circle, was first inhabited by in the 9&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century by, traditionally claimed, vikings or Norwegian settlers. Most of present-day Icelandic culture finds its roots in its Scandinavian heritage, and even now is mostly famous for its medieval sagas and traditional literature and cuisine, as well as its language closely related to Old Norse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Icelandic plateau is one of the newest in the world, the surroundings closely resemble what our continents must’ve looked like millions of years ago. Agriculturally wise, almost everything is imported from countries as Canada, as the only native growths here are limited to bleak bushes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having only a few days off in-between my exams and the start of my next semester, we were very limited in our itinerary. Even more, neither of us had a driver license at this point, so we were forced to book several tours to show us around (a thing I generally dislike, but actually ended up really pleasant). We stayed several nights in Reykjavik as day-trips to iconic views were easiest to reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="golden-circle-tour"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#golden-circle-tour"&gt;Golden Circle Tour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our first proper day, we took a tour leading us through the &lt;strong&gt;Golden Circle&lt;/strong&gt;, the most popular tourist route in Iceland. the host driving us around was an elderly man taking great pride in his viking roots and often talked of bygone farmer days and Icelandic folklore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our way to our first hallmark, we encountered these beauties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29659421145/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Icelandic Horses"&gt;&lt;img alt="Icelandic Horses" src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8116/29659421145_d7c95e17db_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29368542150/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Icelandic Horse"&gt;&lt;img alt="Icelandic Horse" src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8349/29368542150_58d6c26d02.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="geysir"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#geysir"&gt;Geysir&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geysir&lt;/strong&gt; is the geyser the English word is derived from and erupts about every 10 minutes, hurling boiling water up to 70 meters in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/30520292645/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Geyser"&gt;&lt;img alt="Geyser" src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5537/30520292645_66270303bc.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gulfoss"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#gulfoss"&gt;Gulfoss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gulfoss&lt;/strong&gt;, the Icelandic term for “Golden Falls”, is an iconic waterfall located in the midst of a large canyon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29368545040/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Iceland waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iceland waterfall" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8716/29368545040_a4038c7490.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29548193752/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Iceland waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iceland waterfall" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8061/29548193752_26c6213969.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="center border" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29659422675/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Iceland waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iceland waterfall" src="https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8031/29659422675_84529724dd.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="national-park-parliament"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#national-park-parliament"&gt;National Park Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thingvellir …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2016-08-27:/blog/2016/08/travels-an-icelandic-winter/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Iceland</category></item><item><title>Travels: Romance in Rome</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2016/08/travels-romance-in-rome/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;After a long, stressful first semester exam-period, I spent my brief time off traveling to two completely opposite places I’ve been wanting to visit for a very long time: Iceland and the historic city of Rome, Italy, cradle to one of the most well-documented civilizations in western history. In order to recharge our batteries, we decided on this 4-day city trip and, looking back, it really did turn out to be a city that could only be described as a living, breathing open-air museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is our brief itinerary through this charming city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does one start! Rome, Italy’s capital and largest city, has been an extremely influential city for nearly three-thousand years. What is now a global city popular for it’s fashion and design was once a small village on top of a hill that through a series of fascinating military and political events became center of a vast empire and location of Catholicism’s founding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plenty of historical locations have been destroyed following Italy’s rise of Fascism and role in the second World War, but the historic center (Unesco World Heritage) remains as if untouched by time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having limited time, we spent all our time exploring the historical center of Rome and the Vatican. We spent three nights in a lovely bed &amp;amp; breakfast around 15 minutes away from the historical center; which was, due being located in what might might be perceived as a shabby neighborhood, extremely well priced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-1"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#day-1"&gt;Day 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent our first day strolling around the city’s historical center and experiencing some of the more popular destinations such as the famous &lt;strong&gt;Spanish Steps&lt;/strong&gt; square and &lt;strong&gt;Trevi Fountain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29548322602/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Street to Spanish Steps"&gt;&lt;img "="" alt="Street to Spanish Steps" src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8766/29548322602_8d9fa0e2c2_b.jpg" style="height:500px;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As fans of English Romanticism (including poets as &lt;em&gt;Byron&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Shelly&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Keats&lt;/em&gt; we spent a bit of time in what is now a museum dedicated to Keats: the &lt;strong&gt;Keats-Shelley Memorial House museum&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29032997714/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Rome Skyline"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rome Skyline" src="https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8470/29034772843_795100ab25_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We concluded our evening having the most classic dinner one might expect of tourists in Italy: pizza and tiramissu (no regrets).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-2"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#day-2"&gt;Day 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second day was mostly centered around Rome’s ancient &lt;strong&gt;Colosseum&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Palatine Hill&lt;/strong&gt; and the massive &lt;strong&gt;Roman Forum&lt;/strong&gt;. Beautiful ruins rich in history made this area an unforgettable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29032997714/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Colosseum"&gt;&lt;img alt="Colosseum" src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8306/29032997714_5fc1215ae6_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out this area is popular amongst conservatory students as well. Excellent, sunny weather (in the middle of winter!) and a classical violist nearby reciting Vivaldi made for a lovely picnic~.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29032997714/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Rome Skyline"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rome Skyline" src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8174/29548318702_fa92ce10fd_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29032999364/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Roman Forum"&gt;&lt;img alt="Roman Forum" src="https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8799/29032999364_2b8c78b94d_b.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="center border" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29032999364/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Roman Forum"&gt;&lt;img alt="Roman Forum" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8555/29368660840_dbae0e17d8_b.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in the …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2016-08-26:/blog/2016/08/travels-romance-in-rome/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Rome</category><category>Italy</category></item><item><title>Travels: roadtrip through the Deep South</title><link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2016/08/travels-roadtrip-through-the-deep-south/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, me and a couple of friends decided on a summer road-trip throughout the so-called &lt;em&gt;Deep South&lt;/em&gt;, the most southern states of the USA. As we have a shared history of playing in bands and writing music together, my friends and I thought it would be cool to purchase some second-hand instruments and travel through some of the more musically well-known states. This short blog covers our three-week itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Deep South refers to the seven slave states that originally joined forces in what became known as the Confederate States of America. The historical dependence on slave labor (as well as the proximity to Cuba and Mexico) means that the region has both a large present-day ethnic minority of African-Americans and Hispanic Americans (and a more apparent cultural mix). Therefore, parts of this particular region are also informally called Black Belt (as well as Bible Belt). Simultaneously the region politically tends to be more conservative-leaning; with historic revisionism in regards to the region’s role in, and dependence on, trans-Atlantic slavery often neglected in favor of ‘State rights’ rhetoric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29660068685/in/album-72157672692229522/" title="Desert"&gt;&lt;img alt="Desert" src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8131/29660068685_cc58b07e01.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We rented a relatively cheap car that would still be large enough to handle all five of us and our gear. Size-wise The car looked like a limousine, yet  paled in comparison to the cars driving around us; among our first cultural shocks right there. As most of us are still students, we left straight after our finals end of June. The summertime in the South is described as being relentlessly tough, so we made sure to have proper air-conditioning and plenty of water available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="car" class="fcenter" src="http://localhost:8000/images/car.jpg" title="car"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="florida"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#florida"&gt;Florida&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="miami"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#miami"&gt;Miami&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a fairly pleasant eight-hour flight, we arrived at Miami International Airport in Florida. Despite arriving late in the evening, it still took us over a whopping three hours of queuing just to get through border control. It was a Kafkaesque experience for sure; having to queue to use check-in machines and manual check-ups serving the exact same task, yet those manual check-ups were so superficial that it felt entirely unnecessary and a waste of time. An antiqued relic of post-911 measures?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our way out we passed about five fast-food chains within a minute of driving, as well as several drive-through gun shops and pharmacies, and big billboards advertising triple-bypasses. What a country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29035300123/in/album-72157672692229522/" title="Miami"&gt;&lt;img alt="Miami" src="https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8094/29035300123_8272e91fed.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other memorable locations to us as foreigners …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2016-08-24:/blog/2016/08/travels-roadtrip-through-the-deep-south/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>USA</category><category>Deep South</category></item></channel></rss>