<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Onoreto</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://localhost:8000/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://steviepoppe.net/</id><updated>2016-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Travels: a week in Transylvania</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-24:blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;With the academic schoolyear rapidly approaching, my girlfriend and I decided on a short last-minute trip out and booked ourselves cheap tickets to Romania. We spent the week traveling through the historic region of Transylvania, commonly associated with vampire folklore, and situated between the imposing Carpathian mountains. A rich history, ranging from a feudal agricultural culture to a post-war communist regime and more recently the shift to a capitalist mode of production, leaves plenty of marks in its culture, architecture and national mentality, and offers so much more as just touristic amusement. This short blog covers our itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Romania"></category><category term="Transylvania"></category><category term="Travels"></category></entry><entry><title>Visiting a Japanese Elementary School - An (Awkward) Experience to Remember</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-28:blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I, alongside several other second year Japanology students, participated in a small “tell an interesting story” speech contest through our university. This week we were informed the videorecordings of these had been uploaded on the contest’s website and were available for all to watch&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. My story is a classic “awkward Japanese language mix-up” anecdote on a visit to a Japanese elementary school in Brussels, which I’ll touch upon in this post, along embedding the video. (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;日本の方、あまりよくないんですけど、もしよかったら見てみてくださいね！&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Video"></category><category term="KU Leuven"></category></entry></feed>