<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Onoreto - Publication</title><link>http://localhost:8000/</link><description>| Onoreto</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Far Right and the Dissemination of COVID-19-Related Disinformation and Conspiracy Narratives in Japan: the Metapolitics of Kobayashi Yoshinori</title><link>http://localhost:8000/publication/covid-disinformation/</link><description>&lt;h1 id="abstract"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial lack of scientific consensus regarding COVID-19 and public controversies concerning implemented countermeasures have created fertile soil for the circulation of disinformation and conspiracy narratives. Applying a mixed-methods discourse analysis, we examine the use of typical rhetorical strategies and metaphors of conspiracy narratives and disinformation, and we study overlaps with discursive strategies of the New Right in Japan. Our discourse analysis uses a qualitative and a quantitative approach. The former ranges from bestselling publications by the contribution of historical revisionist manga author Kobayashi Yoshinori to the propagation of COVID-19 – related conspiracy narratives and disinformation. The latter analyzes data collected from Amazon’s review section, through which we explore narrative reach and reader reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="citation"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#citation"&gt;Citation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poppe, S., Havenstein, L., &amp;amp; Schäfer, F. (2023). The Far Right and the Dissemination of COVID-19-Related Disinformation and Conspiracy Narratives in Japan: the Metapolitics of Kobayashi Yoshinori, Asiascape: Digital Asia, 10(1-2), 153-180. doi: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1163/22142312-bja10050"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1163/22142312-bja10050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe, Linda Havenstein, and Fabian Schäfer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2023-06-07:/publication/covid-disinformation/</guid><category>Publication</category><category>conspiracy theories</category><category>COVID-19 pandemic</category><category>disinformation</category><category>Kobayashi Yoshinori</category><category>metapolitics</category><category>New Right</category><category>populism</category></item><item><title>“From Y”: A mixed-method analysis of the Twitter Account of Abe Shinzō’s killer</title><link>http://localhost:8000/publication/from-y/</link><description>&lt;h1 id="abstract"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports on the murder of former Japanese Prime Minister Abe Shinzō, even after details on the perpetrator’s Twitter account were made public, reinforce ideas that 1) the perpetrator’s motives were not inherently political and 2) stem from a personal grudge against the Unification Church and the belief that Abe Shinzō was deeply tied to this group. Through a mixed-method content and discourse analysis of his Twitter account, we find that 1) the perpetrator’s worldview is distinctly political and ties into the belief systems associated with online right-wing and misogynist sub-cultural communities, and 2) his account reads as a fragmented manifesto combining self-victimized accounts of his past intertwined with the above political views. Based on these findings, we argue that the perpetrator’s actions are driven both by his political beliefs and by a sense of manifest destiny and urgency we associate with internet-radicalized terrorists and the highly networked communities driving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="citation"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#citation"&gt;Citation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poppe, S. (2022). “From Y”: A mixed-method analysis of the Twitter Account of Abe Shinzō’s killer. Retrieved from: &lt;a href="https://www.digital-japan.org/2022/08/19/analysis-of-the-twitter-account-of-abe-shinzos-killer/"&gt;https://www.digital-japan.org/2022/08/19/analysis-of-the-twitter-account-of-abe-shinzos-killer/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:localhost,2022-08-19:/publication/from-y/</guid><category>Publication</category><category>Corpus linguistics</category><category>Internet-right</category><category>Media analysis</category></item></channel></rss>