<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Onoreto</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/</link><description>| Onoreto</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Far Right and the Dissemination of COVID-19-Related Disinformation and Conspiracy Narratives in Japan: the Metapolitics of Kobayashi Yoshinori</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/publication/covid-disinformation/</link><description>&lt;h1 id="abstract"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial lack of scientific consensus regarding COVID-19 and public controversies concerning implemented countermeasures have created fertile soil for the circulation of disinformation and conspiracy narratives. Applying a mixed-methods discourse analysis, we examine the use of typical rhetorical strategies and metaphors of conspiracy narratives and disinformation, and we study overlaps with discursive strategies of the New Right in Japan. Our discourse analysis uses a qualitative and a quantitative approach. The former ranges from bestselling publications by the contribution of historical revisionist manga author Kobayashi Yoshinori to the propagation of COVID-19 – related conspiracy narratives and disinformation. The latter analyzes data collected from Amazon’s review section, through which we explore narrative reach and reader reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="citation"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#citation"&gt;Citation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poppe, S., Havenstein, L., &amp;amp; Schäfer, F. (2023). The Far Right and the Dissemination of COVID-19-Related Disinformation and Conspiracy Narratives in Japan: the Metapolitics of Kobayashi Yoshinori, Asiascape: Digital Asia, 10(1-2), 153-180. doi: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1163/22142312-bja10050"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1163/22142312-bja10050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe, Linda Havenstein, and Fabian Schäfer</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2023-06-07:/publication/covid-disinformation/</guid><category>Publication</category><category>conspiracy theories</category><category>COVID-19 pandemic</category><category>disinformation</category><category>Kobayashi Yoshinori</category><category>metapolitics</category><category>New Right</category><category>populism</category></item><item><title>Travels: One week in Jordan</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2022/12/travels-one-week-in-jordan/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Completely unrelated to the fact that I had already seen Dune in the cinema three times within the first year it came out, my childhood-era plans to visit the middle-east were bolstered when a friend from high school that I hadn’t seen in over a decade showed me his travel pictures in Jordan. Needless to say, within a few weeks, we had planned an itinerary and booked our flights to Amman, Jordan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that it was our first time to Jordan, we devised a fairly common itinerary that would allow us to see all the major destinations: the capital of Amman, the historic city of Petra (which was listed as one of the New 7 Wonders of the World), the desert valley of Wadi Rum, the Red Sea at the coastal city of Aqaba, and the Dead Sea. The Dead Sea aside, most of these are well-connected by JETT-operated public transport; nevertheless, irregular bus schedules meant that we ended up using a local, Uber-style transport method most of the time (an app called Careem).&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="petra"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#petra"&gt;Petra (ٱلْبَتْراء)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Amman airport rather late at night, and I had to wrap up work on a paper I was working on, so the first day was rather uneventful;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; if anything, I ended up doing a full-nigher and was absolutely deceased on my way to Petra, our first destination. The capital city of an ancient Arab civilization called the Nabateans, Petra is an ancient city in Jordan known today for its rock-cut architecture and the iconic Treasury (Al-Khazneh, الخزنة;) building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center noshadow"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/53020554934/in/album-72177720309515750/" title="Petra"&gt;&lt;img alt="Petra" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53020554934_09b4016625_z.jpg" style="height: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="center noshadow" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/53019802842/in/album-72177720309515750/" title="Petra by Night"&gt;&lt;img alt="Petra by Night" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53019802842_13376c6b18_z.jpg" style="height: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed at a cozy hotel about ten minutes away by shuttle bus to the main entrance point of Petra.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; From there, the city is accessed through a narrow canyon called the Siq, which lead straight to the Treasury. Although stunning, it was the trail beyond, leading to the theater and monarchy, that truly drew me in with its magnificent views of the mountainous landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, given that Petra is an extremely popular destination, we had to be prepared to ward off a variety of scam artists and hawkers; particularly at the entrance of the site and near the Treasury. This was fortunately limited to only those spots and, on a hike further in the ancient city, we were offered coffee and refreshments for next to nothing by a Bedouin mother and her daughter residing …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2022-12-10:/blog/2022/12/travels-one-week-in-jordan/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Jordan</category></item><item><title>“From Y”: A mixed-method analysis of the Twitter Account of Abe Shinzo’s killer</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/publication/from-y/</link><description>&lt;h1 id="abstract"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports on the murder of former Japanese Prime Minister Abe Shinzō, even after details on the perpetrator’s Twitter account were made public, reinforce ideas that 1) the perpetrator’s motives were not inherently political and 2) stem from a personal grudge against the Unification Church and the belief that Abe Shinzō was deeply tied to this group. Through a mixed-method content and discourse analysis of his Twitter account, we find that 1) the perpetrator’s worldview is distinctly political and ties into the belief systems associated with online right-wing and misogynist sub-cultural communities, and 2) his account reads as a fragmented manifesto combining self-victimized accounts of his past intertwined with the above political views. Based on these findings, we argue that the perpetrator’s actions are driven both by his political beliefs and by a sense of manifest destiny and urgency we associate with internet-radicalized terrorists and the highly networked communities driving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="citation"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#citation"&gt;Citation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poppe, S. (2022). “From Y”: A mixed-method analysis of the Twitter Account of Abe Shinzō’s killer. Retrieved from: &lt;a href="https://www.digital-japan.org/2022/08/19/analysis-of-the-twitter-account-of-abe-shinzos-killer/"&gt;https://www.digital-japan.org/2022/08/19/analysis-of-the-twitter-account-of-abe-shinzos-killer/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2022-08-19:/publication/from-y/</guid><category>Publication</category><category>Corpus linguistics</category><category>Internet-right</category><category>Media analysis</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide to Data-mining &amp; (Textual) Analysis of (Japanese) Twitter Part 4: Natural Language Processing With MeCab, Neologd and NLTK</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/07/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-4/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This short series of blogs chronicles the bare-bones required to conduct a basic form of social media analysis on corpora of (Japanese) Tweets. It is primarily intended for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;undergraduate and graduate students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; whose topics of research include contemporary Japan or its online vox populi, and want to strengthen their existing research (such as an undergraduate thesis or term paper) with a social media-based quantitative angle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fourth blog follows up on the MeCab + NEologd set-up described in the third part of this series, and introduces the reader to some of possibilities when working with python-based NLP tools such as NLTK. Concretely, we will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Import the python wrapper mecab-python, necessary to use MeCab in our python scripts,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Learn about NLP tools like NLTK,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Perform a basic sentiment analysis on a corpus of Japanese tweets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mecab-python-binding"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#mecab-python-binding"&gt;MeCab python binding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having set-up MeCab, we now require a python binding in order to use MeCab in our python scripts. As usual, install the required python library using &lt;strong&gt;pip&lt;/strong&gt; in the command prompt: &lt;code&gt;pip install mecab&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Upon installation, let’s test our set-up by using the &lt;code&gt;python&lt;/code&gt; command in the command prompt and copy-pasting the code examples below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example 1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;MeCab&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;tagger&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;MeCab&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Tagger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;parsed&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;tagger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;parse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"お母さんが作ってくれた魚フライ定食を食べてみたいです。"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;parsed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MeCab.Tagger function accepts several arguments we can pass to MeCab:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-d&lt;/code&gt;: path to one or more tokenizer dictionaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-E&lt;/code&gt;: Which escape sequence to use at the end of the parsed string (tabs: \t, backspaces: \b, newlines: \n, etc; don’t forget to escape the backslash with an additional backslash).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-O&lt;/code&gt;: Quick-formatting options. Wakati (short for &lt;em&gt;wakachi-gaki&lt;/em&gt;, 分かち書き), for example, is a tokenizer option for returning a string with only the surface form of each token, separated by spaces.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-F&lt;/code&gt;: Grants us more control over the output formatting. Adding &lt;code&gt;-F%m:\\t\\t%f[0]\\n&lt;/code&gt;, for example, will format the outcome as seen in &lt;strong&gt;figure 4&lt;/strong&gt;: the token surface form and the first element of the ‘&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;‘ array (part-of-speech), separated by tab spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;–unk-feature&lt;/code&gt;: set the return value of the part-of-speech column for unknown words (e.g. to &lt;em&gt;unknown&lt;/em&gt; or to 未知語).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example 2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;MeCab&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;tagger&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;MeCab&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Tagger …&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2020-07-05:/blog/2020/07/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-4/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Digital Humanities</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Python</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Twitter</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide to Data-mining &amp; (Textual) Analysis of (Japanese) Twitter Part 3: Natural Language Processing With MeCab, Neologd and KH Coder</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/06/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-3/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This short series of blogs chronicles the bare-bones required to conduct a basic form of social media analysis on corpora of (Japanese) Tweets. It is primarily intended for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;undergraduate and graduate students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; whose topics of research include contemporary Japan or its online vox populi, and want to strengthen their existing research (such as an undergraduate thesis or term paper) with a social media-based quantitative angle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this third blog and the next, fourth blog is to introduce the reader to the concept of natural language processing (NLP), to the techniques available for processing Japanese texts, and to some basic forms of quantitative content analysis that could be performed with that processed data. Concretely, in this third blog we will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  Learn about natural language processing in a Japanese context,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  Set up the morphological analyzer &lt;strong&gt;MeCab&lt;/strong&gt; and the neologism dictionary &lt;strong&gt;mecab-ipadic-NEologd&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  Install and set-up the quantitative content analysis tool KH Coder,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  Perform a rudimentary content analysis on a corpus of tweets collected with methods described in the previous two blogs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this blog thus assumes that the reader has read &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/04/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter/"&gt;part one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/05/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-2/"&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; of this series, it should also serve as a solid stand-alone introduction to setting up MeCab and the IPADic NEologd dictionary (as of writing still pretty much the &lt;em&gt;de-facto&lt;/em&gt; canonical tools in academic scholarship applying a form of Japanese computational linguistics) and combining them with KH Coder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of the field, parts of this tutorial will be rather technical and rely on having some basic experience working with the Windows command prompt or MacOS Terminal, but despite the complexity of the matter, there shouldn’t be much of a technical difficulty gap compared to the previous tutorials.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="japanese-natural-language-processing"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#japanese-natural-language-processing"&gt;Japanese Natural Language Processing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Natural language’ refers to the usage of language that has developed naturally over time among humans, encompassing methods of communication such as speech, written text and signaling. Natural Language Processing, then, is the field of developing how computers can understand and process such use of language in a cognitive way. Applications of NLP are seen anywhere ranging from AI assistants (such as Siri, Alexa or Google Assistant), to automatic translation (e.g. Google Translate), targeted advertising, and even in health-care.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important preliminary step in processing natural language computationally is to &lt;strong&gt;tokenize&lt;/strong&gt; of language (also referred to as &lt;strong&gt;word segmentation&lt;/strong&gt;). In other words, to break down language into smaller segments …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2020-06-05:/blog/2020/06/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-3/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Digital Humanities</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Python</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Twitter</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide to Data-mining &amp; (Textual) Analysis of (Japanese) Twitter Part 2: Basic Metrics &amp; Graphs</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/05/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This short series of blogs chronicles the bare-bones required to conduct a basic form of social media analysis on corpora of (Japanese) Tweets. It is primarily intended for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;undergraduate and graduate students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; whose topics of research include contemporary Japan or its online vox populi, and want to strengthen their existing research (such as an undergraduate thesis or term paper) with a social media-based quantitative angle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this second blog is two-fold: 1) to introduce the reader to some possibilities in regards to basic social media analysis (applicable almost immediately upon having &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/04/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter/"&gt;finished the previous guide&lt;/a&gt;), and 2) to touch upon a crucial, yet sometimes ignored aspect of social media analysis: the legal and ethical caveats regarding privacy and informed content when researching user-generated content on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using a concrete, real-world example, we will thus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Think about how we might integrate Twitter analysis into our project,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Use the Python scripting language to further process our dataset to our needs and obtain relevant metrics,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Use spreadsheet software such as Openlibre or Excel to produce pivot tables and graphs,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Reflect on the ethical and legal ramifications of working with social media data in academic research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id="context"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#context"&gt;Context&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assisted several third-year BA students working on a group essay covering aspects of the COVID-19 virus and marital issues within a larger framework of hegemonic masculinity, femininity and gender hegemony in Japan. Their choice of incorporating an element of social network analysis was not ungrounded. Correlating to increased remote work measures taken in Japan as a COVID-19 precaution, several hashtags concerning marital issues began to trend on Japanese Twitter starting Mid-April 2020 and saw further acceleration after being promptly picked up on by several news outlets and tabloids both within- and outside of Japan (such as the Japanese hashtag #&lt;em&gt;coronadivorce&lt;/em&gt;, #&lt;em&gt;koronarikon&lt;/em&gt; #コロナ&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;&lt;ruby&gt;&lt;rb&gt;離婚&lt;/rb&gt;&lt;rp&gt;(&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;rt&gt;りこん&lt;/rt&gt;&lt;rp&gt;)&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;/ruby&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my research interests concerns the many ways the internet, as a cultural artifact, augments or subverts our personal reality. Of interest to this project, then, was how the explosion in usage of the above hashtags reifies in Japan a situation that is undoubtedly being felt worldwide among many (married) couples during the pandemic. Concretely we had several questions: how does Twitter (and general social media usage) fit within the lives of struggling couples trying to cope with the uncertainty of the Corona crisis and its amplification of internal relational struggles? Does …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2020-05-15:/blog/2020/05/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-2/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Digital Humanities</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Python</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Twitter</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide to Data-mining &amp; (Textual) Analysis of (Japanese) Twitter Part 1: Twitter Data Collection</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/04/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;This short series of blogs chronicles the bare-bones required to conduct a basic form of textual analysis on corpora of Japanese tweets. Examples of similar tutorials on the Internet are numerous,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but less so are accessible beginner tutorials guiding the reader throughout the processes of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setting up the initial technical environment,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compiling corpora of clean, processed data, and,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding a visual, quantitative element to any qualitative reading of that text, by utilization of textual analysis tools &lt;strong&gt;tailored for Japanese content&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This series is therefore primarily intended for &lt;strong&gt;undergraduate and graduate students&lt;/strong&gt; whose topics of research include contemporary Japan or its online &lt;em&gt;vox populi&lt;/em&gt;, and want to strengthen their existing research (such as an undergraduate thesis or term paper) with a social media-based quantitative angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping in mind that many of those situated in the humanities might experience an initial technical hurdle, this first blog will focus primarily on the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;, rather than on the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; of doing Twitter-based research, by detailing the minimal necessities for getting up and running — supplemented by a brief optional, technical explanation &lt;em&gt;for those who are interested&lt;/em&gt;. With this first blog, the reader will thus concretely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Set up a Twitter Developer account and obtain Twitter credentials,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Set up a Python development environment,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Run tailored Python scripts to build datasets of tweets, based either on keywords or on the tweet history of particular users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Use Python for preprocessing the dataset into a usable corpus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first blog assumes that the reader has already chosen a topic or target of analysis for which a form of Social Network Analysis (SNA) or content analysis of Twitter data is well-suited. A more thorough epistemological introduction to the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; of SNA, as well as further recommended reading, will follow in the future. Suffice to say, the technical ease of working with the Twitter APIs, as well as the global-spread use of Twitter (roughly half a billion tweets are sent every single day, with Japanese per capita usage ranking particularly high), offer an excellent introduction to getting acquainted with SNA through practical, real-life examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It must be emphasized that the field this tutorial roughly falls under, &lt;strong&gt;Digital Humanities&lt;/strong&gt; (DH), is extremely broad; and understanding the various possibilities DH offers, as well as when and how to apply those, have their own intricate challenges. Within the scope of our brief tutorial series, however, the initial technical hurdles …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2020-04-01:/blog/2020/04/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Digital Humanities</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Python</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Twitter</category></item><item><title>Travels: Two Weeks in Mainland China (Changsha, Yunnan, Xi'an)</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/09/travels-two-weeks-in-mainland-china-changsha-yunnan-xian/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;Friday, 16 August 2019, approximately 2PM and approximately 2 hours of sleep. Calling that day a somewhat surreal and emotionally taxing day, might, in retrospect, be putting it mildly. I had just spent the night proofreading my graduate thesis for the thousandth time, buried in anxiety that a minor typo in a footnote still buried somewhere on the tenth page of my appendix would destroy my chances of graduation. Within the timespan of barely an hour, I retrieved the print copies of said thesis at a local print shop, handed them in at my university, shared a cup of coffee with some of my classmates—by now, my good friends—at &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; local coffeehouse hangout, checked my watch, and rushed towards the train-station. I had a flight to China to catch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the unwarranted stress, my five years as both undergraduate and graduate student at KU Leuven—enrolling at this university must have been the single most transformative decision I have ever taken—were now definitely at an end. To ‘celebrate’, I would now partake in a graduation trip to mainland China, accompanied by some of my closest friends while living in Japan. Both literally and figuratively a graduation trip, this trip was simultaneously a finale to my student life at KU Leuven, to my period of living in Japan, and to my youth in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A finale written by a director of slice-of-life situational comedy, that is; while contemplating all the above at the airport, a stoic voice announced that my flight was canceled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial plan was to take the plane to Hong Kong, spend the afternoon hanging out with a friend in Tsim Sha Tsui, and take a late evening train straight to Changsha, my initial destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, after my initial flight was canceled and making my connection in time seemed increasingly unlikely, I received a new itinerary to Changsha through connecting flights in the Netherlands and Shanghai. I would have to wait approximately seven more hours in the airport of Amsterdam, but I’ve had worse experiences and I could just take a nap after checking in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or so I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of hours afterwards I was informed that my flight to Shanghai was canceled. Instead, I was offered a direct flight to Changsha from Frankfurt, Germany the next day as well as a free stay in a nearby hotel. Oh well. Heading towards …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2019-09-10:/blog/2019/09/travels-two-weeks-in-mainland-china-changsha-yunnan-xian/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>China</category></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/09/resources/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;This page contains links and files that have proven to be particularly useful for myself and might be of use for those with similar interests. I’ll update this spot as I encounter more tools or pages I feel are worthy of mention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="useful-links"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#useful-links"&gt;Useful Links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="general"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#general"&gt;General&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ankisrs.net/"&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Free, open-source, multi-platform flashcard application with powerful SRS&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; algorithm. Especially vital for language acquisition and probably the single most important (digital) tool for efficient memorization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="language"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#language"&gt;Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="japanese"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#japanese"&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://foosoft.net/projects/yomichan/"&gt;Yomichan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: a Firefox and Chrome pop-up dictionary and a digital-minded Japanese learner’s best friend. Yomichan allows additional audio playback and full Anki integration. I’ve written a &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/04/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-5-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama-yomichan/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; on how to do this. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/"&gt;Rikaisama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, although no longer by Firefox, also continues to be useful for mass-generating cards while reading HTML-formatted e-books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://animelon.com/"&gt;Animelon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: for all you ‘learn Japanese through Anime’ kids out there! Reminiscent of the classic &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.erin.ne.jp/en/"&gt;Erin’s Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; videos: watch various popular anime with Japanese subtitles and integrated dictionary. Works in combination with Yomichan or Rikaisama as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://tangorin.com/kanji/"&gt;Tangorin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: my favorite online Japanese dictionary with tons of example sentences for each definition, and an excellent Kanji dictionary as well. &lt;a href="http://dictionary.goo.ne.jp"&gt;Goo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.weblio.jp"&gt;Weblio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.sanseido.net"&gt;Sanseido&lt;/a&gt; provide good alternatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://japansnederlandswoordenboek.org/index.php/Hoofdpagina"&gt;Waran Jiten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: a Japanese-Dutch dictionary courtesy of Leuven University. Has a dutch Rikai addon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/directory/home-education/edlanguage/os:windows/?q=Japanese"&gt;Sourceforge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: contains a wide variety of software developed by fellow Japanese learners. Some, such as &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/jnovelformatter/?source=directory"&gt;Jnovelformatter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/japanesetextana/?source=directory"&gt;Japanese Text Analysis Tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/ocrmangareaderforandroid/"&gt;OCR Manga Reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are particularly noteworthy, others not so much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://japanologie.arts.kuleuven.be/"&gt;KULeuven Japanology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the Leuven University Japan Studies homepage. &lt;i class="icon-smile"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="korean"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#korean"&gt;Korean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.toktogi.com/"&gt;Toktogi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: a Korean-English pop-up dictionary similar to yomichan, available both for Firefox and Chrome. It’s still a work-in-progress and not as polished as Yomichan, but very usable nonetheless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://endic.naver.com/?sLn=en"&gt;Naver Dictionary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Naver Corporation, the highly popular South Korean web-hub, has a fairly complete English-Korean dictionary as well as an Android application (requires internet).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sanskrit"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#sanskrit"&gt;Sanskrit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://spokensanskrit.de/"&gt;spokensanskrit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the only decent online Sanskrit dictionary out there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.lexilogos.com/keyboard/sanskrit_devanagari.htm"&gt;Lexilogos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: multilingual web keyboard that beats learning to type &lt;em&gt;devanagari&lt;/em&gt; on a latin-script keyboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h1 id="files"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#files"&gt;Files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="anki"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#anki"&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Anki to complement my other study methods for nearly all my classes. These are a bunch of Anki-sets I made I feel are stand-alone enough to be useful to new students of these classes as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h3 id="inleiding-tot-de-europese-literatuur-na-1750"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#inleiding-tot-de-europese-literatuur-na-1750"&gt;Inleiding tot de Europese Literatuur na 1750&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/yf2hdqxyqobqr60/Europese_Literatuur.apkg?dl=0"&gt;Europese Literatuur &lt;i class="icon-download-alt"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (±26MB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A full set to accompany the textbook ‘&lt;em&gt;Literaire Verbeelding 2&lt;/em&gt;’:&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; contains important dates and summaries of all artists and their discussed works (in Dutch …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2019-09-04:/blog/2019/09/resources/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Japan</category><category>Study</category></item><item><title>Several tips for exchange students heading to Japan / Tokyo</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/05/several-tips-for-exchange-students-living-in-japan-tokyo/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;My home university’s student circle asked me for some tips for new exchange students coming to Japan and after living in Tokyo, Japan for over 18 months I learned some things that might be useful for future exchange students, often glanced over in similar lists. Although this list is a perpetual work-in-progress, I hope it can at least offer some concrete, directly applicable tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="shopping"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#shopping"&gt;Shopping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="get-an-amazoncojp-prime-account"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#get-an-amazoncojp-prime-account"&gt;Get an Amazon.co.jp Prime account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m reluctant for promoting a company with an employment situation as terrible as Amazon. Nevertheless, students are legible for a year-long trial of Amazon Prime Student which might be quite useful for exchange students on a budget. The prime reason to do so would be free expedited shipping, but some other benefits include streaming through Prime Video and free selection of Kindle novels. Personally, I found amazon.co.jp useful for difficult to find research material and access to some other second-hand sellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="use-mercari"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#use-mercari"&gt;Use Mercari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mercari (メルカリ) is a widely used e-commerce application popular for second-hand sales and small time mom-and-pop independent stores. I used it for buying my TV and some rare-to-find records. It’s common to haggle on the price and you pay through convenience stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="get-used-to-customer-cards"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#get-used-to-customer-cards"&gt;Get used to customer cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of stores have customer cards, usually freely obtainable and immediately applicable. A card at my OK Supermarket cost 100 yen and saved me 3% on all my groceries. Places like Big Camera, the must-visit dirt-cheap second hand store Book-Off, Tully’s Coffee, etc have free customer cards. Some stores moved on to smart-phone applications, like the shoes-market chain ABC Market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="services"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#services"&gt;Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="manga-cafes"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#manga-cafes"&gt;(Manga) cafes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I loved my apartment and spent a lot of time at my university lab, I generally felt the most productive studying or reading in bakeries or the omnipresent coffee-shops like Tully’s and Renoir. Perhaps not as romantic, but another cheap option might be studying at McDonalds chains equipped with electric outlets and ordering a cheap coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I grew fond of manga cafes and particularly of the &lt;strong&gt;Kaikatsu Club&lt;/strong&gt; (快活クラブ) chain. Students get steep discounts, private booths are comfortable and equipped with both blankets and pillows for a quick nap, as well as a computer and additional screen I could attach to my laptop, and sufficient electrical outlets. All you can drink soft-ice, hot drinks and …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2019-05-18:/blog/2019/05/several-tips-for-exchange-students-living-in-japan-tokyo/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Japan</category><category>Study abroad</category><category>tips</category></item><item><title>Japanese E-books, vocab-mining, DRM and copyright law</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/05/japanese-e-books-vocab-mining-drm-and-copyright-law/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;The E-book industry in Japan is gaining momentum. Both contemporary releases and more popular classics are seeing an increase in digital publication alongside physical distribution. Through their kindle service Amazon.co.jp has a particularly strong hold on this market, and their extensive catalog could offer good news for any intermediate or advanced Japanese language learner. It is easier to look up new vocabulary from digital media than it is to look something up from print media, and both physical Kindles as Kindle for Windows are surprisingly feature-rich, including in-built dictionaries and flashcard options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/04/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-5-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama-yomichan/"&gt;prior blogs&lt;/a&gt; I’ve described my method of reading digital texts as HTML files through a web-browser; using pop-up dictionaries such as Rikaisama or Yomichan in combination with flashcard application Anki for ‘vocab mining’&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; native materials.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This blog describes options of combining that method with kindle E-books, as well summing up several other alternative sources of E-books. Conclusively it is possible to efficiently utilize the Japanese kindle market for study purposes, but doing requires a bit of technical prowess and borders on technical illegality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="amazon-kindle"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#amazon-kindle"&gt;Amazon Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past two years or so I’ve often relied on Amazon.co.jp’s Kindle service for both academic purposes and as leisure, especially while living in Japan.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Their selection of Japanese language material is immense, with Kodansha-published E-books alone accounting for over 40.000 titles in their library. Having relied on above-mentioned study method for a while now I looked into my options of doing so with Kindle E-books as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="through-browsers"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#through-browsers"&gt;Through Browsers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first option would be to open Kindle E-books with my browser and use Rikaisama or Yomichan to import vocabulary into Anki. When purchasing an E-book on Amazon, one specifically purchases the right to read the E-book and download an amazon proprietary file through the Kindle software (the &lt;code&gt;.AZW&lt;/code&gt; format). This proprietary format is practically identical to the &lt;code&gt;.MOBI&lt;/code&gt; format (which again is basically a more highly compressed HTML file, specifically using the Ebook HTML syntax) with additional DRM-protection on commercial releases as attempt to counter copyright infringement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Chrome and Firefox have plug-ins for parsing those two formats, but these plug-ins are frankly not sufficient for our purposes, and for obvious reasons don’t support files with DRM. One option would be removing the DRM through software and converting the Kindle &lt;code&gt;.AZW&lt;/code&gt; format to a &lt;code&gt;ZHTML&lt;/code&gt; format, which is …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2019-05-14:/blog/2019/05/japanese-e-books-vocab-mining-drm-and-copyright-law/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>Travels: Hong Kong &amp; Macau</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/05/travels-hong-kong-macau/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;At the end of my third semester in Japan, I took use of an extended school holiday &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; my last remaining months in Japan to plan a short trip to Taiwan and Hong Kong. During my stay I’ve had the pleasure to acquaint people from both regions and took this as the perfect excuse for some last minute sightseeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the most important trade and financial hubs in Asia and one of the most densely populated regions in the world; Hong Kong (香港) has a distinct international feel. While historically undeniably Chinese, Hong Kong was conceded by the Qing Dinasty to British rule after the First Opium War and remained a British colony until 1997, with brief control under the Japanese Empire during the Second World War. The majority of Hong Kong’s population have Cantonese ancestry and Cantonese remains the region’s main language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Hong Kong, like Macau, has some political independence under Deng Xiaoping’s “one country, two systems” principle (一国两制), both Macau and Hong Kong are officially part of The People’s Republic of China under the statute of Special Administrative Region. This in turn does lead to occasional political tensions concerning the extent to which mainland China should be allowed governance over Hong Kong. Living in Japan with mutual friends from mainland China, Hong Kong and Taiwan, I’ve had the opportunity to get a more nuanced take on both sides, but I feel this particular blog is not the appropriate platform for such a topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I spent the first half of my last-minute trip (around Taipei) mostly by myself, the second half of my trip (Hong Kong and Macao) was mostly spend with company and as a leisure trip to charge our batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a Hong Kong Airline flight from Taipei to Hong Kong International Airport (a short flight but possibly the most comfortable I’ve flown so far) and arrived at my hotel early in the evening. Similar to the &lt;em&gt;EasyCard&lt;/em&gt; in Taiwan and &lt;em&gt;Pasmo&lt;/em&gt; in Japan, I bought a RFID metro card, the Octopus Card, in Hong Kong. Rather than a card, this one was designed a cute bear key-chain, again applicable as general payment method in most convenient stores and some restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hong-kong"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#hong-kong"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ginza-square"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#ginza-square"&gt;Ginza Square&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stayed at Harbour Plaza Resort City in &lt;strong&gt;Kingswood&lt;/strong&gt;, close to Ginza Square …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2019-05-10:/blog/2019/05/travels-hong-kong-macau/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Hong Kong</category><category>Macau</category></item><item><title>Travels: Taiwan</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/05/travels-taiwan/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;At the end of my third semester in Japan, I took use of an extended school holiday &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; my last remaining months in Japan to plan a short trip to Taiwan and Hong Kong. During my stay I’ve had the pleasure to acquaint people from both regions and took this as the perfect excuse for some last minute sightseeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Island of Taiwan (governed since 1945 by the Republic of China, 中華民國) is an East Asian state located southwest of the Japanese Okinawan islands. Dutch colonization and consequent annexation by the Qing dynasty in the 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, as well as annexation and five decades of rule by by the Empire of Japan after the Sino-Japanese war of 1894-1895, have had a drastic impact on Taiwan’s demography, and presently the Taiwanese indigenous people make up only 2% of the population. Taiwan’s political status and its relation to mainland China, as well as domestic opinions on Japan, remains controversial topics. Nevertheless, the ease of entry for foreign visitors, as well as Taiwan’s scenic beauty and vibrant cultural scene have made Taiwan a popular destination for both mainland Chinese and Japanese nationals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due budget and time restraints I spent just two nights in Taiwan: centered around Taipei with one day trip to some of the more famous spots amongst Japanese tourists. I took an early flight from Tokyo’s &lt;strong&gt;Haneda Airport&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport&lt;/strong&gt; and arrived in Taipei Airport around noon. Preliminary preparations including currency exchange and the purchase of EasyCard RFID smart-card (with student discount) for the Taipei Metro transit system. Like Pasmo and Suica cards in Japan this card is widely accepted in convenience stores and retail outlets as well so I ended up using this as my primary means of payment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-1-taipei"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#day-1-taipei"&gt;Day 1: Taipei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a brisk short train ride I arrived at Taipei Station and experienced Taipei’s outside air and surroundings for the first time. It was by all means a beautiful, sunny day, but due the time of the year quite humid as well and I realized I’m not particularly good at dealing with tropical temperatures. Luckily my hostel, located near the National Taiwan Museum and Peace Park, was but a short walk from the station. On my way, I was struck by the amount of palm trees and the widespread use of …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2019-05-07:/blog/2019/05/travels-taiwan/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Taiwan</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 5: an efficient vocab mining set-up with Anki and Yomichan [2021 UPDATE]</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/04/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-5-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama-yomichan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As an undergraduate student I wrote several blog-posts and tutorials throughout 2016 on how I’ve personally integrated Anki in my daily life. One of those entries extensively documented how to connect Anki with Firefox to vocab-mine Japanese texts in my browser with JPod101 audio-readings, example-sentences and Japanese dictionary definitions; posts that became somewhat high-ranking when looking up all things Anki. The Anki-integrated Firefox pop-up dictionary Rikaisama has since then becoming obsolete, and I have since mostly relied on Yomichan instead. Hence this periodically updated guide.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s 20&lt;strong&gt;XX&lt;/strong&gt;, wasting valuable time on automatable processes bores you and you’re keen on integrating technology more efficiently in your Japanese language-acquisition. Concretely you want to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Vocab-mine Japanese texts you’re reading both on- and off-line using Chrome or Firefox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Improve your retention-rate with hover-able &lt;strong&gt;furigana&lt;/strong&gt; reading-aids and crystal-clear audio-readings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Contextualize your cards with Japanese example sentences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Rely not just solely on foreign-language translations, but use Japanese dictionary definitions for optimized studying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, you want cards like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ankiexample" class="hwimportant fborder fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/ankiexample.gif" title="ankiexample"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What options are available then, sans going all the way and developing said tools yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’ve previously used the Rikaisama pop-up dictionary and followed my previous guides, you can continue doing so using a Firefox-derived browser. I still recommend this method for longer texts such as novels. Head to section &lt;a href="#rikaisama"&gt;Rikaisama&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re new to this site or method, use the Chrome / Firefox add-on Yomichan. It’s user-friendly, highly adjustable and has tons of features. Head to section &lt;a href="#yomichan"&gt;Yomichan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id="yomichan"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#yomichan"&gt;Yomichan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed by &lt;a href="https://foosoft.net/"&gt;Foosoft Productions&lt;/a&gt; - a household name amongst the Anki-utilizing online learning community - Yomichan originated as a stand-alone book-reader with Anki-integration,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; until it in its current form became the most complete Rikaisama alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to Rikaisama, we’ll use Yomichan to vocab-mine Japanese texts and generate extensive Anki-cards with Jpod101 audio-readings, example sentences, &lt;em&gt;furigana&lt;/em&gt;, and Japanese definitions. Furthermore, for ex-Rikaisama users, Yomichan definitely has the upper hand concerning user-friendliness and adaptability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit of this plug-in is that it’s cross-platform, available both on &lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/rikaisama/files/"&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/rikaisama/files/"&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. Pick your platform of choice and after installing we’ll start the initial set-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth checking out &lt;a href="https://foosoft.net/projects/yomichan/"&gt;Yomichan’s homepage&lt;/a&gt; as it contains an extensive manual. This guide will focus purely on connecting Yomichan to Anki, setting up a proper template for our cards, and facilitate generating example sentences and Japanese definitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;
&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yomichan can’t parse …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2019-04-17:/blog/2019/04/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-5-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama-yomichan/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Rikaisama</category><category>Yomichan</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>Study-trip around Fukushima with Chuo FLP Seminar: Fukushima Hope tour</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2018/09/study-trip-around-fukushima-with-chuo-flp-seminar-fukushima-hope-tour/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;At the start of the new academic year in Japan, early April, I joined a music circle and formed several bands with other members of the circle. During the summer break, one of my band’s members invited me to join his class’ study trip to Fukushima; gaining first hand experience at methods Fukushima’s civilians are employing to revitalize Fukushima’s tourist industry after the 2011 earthquake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third largest prefecture in Japan, Fukushima is a northeastern region popular amongst Japanese not just as winter resort, but for its Japanese sake, food and many natural hot springs. Historically, Fukushima is known for it’s role in the last feudal Samurai war, the 1868 Bosshin War. Today however, the region remains heavily associated with the 2011 earthquake and subsequent nuclear disaster. An earthquake on 11 March 2011 led to a tsunami disabling most of the Fukushima Daiichi Nuclear Power Plant (located on the Pacific Ocean coastline of central Fukushima) and subsequent nuclear meltdowns due insufficient cooling. Despite strong criticism on government-level handling of the situation, much has been done on a local scale to restore Fukushima to its former level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A system quite common to Japan and less so where I’m from is the zemi system (derived from the seminar system in Germany); classes of around 10 students working together with the professor in interactive ways about a specific topic the professor is interested in. Usually groups become quite tight and occasionally join the professor for some food and drinks at night, as well as go on study trips (read: glorified city-trips). Earlier this year I had the opportunity of joining my German professor and three other students from KU Leuven studying in Japan for such a study-trip in Matsumoto, but this was my first opportunity doing in a full Japanese context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I was not part of the class, my friend and band-mate mentioned that that shouldn’t deter me from joining; in fact due the topic in question, input from a non-Japanese student would actually be highly appreciated, or so he assured me. Taught by Dr. Prof. Hosono (細野教授), the class itself (FLP, or Faculty-Linkage Program) is open for students of different academic backgrounds and often focuses on international issues. This semester, students worked on city-planning in disaster-struck areas (まちづくり) with a case-study of tourism in Fukushima …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2018-09-27:/blog/2018/09/study-trip-around-fukushima-with-chuo-flp-seminar-fukushima-hope-tour/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Study-trip around Matsumoto</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2018/05/study-trip-around-matsumoto/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;Last April, I had the pleasure to my professor from KU Leuven on a study-trip to Matsumoto, accompanied by several KU Leuven schoolmates also present in Japan, as well as a Japanese historian and professor at Matsumoto’s Shinshū University, and his seminar students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our study-trip, we would first visit the &lt;strong&gt;Old System Matsumoto High School Museum&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Kyūsei Matsumoto kōkō kinenkan&lt;/em&gt; 旧制松本高校記念館) and received a guided tour to a tunnel in &lt;strong&gt;Satoyama&lt;/strong&gt;, said to be dug out by forced laborers during the last few months of the Pacific War. Later on we would visit &lt;strong&gt;Shinshū University&lt;/strong&gt; and hold an impromptu seminar on the topics covered that day, before the obligatory &lt;em&gt;nomikai&lt;/em&gt; (飲み会). On our second day, we would join our professor in the morning for brief breakfast and recap, before spending the rest of the day visiting the center of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A historic castle town and city in Nagano Prefecture, &lt;strong&gt;Matsumoto&lt;/strong&gt; is known as a popular destination for those looking to visit the mountain scenery or traditional hot spring resorts located around the &lt;strong&gt;Northern Japan Alps&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Matsumoto Castle&lt;/strong&gt; in particular is a well-known attraction due to its reputation as one of the most beautiful castles in Japan. Matsumoto is the birthplace of famous artist Yayoi Kusama, and in more recent history, Matsumoto has also attracted attention for having being targeted by doomsday cult Aum Shinrikyo in 1994, leading to eight deaths by a Sarin gas terror attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met up with a junior student of KU Leuven studying in Tokyo (&lt;em&gt;kohai&lt;/em&gt;, 後輩) for our highway bus from Shinjuku to Matsumoto, were we met up with a good friend and KU Leuven classmate of mine studying in Kyushu University. Our first evening was fairly uneventful as it was too late to explore the city. We ended up joining one of the Shinshū University students for some snacks and a few drinks in a Japanese-style bar, mostly catching up on life, before calling it a day and heading towards our hostel, close to Matsumoto Castle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="matsumoto-high-school-museum"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#matsumoto-high-school-museum"&gt;Matsumoto High School Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having met up with our professor and a KU Leuven PhD student currently doing research in Kobe University, we joined the Shinshū University group on a bus ride to our first destination, the &lt;strong&gt;Matsumoto High School Museum&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located in an impressive forest park, &lt;strong&gt;Agatonomori Park&lt;/strong&gt; (あが …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2018-05-21:/blog/2018/05/study-trip-around-matsumoto/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Travels: Golden Week at Okinawa</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2018/04/travels-golden-week-at-okinawa/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;During this year’s golden week in Japan, I joined several of my friends for a short trip to Okinawa Island, the main island of the Okinawa prefecture. Due its pleasant tropic weather and beautiful beaches at this time of the year, Okinawa is one of the more popular destinations during Golden Week, and for us too a good occasion to finally visit Japan’s tropics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of 47 of Japan’s prefectures, Okinawa consists of over 100 small islands located between the island of Taiwan and Kyushu. Historically, the Okinawan Islands were home to the Ryukyu Kingdom and despite strong pressure from both Japan and China maintained a certain degree of sovereignty until complete annexation during the Meiji Restoration in the late 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. For this reason, Okinawa does feel culturally distinct to the rest of Japan even today and, based on my conversation with Okinawans, it appears many Okinawans take pride in their identity as being Okinawan first, over a national pride of being Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due’s Okinawa tragic role in the Pacific War (with war casualties accounting for over a quarter of its civilian population) as well as its subsequent U.S. occupation until 1972, there is a certain animosity amongst Okinawans against both the United States and the Japanese government. That animosity is further fueled by the continuous role of Okinawa as location for U.S. military bases, hosting approximately half of US military personnel in Japan. News stories of harassment by US military, as well as rising concerns over pollution, have led to a strong politically active base and frequent protests held against the Japanese government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more positive side, Okinawa is considered a tropical paradise and attracts tourists both Japanese and foreign. Okinawa’s population is often mentioned in international news as having long record-spanning lifespans and living healthy lifestyles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took a short local flight from Narita airport to Naha, the capital of Okinawa, followed by a convenient monorail ride directly to the city. Although we hoped to explore some of the nearby islands for scuba diving, we arrived during the rainy season and limited our activities to the main Okinawan Island. Our first days would be spent around the city of Nago, on the northern part of the island, while we’d spent the remaining days around the capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nago"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#nago"&gt;Nago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent the first night in a …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2018-04-27:/blog/2018/04/travels-golden-week-at-okinawa/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Japan</category></item><item><title>Travels: South Korea</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2018/04/travels-south-korea/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;As an undergraduate student at my Belgian university, I took several courses related to the Korean language and Korean history, which in turn made me quite eager to visit the country, given that I’d be living relatively close for the next year and a half. During my first semester studying in Japan, I was fortunate enough to make several good friends from South Korea. One of them had already left Japan by the end of the semester, and two of friends still remaining took the academic break in March as an opportunity to return to Seoul for several weeks, inviting me as well: an excellent way of celebrating the successful completion of my first semester in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Korea, officially known as the Republic of Korea, is an East Asian country east of Japan. Despite being sandwiched in-between China and Japan, the Korean Peninsula historically did well to repel repeated attempts of invasion and form an own distinct culture. With evidence of Korean settlements (confederacies) going back many centuries BC, and after hosting three major kingdoms (&lt;em&gt;Baekje&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Silla&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Goguryeo&lt;/em&gt;) as well as smaller confederacies for seven centuries, the peninsula first reached unification in the 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, leading to new peaks in cultural development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent history, Japan’s victory in the 1905 Russo-Japanese War led to Japanese occupation, with official annexation in 1910; until Japan’s defeat in the Second World War. The Korean Peninsula subsequently suffered the effects of the Cold War in an ideological proxy war between the North and the South. Although an armistice has been reached, the conflict remains far from solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topics of Japanese occupation and war crimes remain highly sensitive and are strong political weapons amongst nationalists in both countries. Nevertheless, the steady growth of Republic of Korea’s worldwide soft power (韓流 / 한류, the Hallyu Wave) has warmed the younger Japanese generations to renewed relations with the Republic of Korea. Studying the Korean language is rapidly gaining traction, and many Japanese citizens visit the Republic of Korea for tourism or as exchange students. Likewise, under influence of decades of Japanese soft power (“Cool Japan”), Japan is an increasingly popular destination for Korean tourists and exchange students.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When first planning my trip, I intended a fairly active trip covering Seoul, Sokcho and Busan, with a day-trip to Gapyeong. Right before departure however, my friends …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2018-04-05:/blog/2018/04/travels-south-korea/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Korea</category></item><item><title>Going Abroad as a Research Student</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2017/09/going-abroad-as-a-research-student/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I’ve posted my last blog, and while I’ve had some ideas on new posts, I had to prioritize schoolwork, including finishing my graduation thesis and preparing my cultural exchange. Courtesy of my university I received the opportunity to study and live in Tokyo for a year and half at Chuo University with MEXT scholarship, as part of my Master degree in Japanese Studies. I’m writing this small blog post exactly a week after arriving in Tokyo, in order to talk a bit about my university, my first impressions of my surroundings, and my personal experience with the application process for my scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="chuo-universty"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#chuo-universty"&gt;Chuo Universty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chuo University (中央大学) is a private-run university with several campuses spread throughout Tokyo, and containing a plethora of faculties, graduate schools and researchers. It’s mostly known for its legal studies, dating back to the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, and has many well known alumni ranging from economics and politics (including former Prime Minister Toshiki Kaifu) to arts and letters (including popular director Makoto Shinkai of &lt;em&gt;Kimi no Na wa&lt;/em&gt; 君の名は。 fame).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m studying at the largest campus, Tama Campus, which is located in Hachioji: a city in the western portion of Tokyo, and about an hour by public transport to more central parts of Tokyo such as Shinjuku. As a research student I have some liberty in the classes I can take up; they’re either thematically similar to master classes of Japanese Studies at Leuven, or support the global understanding necessary to write my master thesis. Thus I’ll mostly be taking classes from the Graduate School of Letters (specifically the Socio-Informatics course) and Graduate School of Policy Studies, as well as an introduction to Japanese Law from the Graduate School of Law. If time permits, I hope to continue my Korean studies as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/36534953573/in/album-72157686137772481/" title="Tama Campus"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tama Campus" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4348/36534953573_df9869ea32_k.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty overwhelmed by the size of the campus. It has eleven main buildings, along with a variety of student facilities for after-school activities such as clubs (クラブ) and circles (サークル), sport rooms, several restaurants, etc. I haven’t gotten the hang of it yet and I’m sure I’ll get lost &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; over the next year and a half. I’m pleased to see these amount of facilities available however, and I really look forward …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2017-09-19:/blog/2017/09/going-abroad-as-a-research-student/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Japan</category><category>Blog</category><category>Chuo</category></item><item><title>Travels: One Week of Andalusia</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2017/07/travels-one-week-of-andalusia/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Having finished the final exams for my undergraduate degree in Japan Studies, we decided to spend some time off by visiting a close friend doing an internship in Seville, Spain. We used our time there to get a glimpse of beautiful Andalusia and were not disappointed by the stunning beauty of its architecture and nature, its fascinating history and, importantly, its wonderful culinary traditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andalusia, an autonomous region at the most southward point of Spain, has had due to it’s geographical location - a gateway between Europe and Africa - strong ties with various cultures such as the Phoenicians, Greeks, Romans, Byzantines, Jews and the Muslim Moors. These cultural influences have, of course, left a strong mark on the development of Andalusia, both in its national identity and through cultural markers such as architecture, music, dance, and cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our friend let us stay in her apartment in Nervion, the shopping district of Seville, approximately 20 minutes by foot from the historical center. Taking her apartment as starting point, we arranged most of our activities around Seville and nearby regions. It was quite a pleasant surprise to be located only a short walk from one of the more appraised &lt;em&gt;tapa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; restaurants in Sevilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/35374810940/in/album-72157683544111201/" title="Tapas"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tapas" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4256/35374810940_814fd8d149_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent most of our time in Seville, but used a local carpooling service for two day-trips, to Granada and Ronda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="seville"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#seville"&gt;Seville&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/35630910381/in/album-72157683544111201/" title="Sevilla Street"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sevilla Street" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4125/35630910381_0fdf11d88c_b.jpg" style="height:500px;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seville, the capital of Andalusia and Spain’s 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; largest city, flourished in trade during the middle ages and thus has a well-developed and maintained city center. Amongst our highlights there was the 15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century &lt;strong&gt;Cathedral of Seville&lt;/strong&gt;, the third largest church in the world, built over a late twelfth century mosque. It contains the remains of the historical controversial figure Christopher Columbus. The area around the cathedral (commonly known as the &lt;strong&gt;Jewish Quarter&lt;/strong&gt;) is considered the historical center of Seville and is a delight to stroll through with it’s small cobblestone streets and variety of boutiques and restaurants. Our friend introduced us to a small but crowded bar with late-night flamenco performances, a sure marker of the vibrant nightlife in Seville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/35593087592/in/album-72157683544111201/" title="Seville Cathedral"&gt;&lt;img alt="Seville Cathedral" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4097/35593087592_87eceffb24_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To us, the most impressive site was &lt;strong&gt;Réal Alcázar&lt;/strong&gt;, UNESCO World Heritage Site and palace built in Moorish architectural style across the 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; to 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. It has recently gained new fame as setting of Dorne in the hit-series Game of Thrones. During our trip, we …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2017-07-06:/blog/2017/07/travels-one-week-of-andalusia/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Spain</category><category>Andalusia</category><category>Granada</category><category>Cordoba</category><category>Sevilla</category></item><item><title>New Song: IROHA 【いろは歌】</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2017/03/new-song-iroha-uta/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;During a course on classical Japanese (&lt;em&gt;kobun&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;古文&lt;/span&gt;) last semester, we were introduced to a particularly well-known Heian-era poem titled &lt;strong&gt;Iroha&lt;/strong&gt; – famous for using all characters of the Japanese syllabary exactly once&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attributed to &lt;em&gt;Kūkai&lt;/em&gt; (founder of the Japanese Esoteric sect of Buddhism), the layered meaning of the poem (and the fact we had to be able to recite it for my exam) struck a chord with me. I wrote a short melody to help me memorize it properly and, after my exam period, spent some time getting acquainted with electronic music composition in order to further expand upon that melody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="_1"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#_1"&gt;&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;いろは歌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xh7Nx-8-RZg" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="640"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I begin most of my compositions by playing the piano. I tried to create an otherwordly, esoteric vibe through constant shifts in modulation and relying on ninths and dissonance in the melody. Once I had my base backing track done, I spread the different lines across piano, pan drum and some ambient pads, wrote a sparse drum-track using chimes, woodblocks and taiko and practically drowned the whole in reverb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vocalist’s thin, airy voice works especially well for the kind of setting I hoped to express. The second half in particular used heavily distorted samples of her voice in an attempt to &lt;em&gt;derail&lt;/em&gt; and build up tension in similar fashion (hopefully) to the original poem. It also allowed me to become better acquainted with filters and techniques commonly used in electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several authors debated a hidden message in the original Man’yō-gana version of the text, by putting together the last syllable of each line, which could be read as &lt;em&gt;toka [toga] nakute shisu&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;咎無くて死す&lt;/span&gt;, ‘die without sin’). I tried to incorporate this in the song as some form of hidden message, using distorted whispers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="[background]" class="fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/music/full_bg_smaller.jpg" title="[background]"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the YouTube video I created a wallpaper using a photograph I once took at the grave of Tokugawa Ieyasu in Nikko. At the time of the picture, a typhoon rapidly approached our region and due to heavy rainfall, we were practically alone. Nonetheless, the storm’s influence on the ancient cryptomeria forest and the bronze urn of Tokugawa Ieyasu left for a breathtaking and very humbling sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a bit of editing and used several free Japanese calligraphy fonts to display the contents of the poem. I found the english translation, by Esoteric Buddhist specialist Prof. Dr. Ryūichi Abe …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2017-03-12:/blog/2017/03/new-song-iroha-uta/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Music</category><category>Composing</category></item><item><title>織田信長とアルベール一世：我々の国民の共有している歴史</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/12/oda-nobunaga-to-aruberu-issei/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;私は先週、ブリュッセルで行われた日本語のスピーチコンテストに参加して、「ベルギー・日本友好１５０周年」のために歴史的なスピーチを発表する機会をいただきました。すると、参加者の他者が非常に高いレベルにあったし、質疑応答もやや恥ずかしくなっても、何とか第三位に入賞しました。このブログのエントリーは私が書いたスピーチの原稿です。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="_1"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#_1"&gt;スピーチ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会場にお集まりの皆様、こんにちは！ルーバン大学日本学科3年生のスティービーと申します。私は子供の頃から日本の文化と歴史に大変興味がありました。そして日本学科に入学して2年間勉強をすることで自分の知識をもっと広め、深めることができました。更に、来年日本へ留学する可能性があることや、今年が「ベルギー・日本友好150周年」の年であることから、日本の歴史だけでなく、特に独立前のベルギーと日本の400年も前に遡る両国が共有している歴史への関心も高まってきました。そのため、この発表「我々の国民の共有している歴史」では、二つの歴史的逸話を紹介して、ベルギー人と日本人の友好についてお話したいと思います。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;この共有されている歴史、すなわち、両国間の共感は、私たちの国の歴史的展開がほぼ同じように進んだからだと考えます。ベ …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-12-01:/blog/2016/12/oda-nobunaga-to-aruberu-issei/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Japan</category><category>History</category><category>Belgium</category><category>Speech</category></item><item><title>Oda Nobunaga and King Albert - The shared history of our nations’ people</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/11/oda-nobunaga-and-king-albert-the-shared-history-of-our-nations-people/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;For this year’s Japanese Speech Contest in Brussels, I had the pleasure to prepare and hold a speech in honor of Belgium and Japan’s 150&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; year of mutual friendship. Despite some hickups and an incredibly high level amongst the other candidates (meeting all these excellent Japanese learners was both an extremely humbling experience as well as a perfect motivation booster for the coming years) I was awarded 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; prize. This blog contains my speech’s English translation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="speech"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#speech"&gt;Speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! I’m Stevie, a Belgian student at the university of Leuven and currently third year student in the faculty of Japan Studies. Lately, through my studies and the realization of 150 years of amity between our two nations, I’ve gained an increased interest in our mutual history; a long shared history dating from before Belgium was even officially recognized an independent country. That’s why, through this presentation, I would like to focus on two historical anecdotes in history that show not just a friendship between our countries’ governments, but a friendship between our people as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my belief that the empathy shared between our people stems from similar historical developments. &lt;span data-pullquote="Just as Belgium found its independency while cornered between the great nations of France and Germany, Japan rose as an independent world power despite the large Chinese and Russian empires on one side, and the Western industrial powers on the other."&gt;Just as Belgium found its independency while cornered between the great nations of France and Germany, Japan rose as an independent world power despite the large Chinese and Russian empires on one side, and the Western industrial powers on the other.&lt;/span&gt; Thus, during the Meiji Period and the subsequent Iwakura Mission, Belgium was occasionally reported as a potential model nation with its people possessing a high spirit of self-reliance and independence, just as the Japanese people have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="king-albert-and-oda-nobunaga"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#king-albert-and-oda-nobunaga"&gt;King Albert and Oda Nobunaga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this logic, during the first world war, Belgium was reported on a daily base in Japanese media as a brave, strong-spirited country that fell victim to the conquering German empire, while Belgian King Albert continued resistance from a small village near the French border. Eventually, the Tokyo and Osaka Asahi Newspaper launched both a campaign to collect funds for Belgium and planned the presentation of a Japanese sword to the Belgian king on the occasion of his birthday and as a means to encourage the brave resistance of the Belgian people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sugimura Kotaro, a journalist of the Asahi Newspaper, was sent to deliver the sword and travelled through Great Britain in late 1914. Here, he witnessed a great number …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-11-28:/blog/2016/11/oda-nobunaga-and-king-albert-the-shared-history-of-our-nations-people/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Japan</category><category>History</category><category>Belgium</category><category>Speech</category></item><item><title>Japan Cultural Festival in Antwerp 2016</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/11/japan-cultural-festival-in-antwerp-2016/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="poster" class="border right" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/tsuuyaku/poster.jpg" title="poster"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend the NHK Culture Center and the Embassy of Japan in Belgium organized the 30&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; edition of the Japan Cultural Festival, held in Antwerp in celebration of 150 years of friendship between our two nations. Together with a few classmates and upper class students I had the honor and pleasure of joining this event’s staff of interpreter volunteers, spending my last 3 days assisting two incredible (and incredibly kind) artists convey their works to a large crowd of highly interested Japan aficionados.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The festival included a wide variety of exhibitions, demonstrations and performances related to Japanese artistry: dances, drum performances, calligraphy, clothing, tea ceremonies, etc. During the festival I was responsible for a stand on artistic calligraphy and a Japanese embroidery technique called &lt;em&gt;sashiko&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;刺し子&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, two fields of artistry I had no prior experience in and thus learned a lot about through my interpreting those 3 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interpreting as barely just a third year student was quite an experience. The amount of technical terms related to embroidery processionally made it pretty difficult to accurately translate everything in real time but I think I somehow managed to convey the overall meaning most of the time. Something that quite surprised me was how engrossed I got in my interpreting as well as the group sense we fostered. I felt a certain sense of pride every time guests complimented on our booth’s exhibitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that surprised me was the high interest in these art forms I originally thought maybe to be too specific to draw large crowds. Both days of the event were highly visited and left us drowned in work to the point we barely had time to eat a snack at noon. At the end everyone was exhausted, but it was definitely a good kind of exhaustion, and spending the evening together having dinner in the city center of my hometown made it all the more a pleasant memory!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="festival3" class="border fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/tsuuyaku/festival3.jpg" title="festival3"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:center; font-size: 85%;"&gt;(me and the two artists, Hashimoto Shiori and Chiharu Minato, at our booth)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="festival1" class="border fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/tsuuyaku/festival1.jpg" title="festival1"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:center; font-size: 85%;"&gt;(The opening ceremony was extremely formal, but I was pleased to occasionally perceive a little joke in the Japanese speeches that didn’t translate well in Dutch)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="festival2" class="border fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/tsuuyaku/festival2.jpg" title="festival2"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:center; font-size: 85%;"&gt;(Alas, due to a dead cellphone battery I wasn’t able to take a lot of pictures of the events.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-11-13:/blog/2016/11/japan-cultural-festival-in-antwerp-2016/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Japan</category><category>Belgium</category><category>Culture</category><category>Volunteering</category><category>Interpreting</category></item><item><title>Writing a Musical?</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/writing-a-musical/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I cooperated with several other students at my music academy to write the music for a small local musical called “&lt;strong&gt;Dating&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;a musical for the highly educated&lt;/em&gt;” (a supposedly ironic, yet pretentious title I’m less than fond of, honestly). Being slightly unsatisfied with the end-result of my own compositions, I’ve since started rearranging them. I intend to describe the process in this little blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-idea"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-idea"&gt;The Idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the wings of our arrangement teacher, we collaborated with the Word &amp;amp; Song division of our music academy and the Kontich Orchestra. The W&amp;amp;S division provided the actors, came up with a general concept and devised a tentative track list as well as additional background information we were to use as guidelines in our compositions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We held frequent meetings with the Kontich Orchestra for rehearsals, further fine tuning, and to get a better feel of each musician’s capacities and the sound of their instrument. In the end, due time limits, I only contributed two songs but I’m happy to have been part of the project despite the in my opinion somewhat pretentious premise. The following flyer was distributed around town:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="folder" class="border fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/musical/folder.jpg" title="folder"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-story"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-story"&gt;The Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Dating&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;a musical for the highly educated&lt;/em&gt;” involves a group of supposedly less than highly educated adults from out of town who’ve met up for a double date using a popular dating site. A couple of teenagers, obsessed with selfies and being young (the average age of the writing team was about 50 years by the way) take note of this and decide to ruin their fun by pretending to be each others date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere near the end, things get heated up so much that a member of the audience, using classic “&lt;em&gt;breaking the fourth wall&lt;/em&gt;“&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; techniques, calls the musical to an abrupt end by spouting some idealistic wishes on the concepts of love and relationships. At this stage, &lt;strong&gt;Bacchus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Cupido&lt;/strong&gt; make their entrance in a rather absurd fashion and save the day by convincing the audience that yes, it’s important to believe in love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I just wrote the music! I take no part in this plot!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-songs"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-songs"&gt;The Songs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-banana-caves"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-banana-caves"&gt;The Banana Caves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song is played right at the start of the second half of the musical. As the cast enters the bar and spends a while having a few drinks too many before breaking out into dance, my …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-24:/blog/2016/10/writing-a-musical/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Music</category><category>Composing</category><category>Musical</category></item><item><title>Narrating Newspapers: Weekly Vlogging as a Japanese 練習</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/narrating-newspapers-weekly-vlogging-as-a-japanese-renshu/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: currently on hold due my upcoming exams. Priorities!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to up my Japanese pronunciation and become more fluent in Japanese text recitation, I’ve tried getting acquainted with vlogging in Japanese. I’ll (hopefully) publish weekly videos of myself narrating a newly posted news article published on one of the mainstream Japanese newspaper websites, using a classic streaming-style set-up so any potential viewer can read along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, I’ve found it a fun exercise to try and translate the article as well as create subtitles (maybe I should try fan-subbing some anime or drama one of these days, if I ever find the time, that is~).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this will become a weekly thing I won’t be posting new blog-articles for every single video I do, but feel free to follow me on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PoppeStevie"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or subscribe to my &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-wW8gg1lGVn99X9ue6_eVA"&gt;YT channel&lt;/a&gt;. For now it’s limited to these narrations and (&lt;em&gt;wip&lt;/em&gt;) music, but actually I’ve always wanted to try actual vlogging and/or podcasts.... Maybe it’ll happen one day (when I’m studying abroadかな～).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="videos"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#videos"&gt;Videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="week-9"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#week-9"&gt;Week 9: &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;殺人未遂容疑&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Mainichi Shumbun article is another one related to JR. A guy tried to push two people of train platforms in Osaka and is now wanted for double attempted homicide. The original article can be found on &lt;em&gt;Mainichi Shimbun&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="http://mainichi.jp/articles/20161212/k00/00m/040/075000c#"&gt;線路に６３歳女性突き落とす　男逃走　大阪&lt;/a&gt;). As usual I’ve included English subtitles. &lt;em&gt;(22/11/16)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qknMcYiQ2tk" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="640"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="week-8-jr"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#week-8-jr"&gt;Week 8: &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;ＪＲ山手線&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week’s article is on a small accident on the JR Yamata line caused by a overheated cellphone charger. The original article can be found on &lt;em&gt;Mainichi Shimbun&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="http://mainichi.jp/articles/20161205/k00/00m/040/029000c"&gt;ＪＲ山手線 車内で携帯充電器が発煙&lt;/a&gt;). As usual I’ve included English subtitles. &lt;em&gt;(22/11/16)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O6KXLcDbeRY" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="640"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="week-7"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#week-7"&gt;Week 7: &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;織田信長とアルベール一世&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due the Brussels Japanese Speech Contest this weekend I didn’t record any news articles, but instead uploaded a recording of my speech entry. I’ve posted the original speech in Japanese, as well as an English translation on these blogs: &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/12/oda-nobunaga-to-aruberu-issei/"&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/11/oda-nobunaga-and-king-albert-the-shared-history-of-our-nations-people/"&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;em&gt;(27/11/16)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cHx3xUfM_DY" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="640"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="week-6-ptsd"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#week-6-ptsd"&gt;Week 6: &lt;span lang="ja"&gt;ＰＴＳＤ治療&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one’s an article on a possible treatment to PTSD. The original article can be found on &lt;em&gt;Asahi Shimbun&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.asahi.com/articles/ASJCM5GVTJCMULBJ00D.html"&gt;恐怖の記憶、書き換える技術開発　ＰＴＳＤ治療に効果か&lt;/a&gt;). As usual …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-17:/blog/2016/10/narrating-newspapers-weekly-vlogging-as-a-japanese-renshu/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Vlog</category><category>Video</category></item><item><title>Anki Add-on: Japanese translations for Korean vocabulary</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/anki-add-on-japanese-translations-for-korean-vocabulary/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have recently started studying Korean as part of the minor I took up at my university. While browsing the internet for helpful resources I found that, like us, a remarkable amount of students of the Korean language have knowledge of Japanese and/or study both simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As anyone browsing my blog might have guessed, I’m pretty fond of using Anki for assisting in vocab acquisition, and thus use it for Korean vocabulary as well, using both existing sets and my own based on our textbooks.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Having a broad base in Japanese, I thought it would be more efficient having a link between the two languages in my flashcards. In order to assist myself and other learners of both Japanese and Korean, I wrote an Anki add-on that adds Japanese translations of Korean expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to my previous Anki posts, this blog post serves as a brief tutorial on setting up the add-on and adding Japanese translations to our cards. We’ll install an Anki add-on, alter our card-layout to display the Japanese expressions in a fashionable manner, and finally bulk-edit our existing cards to actually add them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="anki-korean-japanese-add-on"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#anki-korean-japanese-add-on"&gt;Anki Korean-Japanese add-on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The add-on scrapes Weblio’s online Korean-Japanese dictionary for all translations aside from the usually present character decomposition. The expression 개 (transcribed as &lt;em&gt;gae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or &lt;em&gt;kae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and means either dog or is used as a particular counter), for example, results in the &lt;a href="http://kjjk.weblio.jp/content/%EA%B0%9C"&gt;following page&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="weblio" class="fborder fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/korean/weblio.jpg" title="weblio"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(If I feel like it, or if there’s some demand for it, I’ll expand the add-on to scrape the example sentences as seen above as well)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="download"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Japanese Definitions for Korean Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt; add-on has a page on Ankiweb’s &lt;a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/553926167"&gt;plug-in page&lt;/a&gt;, but as usual we’ll install the plug-in using the Desktop Anki application. Go to &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Add-ons&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Browse &amp;amp; Install&lt;/strong&gt;, and copy-paste &lt;strong&gt;553926167&lt;/strong&gt; in the pop-up dialog. Restart the application to complete the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The add-on expects two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The field containing your Korean expression should be called: &lt;code&gt;Korean&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The note-type should contain a field called &lt;code&gt;Japanese&lt;/code&gt; which will contain the Japanese translations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Both names can be edited in the &lt;code&gt;JapaneseDefinitionsKoreanVoc.py&lt;/code&gt; file by opening it with a text-editor and changing the names listed in the beginning. The file can be found on the Anki’s add-on folder on your computer (e.g. &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\your_username\Documents\Anki\addons&lt;/code&gt;))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a new field &lt;code&gt;Japanese&lt;/code&gt;, open the …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-15:/blog/2016/10/anki-add-on-japanese-translations-for-korean-vocabulary/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Korean</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 4: Making the switch - J-J definitions in your vocab cards</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-4-making-the-switch-j-j-definitions-in-your-vocab-cards/</link><description>&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;
&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;2021 Update&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of September 30, 2020, Sanseido &lt;a href="sanseido-publ.co.jp/sp/wbdct_close.html"&gt;stopped&lt;/a&gt; their web dictionary service. This tutorial is thus rendered obsolete. &lt;a href="https://kokugo.jitenon.jp/"&gt;Kokugo Jiten Online&lt;/a&gt; seems like a good alternative. I’ll look into updating the Sanseido add-on to use the above instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve been studying Japanese for a while now and reached a level of Japanese adequate enough to understand (simple) texts. Drilling new vocabulary has become a daily routine so entangled in your lifestyle you barely notice anymore. If you were to describe your current level of proficiency, you’d proudly present yourself as an intermediate level learner. Sounds familiar? Let’s take it a notch further by adding Japanese definitions&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to our Anki-sets and reduce our dependency on English definition crutches!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve followed my &lt;a href="#"&gt;previous tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on adding Japanese example sentences to your vocabulary cards, this tutorial will feel very similar: we’ll install an Anki add-on, alter our card-layout to display the definitions in a fashionable manner, and finally bulk-edit our existing cards to actually add them. (This might be my first tutorial worthy of the header &lt;strong&gt;quick&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="sanseido-add-on"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#sanseido-add-on"&gt;Sanseido add-on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various online monolingual dictionaries for Japanese vocabulary. I personally like &lt;a href="http://www.weblio.jp"&gt;Weblio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://dictionary.goo.ne.jp/"&gt;Goo&lt;/a&gt;, but for our Anki cards we’ll use &lt;a href="http://www.sanseido.net/"&gt;Sanseido&lt;/a&gt; - their definitions are usually more concise as the other dictionaries and tend to employ more comprehensible vocabulary. Luck has it someone has already written an anki add-on to serve our blog’s purpose. The result of our work will look as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="anki-gyakuten" class="fborder fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/anki-gyakuten.jpg" title="anki-gyakuten"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="download"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Sanseido Definitions&lt;/strong&gt; add-on has a page on Ankiweb’s &lt;a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1967553085"&gt;plug-in page&lt;/a&gt;, but as usual we’ll install the plug-in using the Desktop Anki application. Go to &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Add-ons&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Browse &amp;amp; Install&lt;/strong&gt;, and copy-paste &lt;strong&gt;1967553085&lt;/strong&gt; in the pop-up dialog. Restart the application to complete the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The note-types of the vocabulary you want Japanese definitions for will need a new field to contain the definition. On the desktop Anki application, press &lt;kbd&gt;CTRL-SHIFT-N&lt;/kbd&gt;, or click &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Manage Note Types&lt;/strong&gt;, to enter the note-type management screen. Select the note-type of the cards you’d like to contain example sentences and click &lt;strong&gt;fields&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="anki-notetype-select" class="fborder fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/anki-notetype-select.jpg" title="anki-notetype-select"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next screen, click &lt;strong&gt;add&lt;/strong&gt; and call the field &lt;code&gt;Sanseido&lt;/code&gt;. Now close this screen. On the previous note-type management screen, click &lt;strong&gt;cards&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ll edit our lay-out and display the new field in our cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="anki-note-lay-out"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#anki-note-lay-out"&gt;Anki Note Lay-out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lay-out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the CSS code below to the shared …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-02:/blog/2016/10/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-4-making-the-switch-j-j-definitions-in-your-vocab-cards/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>Travels: a week in Transylvania</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;With the academic school year rapidly approaching, we decided on a short last-minute trip abroad and booked tickets to Romania. We spent spent a week,traveling through the historic region of Transylvania, commonly associated with vampire folklore, and situated between the imposing Carpathian mountains. A rich history, ranging from a feudal agricultural culture to a post-war communist regime and following shift to a capitalist mode of production, leaves a very layered culture represented in all aspects from architecture to national mentality. This short blog covers our itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, Transylvania, a traditionally more agricultural region, has been conquered by plenty of nations, including the Roman Empire, Bulgaria, Hungary, the Ottoman Empire and the Austro-Hungarian Empire until it’s disintegration following the first world war. Transylvania, as the rest of Romania, played an important role in European politics throughout the Interwar period, but suffered greatly through the second world war and the subsequent communist regime (1947 - 1989). The 1989 revolutions brought an end to Romanian Communist leader Ceausescu’s repressive regime&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and led to the implementation of the free market as well as a 2007 accession to the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of the people are ethnically Romanian, but there’s a sizable Hungarian and Roma population as well. Especially the Romani people, an ethnic minority originating from northwestern India and historically serving as slaves in Romania, undergo plenty of discrimination both in Romania and throughout Europe, thus leaving them segregated and socially vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As “poor college students” without driver licenses, we relied heavily on public transport. Luckily, Romania has an excellent public transport system both within cities as throughout the country. Thus commuting through the city felt as easy as at home. Unfortunately, due to time issues, we had to cut several important destinations (such as Sighisoara) out of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bucharest"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#bucharest"&gt;Bucharest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Bucharest’s Otopeni airport on the 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of September and after a brief stroll through town headed to Gara de Nord train station for a train to Sinaia. As a West-European citizen, the contrasts were a bit surprising. Balkan and Latin architectural influences contradict strongly with the tight, functional soviet designs,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and even the more touristic access able historical center underwent heavy decay and is now mostly covered in graffiti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29865697296/in/album-72157673147829801/" title="Decayed building"&gt;&lt;img alt="Decayed building" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8129/29865697296_916f618502.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="center border" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29606361880/in/album-72157673147829801/" title="Constructivist architecture"&gt;&lt;img alt="Constructivist architecture" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8492/29606361880_02850fb836.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sinaia"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#sinaia"&gt;Sinaia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sinaia is a quaint little town about an hour and …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-24:/blog/2016/09/travels-a-week-in-transylvania/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Romania</category><category>Transylvania</category><category>Travels</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 3: contextualize your vocab cards with example sentences</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-3-contextualize-your-vocab-cards-with-example-sentences/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;So you’ve followed &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/"&gt;my previous tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and set up this wonderful environment for creating vocabulary cards with audio and &lt;em&gt;furigana&lt;/em&gt; based on all kinds of Japanese text you find online. Yet, while studying your new set, you feel this nagging feeling deep down inside… There’s something missing, still… “&lt;em&gt;Hm, could it be…?&lt;/em&gt;”, you ponder quietly. &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;. You need &lt;code&gt;Japanese example sentences for providing context to your vocab cards&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the common pitfalls of learning Japanese vocabulary through Anki cards is memorizing them loose of context. Perhaps you’ve found yourself in a situation having no particular problems recalling vocabulary whilst reviewing your cards, but less so when confronted with real-life situations. If that sounds familiar, one way to counter this common problem would be to install an additional Anki add-on, and bring our vocab cards to a next level by adding Japanese example sentences and their translations. This blog offers an easy step-by-step tutorial on setting this up. Additionally, for those who’ve followed my previous tutorial, I add some extra code to combine the example sentence functions with the instant-import features of the Firefox plug-in Rikaisama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="plug-in"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#plug-in"&gt;Plug-in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll use an existing Anki add-on called &lt;strong&gt;Japanese Example Sentences&lt;/strong&gt; to add Japanese sentences taken from &lt;a href="https://tatoeba.org/eng/"&gt;Tatoeba.org&lt;/a&gt;, a “collaborative, open, free and even addictive” community on producing example sentences. The result of our work will look as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="anki-contextcard" class="fborder fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/anki-contextcard.jpg" title="anki-contextcard"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="download"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japanese Example Sentences add-on has a page on Ankiweb’s &lt;a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/2413435972"&gt;plug-in page&lt;/a&gt;, but as usual we’ll install the plug-in using the Desktop Anki application. Go to &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Add-ons&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Browse &amp;amp; Install&lt;/strong&gt;, and copy-paste &lt;strong&gt;2413435972&lt;/strong&gt; in the pop-up dialog. Restart the application to complete the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: as user &lt;em&gt;nwt&lt;/em&gt; mentioned in the comments, this example-set is fairly outdated. Follow &lt;a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/2413435972"&gt;the instructions&lt;/a&gt; left in the plug-in’s comment section to update to the most recent set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a test Anki deck to work with, I’ve uploaded an example set, the result of my previous Anki tutorial, containing the necessary notetype and two test-notes for download: &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/xnj67hqj3cubfn2/Rikai%20vocab.apkg?dl=0"&gt;Example set Rikai &lt;i class="icon-download-alt"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The note-types of the vocabulary you want sentences for will need a new field to contain these. On the desktop Anki application, press &lt;kbd&gt;CTRL-SHIFT-N&lt;/kbd&gt;, or click &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Manage Note Types&lt;/strong&gt;, to enter the note-type management screen. Select the note-type of the cards you’d like to contain example sentences and click &lt;strong&gt;fields&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="anki-notetype-select" class="border fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/anki-notetype-select.jpg" title="anki-notetype-select"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next screen …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-17:/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-3-contextualize-your-vocab-cards-with-example-sentences/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>Waarom Japanologie?</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/waarom-japanologie/</link><description>
&lt;!-- PELICAN_START_SUMMARY --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoals velen in mijn richting ontstond mijn interesse in Japan al op jonge leeftijd onder invloed van het zogenaamde &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cool_Japan"&gt;Cool Japan&lt;/a&gt;: de globale verspreiding van Japanse popcultuur (muziek, televisie, games, …) die sinds de jaren ‘80 geleidelijk aan begon door te sijpelen in ook onze nationale media. Het zou, zo blijkt, zelfs een interesse worden die zodanig groeide dat ik er jaren later mijn studiekeuze door liet beïnvloeden. Vaak krijg ik bij vermelding daarvan echter nog, zoals mijn klasgenoten ongetwijfeld kunnen beamen, een hoop verbaasde blikken toegesmeten en dus ook dé klassieke hamvraag voorgeschoteld: &lt;strong&gt;Waarom nu juist Japanologie&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Als tweedejaars werd ik eerder dit jaar gevraagd om op een opendeurdag van onze richting een kort woordje over mijn persoonlijke ervaringen met Japanologie aan de KU Leuven, waar ik aldos ook bovenstaande vraag probeerde te beantwoorden. Toch werd ik daarna door verschillende bezorgde ouders aangesproken met enkele niet geheel onterechte vragen als “&lt;em&gt;Ja maar, wat zijt ge daar nu mee?&lt;/em&gt;”, “&lt;em&gt;Leert ge dan enkel over Japan? Oeioei, is da ni héél beperkt?&lt;/em&gt;” en “&lt;em&gt;Is Japan nog wel relevant?&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Om beter de oorspronkelijke vraag “Waarom Japanologie?” te beantwoorden lijkt het mij het beste om te vertrekken vanuit juist die drie bovenstaande vragen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="vragen"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#vragen"&gt;Vragen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="japanologie-dan-leert-ge-enkel-over-japan-oeioei"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#japanologie-dan-leert-ge-enkel-over-japan-oeioei"&gt;“Japanologie? Dan leert ge enkel over Japan? Oeioei!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Als je naar &lt;a href="https://onderwijsaanbod.kuleuven.be/opleidingen/n/CQ_50268982.htm#activetab=diploma_omschrijving"&gt;de onderwijsaanbod-pagina van Japanologie&lt;/a&gt; aan de KU Leuven gaat krijg je het volgende te zien:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bachelor in de taal- en regiostudies: japanologie (Leuven)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Bachelor of Arts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In de bacheloropleiding Japanologie bestudeer je in de eerste plaats het moderne Japans op een intensieve manier. De opleiding plaatst het Japans steeds centraal tegenover de achtergrond van de Japanse cultuur, geschiedenis, filosofie, economie en politiek. Je kiest een minor, wat je de mogelijkheid geeft om je eigen interesses beter in te werken in je studie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het spreekt voor zich dat de Japanse taal en theoretische vakken gericht op Japan centraal staan in onze richting, maar bovenstaande tekst zegt toch wat meer: Japanologie aan de KU Leuven is een onderdeel van taal- en regiostudies, en levert een &lt;em&gt;Bachelor of Arts&lt;/em&gt; op: een diploma binnen de geestes- of sociale wetenschappen. &lt;span data-pullquote="Concreter betekent dat dat een student Japanologie een hoop vaardigheden onder de knie hoort te krijgen die op eerste zicht geen rechtstreeks verband met Japan lijken te houden maar de student vormt om genuanceerder en meer kritisch te kijken naar niet enkel Japan, maar de hele wereld ."&gt;Concreter betekent dat dat een student Japanologie een hoop vaardigheden onder de knie hoort te krijgen die op eerste zicht geen rechtstreeks verband met Japan lijken te houden maar de student vormt om genuanceerder en meer kritisch te kijken naar niet enkel Japan, maar de hele wereld .&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dat lijkt me ook logisch. Enkel kennis …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-14:/blog/2016/09/waarom-japanologie/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Japanologie</category><category>KU Leuven</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 2: an efficient vocab mining set-up with Anki and Rikaisama</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 2018~: Rikaisama has been rendered obsolete since 2018 updates broke Firefox’ support of unsigned XUL-based add-ons. Nevertheless, this guide can still prove useful in two ways: further use of Rikaisama through XUL-supporting Firefox-derivatives such as Waterfox, Pale Moon and Basilisk, as well as the list of applications for Browser/Anki-integration listed in the second half of this guide. As I personally use Waterfox, I’ll refer to Waterfox as main option hereafter. Another option is to use Yomichan for Chrome, described &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/04/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-5-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama-yomichan/"&gt;in this updated blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you want to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; read a Japanese novel without ending up crying yourself to sleep realizing you know &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;, Jon Snow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; learn Japanese by watching anime, but like, for real?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; create beautiful Anki sets filled with handpicked vocabulary, hidden &lt;em&gt;furigana&lt;/em&gt; reading-aids, AND crystal-clear audio pronunciations, all without spending days of mind-numbing copy-pasting?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the lovely world of &lt;code&gt;Integrated Anki &amp;amp; Rikaisama&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hove-over Japanese dictionary plug-in &lt;strong&gt;Rikaichan&lt;/strong&gt; and its Chrome variant &lt;strong&gt;Rikaikun&lt;/strong&gt; have already been widely established as incredibly helpful tools for reading Japanese online. Nevertheless, one major function remained missing still: a seamless integration with Anki for efficient vocabulary mining. A recent expansion of the original Rikaichan, aptly named &lt;strong&gt;Rikaisama&lt;/strong&gt; (it’s a &lt;em&gt;pun&lt;/em&gt;!), adds several new features including communication with the Anki API, &lt;em&gt;Sanseido Web Dictionary&lt;/em&gt;‘s J-J dictionary definitions, access to &lt;em&gt;J-Pod101&lt;/em&gt;‘s audio-files,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and more.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Concretely, this means audio playback of tens of thousands of words and expressions as well as easy integration of new vocab into Anki. Despite these incredibly useful features, Rikaisama remains fairly  about. To counter that, this blog serves as a brief tutorial on setting up a Rikaisama/Anki environment as well as demonstrating some useful real-life use-cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="rikaisama"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#rikaisama"&gt;Rikaisama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="download"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Rikaichan, Rikaisama is a &lt;del&gt;Firefox&lt;/del&gt; Waterfox plugin, available for download on their &lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/rikaisama/files/"&gt;sourceforge download page&lt;/a&gt; (free, of course). If you’re an avid Chrome supporter, this one might be worth switching for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="rikaisama" class="right" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/rikaisama.jpg" title="rikaisama"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After installation you’ll have two new buttons at your disposal, either already visible at the top-right of your menubar, or in &lt;del&gt;Firefox&lt;/del&gt; Waterfox’s toolbar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The left one activates Rikaisama. I just leave it permanently open. The right one switches the Rikaisama lookupbar. I don’t use this one often so I hide it in the toolbox myself, but for now we’ll need it to access Rikaisama’s settings. Open the toolbar and click the right-most icon to open …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-08:/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Rikaisama</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki (effectively) (in an academic context)</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Those who know me well might accuse me of preaching popular memorization tool &lt;strong&gt;Anki&lt;/strong&gt; as a revolution in studying, and they wouldn’t be that far off. Over the past year I have extensively integrated this software in my studies, with (to me personally) remarkable results in both productivity and academic grades. There are, however, some pitfalls for the casual user to take heed of, and getting the full benefit of your time requires cultivating a proper mindset. Considering the amounts of time I mention Anki abundantly on this site, I decided to write my own  &lt;del&gt;&lt;em&gt;short&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/del&gt; guide on setting up and using Anki efficiently, as well as describe how I’ve personally integrated Anki in my studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone with an interest in studying Japanese will surely have heard of Anki. It’s covered extensively on all major learning resources on-line, and the canonical self learner’s beginner path seems to be that of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Remembering_the_Kanji_and_Remembering_the_Hanzi#Heisig.27s_method"&gt;Heisig’s Kanji method&lt;/a&gt;, Tae Kim’s online &lt;a href="http://www.guidetojapanese.org/learn/grammar"&gt;Grammar Guide&lt;/a&gt;, and Core 2K/6K/10K,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; all three heavily relying on Anki. Language acquisition certainly remains Anki’s most popular usage, although the software has become broad enough to find it’s way in various other branches (it’s become an integrated routine for medical students, for example, as well as math students thanks to LaTeX support). While it sounds like I’m being paid to advertise Anki, the application remains &lt;strong&gt;free and open source&lt;/strong&gt; (and if you don’t like synchronizing your Anki progress over Anki’s servers you could even set that up on your own as well).&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-is-anki-why-is-anki-how-is-anki"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#what-is-anki-why-is-anki-how-is-anki"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&lt;/em&gt; is Anki? &lt;em&gt;Why&lt;/em&gt; is Anki?! &lt;em&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; is Anki?!?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To recap: Anki is an extremely customizable application designed for memorization, available for free on nearly all the major devices&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; as well as being accessible online. Being able to study on the road (I commute by train, taking me up to three hours of total traveling time every day) and synchronizing your progress at home is a major boon on using your time practically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of studies on methods for efficient learning, and not surprisingly, classic late-night cramming, along passive studying methods as extensive marking and rereading of texts don’t score very high. On the other hand, &lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;active recall testing&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (questioning yourself by actively trying to come up with the answer to a question) and &lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;spaced learning&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (spreading information absorption over long …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-07:/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>Parsing Japanese Text in Markdown-Python for Stylizing and Semantic Purposes</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/parsing-japanese-text-in-markdown-python-for-stylizing-and-semantic-purposes/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Due to my studies I (will) often use Japanese in my blog. As I gave some thought to typography and readability, I found the default appearance of Japanese text to be in stark contrast with the rest of my design.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; To target specifically Japanese text, I wrote a small Markdown-Python extension for use in static blog generators as Jekyll and Pelican (or pretty much anything that utilizes Markdown-Python to parse Markdown in HTML) and embed such text in a span with the language attribute set to Japanese. The added, and probably more important bonus, aside from styling and semantic reasons, is that this method counters the negative effects of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Han_unification"&gt;Han unification&lt;/a&gt; in so-called CJK-languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="download"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve added the extension on its &lt;a href="https://github.com/steviepoppe/lang_ja_span_markdown"&gt;own repository&lt;/a&gt; on my GitHub for anyone interested, but as it serves its purpose for me as-is I have no further interest in maintaining it at the moment.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="installation"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#installation"&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy the &lt;code&gt;japanese.py&lt;/code&gt; script into your python-markdown extension directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using &lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/latest/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; as static site generator, open your project’s &lt;code&gt;pelicanconf.py&lt;/code&gt; and add &lt;code&gt;'japanese'&lt;/code&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;MD_EXTENSIONS&lt;/code&gt; list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class="n"&gt;MD_EXTENSIONS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'japanese'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h1 id="usage"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#usage"&gt;Usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a simple regular expression &lt;code&gt;(\{\{)(.+?)(\}\})&lt;/code&gt;, the extension treats double {} brackets as span tags with a &lt;code&gt;lang="ja"&lt;/code&gt; attribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;    {{読書クラブ}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;will output&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;span&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;lang&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;"ja"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;読書クラブ&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;span&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example 1&lt;/strong&gt; (fonts): just compare &lt;span style="font-size: 135%;"&gt;&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;&lt;ruby&gt;&lt;rb&gt;読書&lt;/rb&gt;&lt;rp&gt;(&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;rt&gt;どくしょ&lt;/rt&gt;&lt;rp&gt;)&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;/ruby&gt;クラブ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (custom) to &lt;span style="font-size: 130%;"&gt;&lt;ruby&gt;&lt;rb&gt;読書&lt;/rb&gt;&lt;rp&gt;(&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;rt&gt;どくしょ&lt;/rt&gt;&lt;rp&gt;)&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;/ruby&gt;クラブ&lt;/span&gt; (Meiryo) to &lt;span style='font-size: 130%; font-family: "MS Gothic";'&gt;&lt;ruby&gt;&lt;rb&gt;読書&lt;/rb&gt;&lt;rp&gt;(&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;rt&gt;どくしょ&lt;/rt&gt;&lt;rp&gt;)&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;/ruby&gt;クラブ&lt;/span&gt; (MS Gothic default).&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example 2&lt;/strong&gt; (unihan): compare the Chinese to Japanese characters: &lt;span lang="zh" style="font-size: 130%; font-family: 'Quicksand',sans-serif;"&gt;隆&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span lang="ja" style="font-size: 135%;"&gt;隆&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span lang="zh" style="font-size: 130%; font-family: 'Quicksand',sans-serif;"&gt;誤&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span lang="ja" style="font-size: 135%;"&gt;誤&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span lang="zh" style="font-size: 130%; font-family: 'Quicksand',sans-serif;"&gt;直&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span lang="ja" style="font-size: 135%;"&gt;直&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="styling"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#styling"&gt;Styling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it’s a bit of a risk performance-wise, I’m quite a fan of Google’s free web-fonts.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Due the complexity of the Japanese character-set, development on these have been slow&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noto_fonts"&gt;Google’s Noto Font&lt;/a&gt; is getting quite efficient and with the Japanese font set supporting near 7000 characters, it should pose no problem for most web-projects. Since it works better, typography-wise, with the rest of my fonts, I use this one over fonts as Meiryo that are more widespread across all platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the CSS below, I ensure max compatibility by using Meiryo and others as fall-back if the page can’t connect to Google’s font API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;5 …&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-06:/blog/2016/09/parsing-japanese-text-in-markdown-python-for-stylizing-and-semantic-purposes/</guid><category>technical</category><category>python</category><category>pelican</category><category>markdown</category><category>Japanese</category><category>fonts</category></item><item><title>Visiting a Japanese Elementary School - An (Awkward) Experience to Remember</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year us second year Japanese Students were invited to participate in an international speech contest (theme: “tell an interesting story”), organized by Kobe University. Just this week we were informed that the video-recordings of those entries had been uploaded to the contest’s website and were available for all to watch.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; My story is a classic “awkward Japanese language mix-up” anecdote from a school trip to a Japanese elementary school in Brussels, which I’ll touch upon in this post, alongside the embedded video. (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;日本の方、あまり自信がないのですが、もしよろしければ是非ともご覧ください！&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: I just found out that I somehow managed to win first prize out of all the foreign contestants!! This is so cool to hear! Thanks for the cookies, Kobe University! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cookies" class="fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/kobe_cookies.jpg" title="cookies"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-video"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-video"&gt;The Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="video"&gt;
&lt;video class="video-js vjs-default-skin" controls="" data-setup="{}" id="pelican-installation" poster="/static/screencasts/pelican-installation.png" preload="auto"&gt;
&lt;source src="http://www.speech-data.jp/chotto/media/2015F_sub/f2015037s.mp4" type="video/mp4"/&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video, along with my participation entry, is available at &lt;a href="http://www.speech-data.jp/chotto/2015F_sub/2015037.html"&gt;speech-data.jp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-story"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-story"&gt;The story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story isn’t that interesting and a bit embarrassing, but here goes anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cookies" class="right border" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/omoshiroi/brabo.jpg" title="cookies"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As second year students Japanese Studies, our class participated in an excursion to a Japanese elementary school in Brussels: a fun opportunity to practice our language skills as well as have some fun playing games and learn about cultural differences and customs. The event even warranted a small post on the &lt;strong&gt;JSB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; section on &lt;a href="http://blogs.yahoo.co.jp/jsbbxl/55269213.html"&gt;yahoo.co.jp&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In advance of this trip, we split our class in several groups, each preparing a presentation or activity related to our country. Several students in our group live in Antwerp, thus we thought it fun to hold a small presentation on the famous Antwerp folklore story of &lt;em&gt;Druon Antigoon&lt;/em&gt;, an evil giant guarding a bridge and exacting an exorbitant toll of those wishing to cross. Failing to cross meant &lt;em&gt;getting your hand chopped off&lt;/em&gt; and thrown into the river.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; A tad morbid, but it worked well with a popular Belgian children’s game we thought fun to teach them, and in addition, there’s some really nice chocolate treats based on this tale we wanted to distribute afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-game"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-game"&gt;The game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is a variation of a classic tag game called “&lt;em&gt;schipper, mag ik over varen?&lt;/em&gt;” (Eng: “&lt;em&gt;Skipper, may I cross?&lt;/em&gt;”) and usually played on a school’s courtyard or in a larger PE classroom. To play, the …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-28:/blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Video</category><category>KU Leuven</category></item><item><title>Travels: an Icelandic Winter</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/travels-an-icelandic-winter/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;After a long, stressful first semester exam-period, I spent my brief time off traveling to two completely opposite places I’ve been wanting to visit for a very long time: &lt;strong&gt;Rome, Italy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;: one of the coldest winter destinations I could imagine, but a place of stunning natural beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past years, Iceland has gained somewhat of a reputation for its hipster trends and excellent music scene (both true), but its biggest attraction to me personally remains its wild, barren landscapes: sceneries that appeared downright alien at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is our brief itinerary through this beautiful country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iceland, a volcanically active island close to the Arctic Circle, was first inhabited by in the 9&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century by, traditionally claimed, vikings or Norwegian settlers. Most of present-day Icelandic culture finds its roots in its Scandinavian heritage, and even now is mostly famous for its medieval sagas and traditional literature and cuisine, as well as its language closely related to Old Norse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Icelandic plateau is one of the newest in the world, the surroundings closely resemble what our continents must’ve looked like millions of years ago. Agriculturally wise, almost everything is imported from countries as Canada, as the only native growths here are limited to bleak bushes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having only a few days off in-between my exams and the start of my next semester, we were very limited in our itinerary. Even more, neither of us had a driver license at this point, so we were forced to book several tours to show us around (a thing I generally dislike, but actually ended up really pleasant). We stayed several nights in Reykjavik as day-trips to iconic views were easiest to reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="golden-circle-tour"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#golden-circle-tour"&gt;Golden Circle Tour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our first proper day, we took a tour leading us through the &lt;strong&gt;Golden Circle&lt;/strong&gt;, the most popular tourist route in Iceland. the host driving us around was an elderly man taking great pride in his viking roots and often talked of bygone farmer days and Icelandic folklore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our way to our first hallmark, we encountered these beauties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29659421145/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Icelandic Horses"&gt;&lt;img alt="Icelandic Horses" src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8116/29659421145_d7c95e17db_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29368542150/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Icelandic Horse"&gt;&lt;img alt="Icelandic Horse" src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8349/29368542150_58d6c26d02.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="geysir"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#geysir"&gt;Geysir&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geysir&lt;/strong&gt; is the geyser the English word is derived from and erupts about every 10 minutes, hurling boiling water up to 70 meters in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/30520292645/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Geyser"&gt;&lt;img alt="Geyser" src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5537/30520292645_66270303bc.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gulfoss"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#gulfoss"&gt;Gulfoss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gulfoss&lt;/strong&gt;, the Icelandic term for “Golden Falls”, is an iconic waterfall located in the midst of a large canyon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29368545040/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Iceland waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iceland waterfall" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8716/29368545040_a4038c7490.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29548193752/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Iceland waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iceland waterfall" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8061/29548193752_26c6213969.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="center border" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29659422675/in/album-72157672690983682/" title="Iceland waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iceland waterfall" src="https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8031/29659422675_84529724dd.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="national-park-parliament"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#national-park-parliament"&gt;National Park Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thingvellir …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-27:/blog/2016/08/travels-an-icelandic-winter/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Iceland</category></item><item><title>Travels: Romance in Rome</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/travels-romance-in-rome/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;After a long, stressful first semester exam-period, I spent my brief time off traveling to two completely opposite places I’ve been wanting to visit for a very long time: Iceland and the historic city of Rome, Italy, cradle to one of the most well-documented civilizations in western history. In order to recharge our batteries, we decided on this 4-day city trip and, looking back, it really did turn out to be a city that could only be described as a living, breathing open-air museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is our brief itinerary through this charming city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does one start! Rome, Italy’s capital and largest city, has been an extremely influential city for nearly three-thousand years. What is now a global city popular for it’s fashion and design was once a small village on top of a hill that through a series of fascinating military and political events became center of a vast empire and location of Catholicism’s founding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plenty of historical locations have been destroyed following Italy’s rise of Fascism and role in the second World War, but the historic center (Unesco World Heritage) remains as if untouched by time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having limited time, we spent all our time exploring the historical center of Rome and the Vatican. We spent three nights in a lovely bed &amp;amp; breakfast around 15 minutes away from the historical center; which was, due being located in what might might be perceived as a shabby neighborhood, extremely well priced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-1"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#day-1"&gt;Day 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent our first day strolling around the city’s historical center and experiencing some of the more popular destinations such as the famous &lt;strong&gt;Spanish Steps&lt;/strong&gt; square and &lt;strong&gt;Trevi Fountain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29548322602/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Street to Spanish Steps"&gt;&lt;img "="" alt="Street to Spanish Steps" src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8766/29548322602_8d9fa0e2c2_b.jpg" style="height:500px;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As fans of English Romanticism (including poets as &lt;em&gt;Byron&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Shelly&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Keats&lt;/em&gt; we spent a bit of time in what is now a museum dedicated to Keats: the &lt;strong&gt;Keats-Shelley Memorial House museum&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29032997714/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Rome Skyline"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rome Skyline" src="https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8470/29034772843_795100ab25_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We concluded our evening having the most classic dinner one might expect of tourists in Italy: pizza and tiramissu (no regrets).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-2"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#day-2"&gt;Day 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second day was mostly centered around Rome’s ancient &lt;strong&gt;Colosseum&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Palatine Hill&lt;/strong&gt; and the massive &lt;strong&gt;Roman Forum&lt;/strong&gt;. Beautiful ruins rich in history made this area an unforgettable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29032997714/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Colosseum"&gt;&lt;img alt="Colosseum" src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8306/29032997714_5fc1215ae6_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out this area is popular amongst conservatory students as well. Excellent, sunny weather (in the middle of winter!) and a classical violist nearby reciting Vivaldi made for a lovely picnic~.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29032997714/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Rome Skyline"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rome Skyline" src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8174/29548318702_fa92ce10fd_b.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29032999364/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Roman Forum"&gt;&lt;img alt="Roman Forum" src="https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8799/29032999364_2b8c78b94d_b.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="center border" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29032999364/in/album-72157672616633970/" title="Roman Forum"&gt;&lt;img alt="Roman Forum" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8555/29368660840_dbae0e17d8_b.jpg" style="width: 45%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in the …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-26:/blog/2016/08/travels-romance-in-rome/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>Rome</category><category>Italy</category></item><item><title>Pelican Plugin: CSS-only footnote pop-up</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/pelican-plugin-css-only-footnote-pop-up/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a classic staple in any writer’s toolbox, allowing them to, in an unobtrusive way, cite sources or display additional information not directly related to the original argument. Nevertheless it is my impression that online footnotes, through the way they are often implemented imitating printed media footnotes, come over quite counterintuitive and force the reader to disrupt his reading flow,failing to make use of today’s extensive web design possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I royally use footnotes in my markdown writing work-flow&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I figured I’d get acquainted with the Pelican documentation a bit and write a small unobtrusive CSS pop-up plugin to display these on hover for those devices that support it.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My solution is pretty rough and based on the way Python-Markdown parses markdown into HTML. As it’s a quick ‘n dirty workaround untested with other parsers, I have no intention to further maintain this code so feel free to use it however you’d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;content_object_init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;_content&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kc"&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="n"&gt;content&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;_content&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="n"&gt;soup&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'html.parser'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

            &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'sup'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="n"&gt;footnotes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;soup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;find&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;class_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"footnote"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;find_all&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'p'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="n"&gt;footnoteref&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;soup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;find_all&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;class_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"footnote-ref"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

                &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;item&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;enumerate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;footnotes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class="n"&gt;footnoteref&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;parent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'class'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'popup_footnote'&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class="n"&gt;tag&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;soup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;new_tag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'span'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class="n"&gt;tag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;decode_contents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'html.parser'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class="n"&gt;footnoteref&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;insert_after&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;tag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

            &lt;span class="n"&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;_content&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;soup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;decode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;register&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;signals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;content_object_init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;connect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;content_object_init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For simplicity’s sake I use the BeautifulSoup library to locate all footnote references and their respective footnotes. Then I loop through them and copy the contents of the footnote in a ‘popup_footnote’ span I append to the footnote reference container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Styling is done in CSS. Below is my markup. I use &lt;code&gt;left: 50%;&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;transform: translate(-50%, 0);&lt;/code&gt; to center the absolute-positioned pop-up over the footnote reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;21&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class="nt"&gt;sup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nc"&gt;popup_footnote&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;span&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;   
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;text-align&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kc"&gt;justify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;z-index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;display&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kc"&gt;none&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;padding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;line-height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;opacity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mf"&gt;0.9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;border-radius&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;box-shadow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;px&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;px&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;px&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mh"&gt;#D4D4D4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;top&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;transform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;translate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;-50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;position&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kc"&gt;absolute&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;250&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nt"&gt;sup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nc"&gt;popup_footnote&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;hover&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;span&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;display&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kc"&gt;inline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mh"&gt;#111&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;border&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;px&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kc"&gt;solid&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mh"&gt;#eaeaea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mh"&gt;#fffcfc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-25:/blog/2016/08/pelican-plugin-css-only-footnote-pop-up/</guid><category>Technical</category><category>Pelican</category><category>Markdown</category><category>Python</category><category>Footnotes</category></item><item><title>Travels: roadtrip through the Deep South</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/travels-roadtrip-through-the-deep-south/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, me and a couple of friends decided on a summer road-trip throughout the so-called &lt;em&gt;Deep South&lt;/em&gt;, the most southern states of the USA. As we have a shared history of playing in bands and writing music together, my friends and I thought it would be cool to purchase some second-hand instruments and travel through some of the more musically well-known states. This short blog covers our three-week itinerary, with plenty of pictures to go along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="brief-history"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#brief-history"&gt;Brief history &lt;i class="icon-history small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Deep South refers to the seven slave states that originally joined forces in what became known as the Confederate States of America. The historical dependence on slave labor (as well as the proximity to Cuba and Mexico) means that the region has both a large present-day ethnic minority of African-Americans and Hispanic Americans (and a more apparent cultural mix). Therefore, parts of this particular region are also informally called Black Belt (as well as Bible Belt). Simultaneously the region politically tends to be more conservative-leaning; with historic revisionism in regards to the region’s role in, and dependence on, trans-Atlantic slavery often neglected in favor of ‘State rights’ rhetoric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29660068685/in/album-72157672692229522/" title="Desert"&gt;&lt;img alt="Desert" src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8131/29660068685_cc58b07e01.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="itinerary"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#itinerary"&gt;Itinerary &lt;i class="icon-plane small-font"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We rented a relatively cheap car that would still be large enough to handle all five of us and our gear. Size-wise The car looked like a limousine, yet  paled in comparison to the cars driving around us; among our first cultural shocks right there. As most of us are still students, we left straight after our finals end of June. The summertime in the South is described as being relentlessly tough, so we made sure to have proper air-conditioning and plenty of water available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="car" class="fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/car.jpg" title="car"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="florida"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#florida"&gt;Florida&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="miami"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#miami"&gt;Miami&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a fairly pleasant eight-hour flight, we arrived at Miami International Airport in Florida. Despite arriving late in the evening, it still took us over a whopping three hours of queuing just to get through border control. It was a Kafkaesque experience for sure; having to queue to use check-in machines and manual check-ups serving the exact same task, yet those manual check-ups were so superficial that it felt entirely unnecessary and a waste of time. An antiqued relic of post-911 measures?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our way out we passed about five fast-food chains within a minute of driving, as well as several drive-through gun shops and pharmacies, and big billboards advertising triple-bypasses. What a country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="center border"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/147061735@N04/29035300123/in/album-72157672692229522/" title="Miami"&gt;&lt;img alt="Miami" src="https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8094/29035300123_8272e91fed.jpg" style="width:500px;height:281px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other memorable locations to us as foreigners …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-24:/blog/2016/08/travels-roadtrip-through-the-deep-south/</guid><category>Personal</category><category>Travels</category><category>USA</category><category>Deep South</category></item><item><title>Hello World - About This Blog</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/hello-world-about-this-blog/</link><description>
&lt;!-- PELICAN_START_SUMMARY --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been thinking on starting a small, personal blog for a while now and was already in the progress of writing up a small stack of possible articles to post. A long summer-break permitted me to sit down and get started on the technicalities; a process a bit more complicated as initially expected but worth it in the long run. This blog serves not as a tutorial on making one with Pelican (I’ll get to that &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt;), but as a brief log on my reasoning and thought process during creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="blog-platform"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#blog-platform"&gt;Blog-platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="deciding"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#deciding"&gt;Deciding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conceptually I tried to steer away from heavy content management systems such as &lt;strong&gt;Drupal&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;WordPress&lt;/strong&gt;. While easy to work with (and taking quite a bit of technical work of your hands), a server-side database means too heavy a load for what’s basically a small-scale personal blog, and several unnecessary security risks on top.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The tinkerer in me opted for a DIY approach with full control over both content and design. As far as Static blog frameworks go there were several popular options, but since I’m more accustomed to the &lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt; programming language I ended up choosing for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; over more widespread options such as the &lt;em&gt;Ruby&lt;/em&gt;-based &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jekyllrb.com/"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. An added value of managing my blogs client-side and delivering small sized static pages is the ease of finding an appropriate host (I host my pages on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; while serving larger files through DropBox) as well as seamless integration with my &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt;-based writing work-flow.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial set-up is relatively simple, as installation and basic generation are done through command line, and content written in &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;AsciiDoc&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; gets served as stand-alone pages or articles. There’s a wide choice of &lt;a href="http://www.pelicanthemes.com/"&gt;existing templates&lt;/a&gt;, but further customization requires some working knowledge on web-design as well as, preferably, on basic programming concepts (Pelican templates are created using the python-based &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jinja.pocoo.org/"&gt;Jinja2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing for template logic and inheritance). Needless to say, hosting on GitHub Pages requires rudementary knowledge of &lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt;, but that’s really not a skill learned in vain as the concept of version control applies well to writing papers and other documents too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="development"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#development"&gt;Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting acquainted with these tools can be time consuming. Luckily Pelican’s &lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.6.3/#"&gt;well documented&lt;/a&gt;, and there are plenty of tutorials out there, as well as hundreds of working examples hosted on GitHub available as reference (the backbone …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-23:/blog/2016/08/hello-world-about-this-blog/</guid><category>technical</category><category>pelican</category><category>blog</category><category>github</category></item></channel></rss>