<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Onoreto - Stevie Poppe, Linda Havenstein, and Fabian Schäfer</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://localhost:8000/feeds/stevie-poppe-linda-havenstein-and-fabian-schafer.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://steviepoppe.net/</id><updated>2023-06-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><subtitle>| Onoreto</subtitle><entry><title>The Far Right and the Dissemination of COVID-19-Related Disinformation and Conspiracy Narratives in Japan: the Metapolitics of Kobayashi Yoshinori</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/publication/covid-disinformation/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-06-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-06-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Stevie Poppe, Linda Havenstein, and Fabian Schäfer</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2023-06-07:/publication/covid-disinformation/</id><content type="html">&lt;h1 id="abstract"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial lack of scientific consensus regarding COVID-19 and public controversies concerning implemented countermeasures have created fertile soil for the circulation of disinformation and conspiracy narratives. Applying a mixed-methods discourse analysis, we examine the use of typical rhetorical strategies and metaphors of conspiracy narratives and disinformation, and we study overlaps with discursive strategies of the New Right in Japan. Our discourse analysis uses a qualitative and a quantitative approach. The former ranges from bestselling publications by the contribution of historical revisionist manga author Kobayashi Yoshinori to the propagation of COVID-19 – related conspiracy narratives and disinformation. The latter analyzes data collected from Amazon’s review section, through which we explore narrative reach and reader reception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="citation"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#citation"&gt;Citation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poppe, S., Havenstein, L., &amp;amp; Schäfer, F. (2023). The Far Right and the Dissemination of COVID-19-Related Disinformation and Conspiracy Narratives in Japan: the Metapolitics of Kobayashi Yoshinori, Asiascape: Digital Asia, 10(1-2), 153-180. doi: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1163/22142312-bja10050"&gt;https://doi.org/10.1163/22142312-bja10050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Publication"></category><category term="conspiracy theories"></category><category term="COVID-19 pandemic"></category><category term="disinformation"></category><category term="Kobayashi Yoshinori"></category><category term="metapolitics"></category><category term="New Right"></category><category term="populism"></category></entry></feed>