<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Onoreto</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://localhost:8000/feeds/stevie-poppe.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://steviepoppe.net/</id><updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Visiting a Japanese Elementary School - An (Awkward) Experience to Remember</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-28:blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I, alongside several other second year Japanology students, participated in a small “tell an interesting story” speech contest through our university. Earlier this week we were informed the videorecordings of these had been uploaded on the contest’s website and were available for all to watch.&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; My story is a classic “awkward Japanese language mix-up” anecdote on a visit to a Japanese elementary school, which I’ll touch upon in this post, along embedding the video. (日本の方、あまりよくないんですけど、もしよかったら見てみてくださいね！)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Video"></category><category term="KULeuven"></category></entry><entry><title>Pelican Plugin: CSS-only footnote pop-up</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/pelican-plugin-css-only-footnote-pop-up/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-25:blog/2016/08/pelican-plugin-css-only-footnote-pop-up/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a classic staple in any writer’s toolbox and allows them to, in an unobtrusive way, citate sources or display additional information not directly related to the original argument. Yet I feel online footnotes, through the way they’re often implemented imitating printed media footnotes, come over quite counterintuitive by forcing the interested reader to disrupt his reading flow, and by failing to make use of today’s extensive webdesign posibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I royally use footnotes in my markdown writing workflow&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I figured I’d get acquainted with the Pelican documentation a bit and write a small unobtrusive CSS pop-up plugin to display these on hover for those devices that support it.&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Pelican"></category><category term="Markdown"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Footnotes"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World - About This Blog</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/hello-world-about-this-blog/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-23:blog/2016/08/hello-world-about-this-blog/</id><summary type="html">I’ve been thinking on maintaining a blog for a while now and had already stacked up a pile of writings ready to post. A long summer break allowed me enough free time to sit down and get started on the technicalities; a process a bit more complicated as initially expected but worth it in the long run. This blog serves not as a tutorial on making one with Pelican (I’ll get to that eventually), but as a brief log on my reasoning and thought process during creation.</summary><category term="pelican"></category><category term="blog"></category><category term="github"></category></entry></feed>