<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Onoreto</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/</link><description>@Stevie Poppe</description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 2: an efficient vocab mining set-up with Anki and Rikaisama</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rikaichan&lt;/strong&gt;, and it’s Chrome variant &lt;strong&gt;Rikaikun&lt;/strong&gt;, have already been widely established as incredibly helpful tools for reading Japanese online. Nevertheless, one major function remained missing still: a seamless integration with Anki for efficient vocabulary mining. A recent extension of the original Rikaichan, aptly named &lt;strong&gt;Rikaisama&lt;/strong&gt; (it’s a &lt;em&gt;pun&lt;/em&gt;!), adds several new features including communication with the Anki API, &lt;em&gt;Sanseido Web Dictionary&lt;/em&gt;‘s J-J dictionary definitions, access to &lt;em&gt;J-Pod101&lt;/em&gt;‘s&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; audiofiles, and several more.&lt;sup id="fnref:6"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Concretely, this means audio playback of tens of thousands of words and expressions as well as easy integration of new vocab into Anki. Despite these incredibly useful features, Rikaisama remains fairly unknown and unblogged about. To counter that, this blog serves as a brief tutorial on setting up a Rikaisama/Anki environment as well as demonstrating some useful real-life appliances.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-08:blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/</guid><category>Anki</category><category>Rikaisama</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>set-up</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki (effectively) (in an academic context)</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Those who know me might accuse me of preaching the memorization tool &lt;strong&gt;Anki&lt;/strong&gt; as the best thing that’s ever happened to studying, and they wouldn’t be that far off. Over the past year I’ve extensively integrated this software in my studies, with (to me personally) remarkable results in both productivity and academic grades. There are however, some pitfalls for the casual user to take heed of, and getting the full benefit of your time requires cultivating a proper mindset. As I mention Anki a great deal on this site, I decided on writing my own &lt;del&gt;&lt;em&gt;short&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/del&gt; guide on setting up and using Anki, as well as describe how I personally integrate it into my studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-07:blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/</guid><category>Anki</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>set-up</category></item><item><title>Parsing Japanese Text in Markdown-Python for Stylizing and Semantic Purposes</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/parsing-japanese-text-in-markdown-python-for-stylizing-and-semantic-purposes/</link><description>Due to my studies I (will) often use Japanese in my blog. As I gave some thought to typography and readability, I found the default appearance of Japanese text to be in stark contrast with the rest of my design.&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; To target specifically Japanese text, I wrote a small Markdown-Python extension for use in static blog generators as Jekyll and Pelican (or pretty much anything that utilizes Markdown-Python to parse Markdown in HTML) and embed such text in a span with the language attribute set to Japanese. The added, and probably more important bonus, aside from styling and semantic reasons, is that this method counters the negative effects of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Han_unification"&gt;Han unification&lt;/a&gt; in so-called CJK-languages.</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-06:blog/2016/09/parsing-japanese-text-in-markdown-python-for-stylizing-and-semantic-purposes/</guid><category>python</category><category>pelican</category><category>markdown</category><category>Japanese</category><category>fonts</category></item><item><title>Visiting a Japanese Elementary School - An (Awkward) Experience to Remember</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I, alongside several other second year Japanology students, participated in a small “tell an interesting story” speech contest through our university. This week we were informed the videorecordings of these had been uploaded on the contest’s website and were available for all to watch&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. My story is a classic “awkward Japanese language mix-up” anecdote on a visit to a Japanese elementary school in Brussels, which I’ll touch upon in this post, along embedding the video. (&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;日本の方、あまりよくないんですけど、もしよかったら見てみてくださいね！&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-28:blog/2016/08/visiting-a-japanese-elementary-school-an-awkward-experience-to-remember/</guid><category>Japanese</category><category>Video</category><category>KULeuven</category></item><item><title>Pelican Plugin: CSS-only footnote pop-up</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/pelican-plugin-css-only-footnote-pop-up/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a classic staple in any writer’s toolbox and allows them to, in an unobtrusive way, citate sources or display additional information not directly related to the original argument. Yet I feel online footnotes, through the way they’re often implemented imitating printed media footnotes, come over quite counterintuitive by forcing the interested reader to disrupt his reading flow, and by failing to make use of today’s extensive webdesign posibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I royally use footnotes in my markdown writing workflow&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I figured I’d get acquainted with the Pelican documentation a bit and write a small unobtrusive CSS pop-up plugin to display these on hover for those devices that support it.&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-25:blog/2016/08/pelican-plugin-css-only-footnote-pop-up/</guid><category>Pelican</category><category>Markdown</category><category>Python</category><category>Footnotes</category></item><item><title>Hello World - About This Blog</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/08/hello-world-about-this-blog/</link><description>I’ve been thinking on maintaining a blog for a while now and had already stacked up a pile of writings ready to post. A long summer break allowed me enough free time to sit down and get started on the technicalities; a process a bit more complicated as initially expected but worth it in the long run. This blog serves not as a tutorial on making one with Pelican (I’ll get to that eventually), but as a brief log on my reasoning and thought process during creation.</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-08-23:blog/2016/08/hello-world-about-this-blog/</guid><category>pelican</category><category>blog</category><category>github</category></item></channel></rss>