<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Onoreto</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://localhost:8000/feeds/studies.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://steviepoppe.net/</id><updated>2016-09-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Waarom Japanologie?</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/waarom-japanologie/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-14:blog/2016/09/waarom-japanologie/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;!-- PELICAN_START_SUMMARY --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoals velen in mijn richting ontstond mijn interesse in Japan al op jonge leeftijd onder invloed van het zogenaamde &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cool_Japan"&gt;Cool Japan&lt;/a&gt;: de verspreiding en globalisatie van Japanse popcultuur (muziek, televisie, games, enzovoort) die toen geleidelijk aan al doorsijpelde in onze nationale media. Het zou zelfs een interesse worden die zodanig groeide dat ik er jaren later mijn studiekeuze door liet beïnvloeden. Vaak krijg ik bij vermelding daarvan echter nog, zoals mijn klasgenoten ongetwijfeld kunnen beamen, een hoop verbaasde blikken toegesmeten en dé klassieke hamvraag voorgeschoteld: &lt;strong&gt;Waarom nu juist Japanologie&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japanologie"></category><category term="KU Leuven"></category></entry><entry><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 2: an efficient vocab mining set-up with Anki and Rikaisama</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-08:blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rikaichan&lt;/strong&gt;, and it’s Chrome variant &lt;strong&gt;Rikaikun&lt;/strong&gt;, have already been widely established as incredibly helpful tools for reading Japanese online. Nevertheless, one major function remained missing still: a seamless integration with Anki for efficient vocabulary mining. A recent extension of the original Rikaichan, aptly named &lt;strong&gt;Rikaisama&lt;/strong&gt; (it’s a &lt;em&gt;pun&lt;/em&gt;!), adds several new features including communication with the Anki API, &lt;em&gt;Sanseido Web Dictionary&lt;/em&gt;‘s J-J dictionary definitions, access to &lt;em&gt;J-Pod101&lt;/em&gt;‘s&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; audiofiles, and several more&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Concretely, this means audio playback of tens of thousands of words and expressions as well as easy integration of new vocab into Anki. Despite these incredibly useful features, Rikaisama remains fairly unknown and unblogged about. To counter that, this blog serves as a brief tutorial on setting up a Rikaisama/Anki environment as well as demonstrating some useful real-life appliances.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Rikaisama"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry><entry><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki (effectively) (in an academic context)</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-07:blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Those who know me might accuse me of preaching the memorization tool &lt;strong&gt;Anki&lt;/strong&gt; as the best thing that’s ever happened to studying, and they wouldn’t be that far off. Over the past year I’ve extensively integrated this software in my studies, with (to me personally) remarkable results in both productivity and academic grades. There are however, some pitfalls for the casual user to take heed of, and getting the full benefit of your time requires cultivating a proper mindset. As I mention Anki a great deal on this site, I decided on writing my own &lt;del&gt;&lt;em&gt;short&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/del&gt; guide on setting up and using Anki, as well as describe how I personally integrate it into my studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry></feed>