<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Onoreto</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/feeds/studies.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://steviepoppe.net/</id><updated>2016-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>織田信長とアルベール一世：我々の国民の共有している歴史</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/12/oda-nobunaga-to-aruberu-issei/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-12-01:blog/2016/12/oda-nobunaga-to-aruberu-issei/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;私は先週、ブリュッセルで行われた日本語のスピーチコンテストに参加して、「ベルギー・日本友好１５０周年」のために歴史的なスピーチを発表する機会をいただいた。すると、参加者の他者が非常に高いレベルにあったし、質疑応答もやや恥ずかしくなっても、何とか第三位に入賞した。このブログのエントリーは私が書いたスピーチの原稿である。&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japan"></category><category term="History"></category><category term="Belgium"></category><category term="Speech"></category></entry><entry><title>Oda Nobunaga and King Albert - The shared history of our nations’ people</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/11/oda-nobunaga-and-king-albert-the-shared-history-of-our-nations-people/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-11-28:blog/2016/11/oda-nobunaga-and-king-albert-the-shared-history-of-our-nations-people/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;For this year’s Japanese Speech Contest in Brussels, I had the pleasure to prepare and hold a speech in honor of Belgium and Japan’s 150th year of mutual friendship. Despite some hickups and an incredibly high level amongst the other candidates (meeting all these excellent Japanese learners was both an extremely humbling experience as well as a perfect motivation booster for the coming years) I was awarded 3rd prize. This blog contains my speech’s English translation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japan"></category><category term="History"></category><category term="Belgium"></category><category term="Speech"></category></entry><entry><title>Anki Add-on: Japanese translations for Korean vocabulary</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/anki-add-on-japanese-translations-for-korean-vocabulary/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-15:blog/2016/10/anki-add-on-japanese-translations-for-korean-vocabulary/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;As anyone browsing my blog might have guessed, I’m pretty fond of using Anki for assisting in vocab acquisition, and thus use it for Korean vocabulary as well, using both existing sets and my own based on our textbooks&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Having a broad base in Japanese, I thought it would be more efficient having a link between the two languages in my flashcards. In order to assist myself and other learners of both Japanese and Korean, I wrote an Anki add-on that adds Japanese translations of Korean expressions. &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Korean"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry><entry><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 4: Making the switch - J-J definitions in your vocab cards</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-4-making-the-switch-j-j-definitions-in-your-vocab-cards/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-02:blog/2016/10/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-4-making-the-switch-j-j-definitions-in-your-vocab-cards/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;You’ve been studying Japanese for a while now and reached a level of Japanese adequate enough to understand (simple) texts. Drilling new vocabulary has become a daily routine so entangled in your lifestyle you barely notice anymore. If you were to describe your current level of proficiency, you’d proudly present yourself as an intermediate level learner. Sounds familiar? Let’s take it a notch further by adding Japanese definitions&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to our ankisets and reduce our dependency on English definition crutches!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry><entry><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 3: contextualize your vocab cards with example sentences</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-3-contextualize-your-vocab-cards-with-example-sentences/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-17:blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-3-contextualize-your-vocab-cards-with-example-sentences/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;One of the common pitfalls of learning Japanese vocabulary through ankicards is memorizing them loose of context. Perhaps you’ve found yourself in a situation having no particular problems recalling vocabulary whilst reviewing your anki cards, but less so when confronted with real-life situations. If that sounds familar, one way to counter this common problem would be to install an additional Anki add-on, and bring our vocab cards to a next level by adding Japanese example sentences and their translations. This blog offers an easy step-by-step tutorial on setting this up. Additionally, for those who’ve followed my previous tutorial, I add some extra code to combine the example sentence functions with the instant-import features of the firefox plug-in Rikaisama.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry><entry><title>Waarom Japanologie?</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/waarom-japanologie/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-14:blog/2016/09/waarom-japanologie/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;!-- PELICAN_START_SUMMARY --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoals velen in mijn richting ontstond mijn interesse in Japan al op jonge leeftijd onder invloed van het zogenaamde &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cool_Japan"&gt;Cool Japan&lt;/a&gt;: de verspreiding en globalisatie van Japanse popcultuur (muziek, televisie, games, enzovoort) die toen geleidelijk aan al doorsijpelde in onze nationale media. Het zou zelfs een interesse worden die zodanig groeide dat ik er jaren later mijn studiekeuze door liet beïnvloeden. Vaak krijg ik bij vermelding daarvan echter nog, zoals mijn klasgenoten ongetwijfeld kunnen beamen, een hoop verbaasde blikken toegesmeten en dé klassieke hamvraag voorgeschoteld: &lt;strong&gt;Waarom nu juist Japanologie&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Japanologie"></category><category term="KU Leuven"></category></entry><entry><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki (effectively) (in an academic context)</title><link href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Stevie Poppe</name></author><id>tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-07:blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Those who know me might accuse me of preaching the memorization tool &lt;strong&gt;Anki&lt;/strong&gt; as the best thing that’s ever happened to studying, and they wouldn’t be that far off. Over the past year I’ve extensively integrated this software in my studies, with (to me personally) remarkable results in both productivity and academic grades. There are however, some pitfalls for the casual user to take heed of, and getting the full benefit of your time requires cultivating a proper mindset. As I mention Anki a great deal on this site, I decided on writing my own &lt;del&gt;&lt;em&gt;short&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/del&gt; guide on setting up and using Anki, as well as describe how I personally integrate it into my studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Anki"></category><category term="Tutorial"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Studying"></category></entry></feed>