<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Onoreto - Studies</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/</link><description>@Stevie Poppe</description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>A Quick Guide to Data-mining &amp; (Textual) Analysis of (Japanese) Twitter Part 4: Natural Language Processing With MeCab, Neologd and NLTK</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/07/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-4/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This short series of blogs chronicles the bare-bones required to conduct a basic form of social media analysis on corpora of (Japanese) Tweets. It is primarily intended for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;undergraduate and graduate students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; whose topics of research include contemporary Japan or its online vox populi, and want to strengthen their existing research (such as an undergraduate thesis or term paper) with a social media-based quantitative angle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fourth blog follows up on the MeCab + NEologd set-up described in the third part of this series, and introduces the reader to some of possibilities when working with python-based NLP tools such as NLTK. Concretely, we will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Import the python wrapper mecab-python, necessary to use MeCab in our python scripts,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Learn about NLP tools like NLTK,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Perform a basic sentiment analysis on a corpus of Japanese tweets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mecab-python-binding"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#mecab-python-binding"&gt;MeCab python binding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having set-up MeCab, we now require a python binding in order to use MeCab in our python scripts. As usual, install the required python library using &lt;strong&gt;pip&lt;/strong&gt; in the command prompt: &lt;code&gt;pip install mecab&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Upon installation, let’s test our set-up by using the &lt;code&gt;python&lt;/code&gt; command in the command prompt and copy-pasting the code examples below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example 1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;MeCab&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;tagger&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;MeCab&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Tagger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;parsed&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;tagger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;parse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"お母さんが作ってくれた魚フライ定食を食べてみたいです。"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;parsed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MeCab.Tagger function accepts several arguments we can pass to MeCab:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-d&lt;/code&gt;: path to one or more tokenizer dictionaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-E&lt;/code&gt;: Which escape sequence to use at the end of the parsed string (tabs: \t, backspaces: \b, newlines: \n, etc; don’t forget to escape the backslash with an additional backslash).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-O&lt;/code&gt;: Quick-formatting options. Wakati (short for &lt;em&gt;wakachi-gaki&lt;/em&gt;, 分かち書き), for example, is a tokenizer option for returning a string with only the surface form of each token, separated by spaces.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-F&lt;/code&gt;: Grants us more control over the output formatting. Adding &lt;code&gt;-F%m:\\t\\t%f[0]\\n&lt;/code&gt;, for example, will format the outcome as seen in &lt;strong&gt;figure 4&lt;/strong&gt;: the token surface form and the first element of the ‘&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;‘ array (part-of-speech), separated by tab spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;–unk-feature&lt;/code&gt;: set the return value of the part-of-speech column for unknown words (e.g. to &lt;em&gt;unknown&lt;/em&gt; or to 未知語).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example 2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="normal"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;MeCab&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;tagger&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;MeCab&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Tagger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"-F%m:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="se"&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;%f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;[0]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="se"&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;n -E&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="se"&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;n --unk-feature 未知語"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"うわー！母が作ってくれた魚フライ定食は素敵だったな～！？ウェーーーーイイイイイイイイィ！"&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;parsed&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;tagger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;parse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;parsed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id="normalizing-japanese-text-with-neologdn-optional"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#normalizing-japanese-text-with-neologdn-optional"&gt;Normalizing Japanese text with Neologdn (optional)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/ikegami-yukino/neologdn"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; small library consists of …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2020-07-05:/blog/2020/07/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-4/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Digital Humanities</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Python</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Twitter</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide to Data-mining &amp; (Textual) Analysis of (Japanese) Twitter Part 3: Natural Language Processing With MeCab, Neologd and KH Coder</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/06/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-3/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This short series of blogs chronicles the bare-bones required to conduct a basic form of social media analysis on corpora of (Japanese) Tweets. It is primarily intended for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;undergraduate and graduate students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; whose topics of research include contemporary Japan or its online vox populi, and want to strengthen their existing research (such as an undergraduate thesis or term paper) with a social media-based quantitative angle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this third blog and the next, fourth blog is to introduce the reader to the concept of natural language processing (NLP), to the techniques available for processing Japanese texts, and to some basic forms of quantitative content analysis that could be performed with that processed data. Concretely, in this third blog we will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  Learn about natural language processing in a Japanese context,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  Set up the morphological analyzer &lt;strong&gt;MeCab&lt;/strong&gt; and the neologism dictionary &lt;strong&gt;mecab-ipadic-NEologd&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  Install and set-up the quantitative content analysis tool KH Coder,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  Perform a rudimentary content analysis on a corpus of tweets collected with methods described in the previous two blogs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this blog thus assumes that the reader has read &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/04/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter/"&gt;part one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/05/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-2/"&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; of this series, it should also serve as a solid stand-alone introduction to setting up MeCab and the IPADic NEologd dictionary (as of writing still pretty much the de-facto canonical tools in academic scholarship applying a form of Japanese computational linguistics) and combining them with KH Coder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of the field, parts of this tutorial will be rather technical and rely on having some basic experience working with the Windows command prompt or MacOS Terminal, but despite the complexity of the matter, there shouldn’t be much of a technical difficulty gap compared to the previous tutorials.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="japanese-natural-language-processing"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#japanese-natural-language-processing"&gt;Japanese Natural Language Processing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Natural language’ refers to the usage of language that has developed naturally over time among humans, encompassing methods of communication such as speech, written text and signaling. Natural Language Processing, then, is the field of developing how computers can understand and process such use of language in a cognitive way. Applications of NLP are seen anywhere ranging from AI assistants (such as Siri, Alexa or Google Assistant), to automatic translation (e.g. Google Translate), targeted advertising, and even in health-care.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important preliminary step in processing natural language computationally is to &lt;strong&gt;tokenize&lt;/strong&gt; of language (also referred to as &lt;strong&gt;word segmentation&lt;/strong&gt;). In other words, to break down language into smaller segments …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2020-06-05:/blog/2020/06/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-3/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Digital Humanities</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Python</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Twitter</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide to Data-mining &amp; (Textual) Analysis of (Japanese) Twitter Part 2: Basic Metrics &amp; Graphs</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/05/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This short series of blogs chronicles the bare-bones required to conduct a basic form of social media analysis on corpora of (Japanese) Tweets. It is primarily intended for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;undergraduate and graduate students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; whose topics of research include contemporary Japan or its online vox populi, and want to strengthen their existing research (such as an undergraduate thesis or term paper) with a social media-based quantitative angle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this second blog is two-fold: 1) to introduce the reader to some possibilities in regards to basic social media analysis (applicable almost immediately upon having &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/04/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter/"&gt;finished the previous guide&lt;/a&gt;), and 2) to touch upon a crucial, yet sometimes ignored aspect of social media analysis: the legal and ethical caveats regarding privacy and informed content when researching user-generated content on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using a concrete, real-world example, we will thus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Think about how we might integrate Twitter analysis into our project,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Use the Python scripting language to further process our dataset to our needs and obtain relevant metrics,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Use spreadsheet software such as Openlibre or Excel to produce pivot tables and graphs,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Reflect on the ethical and legal ramifications of working with social media data in academic research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id="context"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#context"&gt;Context&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assisted several third-year BA students working on a group essay covering aspects of the COVID-19 virus and marital issues within a larger framework of hegemonic masculinity, femininity and gender hegemony in Japan. Their choice of incorporating an element of social network analysis was not ungrounded. Correlating to increased remote work measures taken in Japan as a COVID-19 precaution, several hashtags concerning marital issues began to trend on Japanese Twitter starting Mid-April 2020 and saw further acceleration after being promptly picked up on by several news outlets and tabloids both within- and outside of Japan (such as the Japanese hashtag #&lt;em&gt;coronadivorce&lt;/em&gt;, #&lt;em&gt;koronarikon&lt;/em&gt; #コロナ&lt;span lang="ja"&gt;&lt;ruby&gt;&lt;rb&gt;離婚&lt;/rb&gt;&lt;rp&gt;(&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;rt&gt;りこん&lt;/rt&gt;&lt;rp&gt;)&lt;/rp&gt;&lt;/ruby&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my research interests concerns the many ways the internet, as a cultural artifact, augments or subverts our personal reality. Of interest to this project, then, was how the explosion in usage of the above hashtags reifies in Japan a situation that is undoubtedly being felt worldwide among many (married) couples during the pandemic. Concretely we had several questions: how does Twitter (and general social media usage) fit within the lives of struggling couples trying to cope with the uncertainty of the Corona crisis and its amplification of internal relational struggles? Does the usage of those hashtags …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2020-05-15:/blog/2020/05/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter-part-2/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Digital Humanities</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Python</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Twitter</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide to Data-mining &amp; (Textual) Analysis of (Japanese) Twitter Part 1: Twitter Data Collection</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2020/04/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;This short series of blogs chronicles the bare-bones required to conduct a basic form of textual analysis on corpora of Japanese tweets. Examples of similar tutorials on the Internet are numerous,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but less so are accessible beginner tutorials guiding the reader throughout the processes of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setting up the initial technical environment,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compiling corpora of clean, processed data, and,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding a visual, quantitative element to any qualitative reading of that text, by utilization of textual analysis tools &lt;strong&gt;tailored for Japanese content&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This series is therefore primarily intended for &lt;strong&gt;undergraduate and graduate students&lt;/strong&gt; whose topics of research include contemporary Japan or its online &lt;em&gt;vox populi&lt;/em&gt;, and want to strengthen their existing research (such as an undergraduate thesis or term paper) with a social media-based quantitative angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping in mind that many of those situated in the humanities might experience an initial technical hurdle, this first blog will focus primarily on the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;, rather than on the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; of doing Twitter-based research, by detailing the minimal necessities for getting up and running — supplemented by a brief optional, technical explanation &lt;em&gt;for those who are interested&lt;/em&gt;. With this first blog, the reader will thus concretely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Set up a Twitter Developer account and obtain Twitter credentials,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Set up a Python development environment,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Run tailored Python scripts to build datasets of tweets, based either on keywords or on the tweet history of particular users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Use Python for preprocessing the dataset into a usable corpus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first blog assumes that the reader has already chosen a topic or target of analysis for which a form of Social Network Analysis (SNA) or content analysis of Twitter data is well-suited. A more thorough epistemological introduction to the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; of SNA, as well as further recommended reading, will follow in the future. Suffice to say, the technical ease of working with the Twitter APIs, as well as the global-spread use of Twitter (roughly half a billion tweets are sent every single day, with Japanese per capita usage ranking particularly high), offer an excellent introduction to getting acquainted with SNA through practical, real-life examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It must be emphasized that the field this tutorial roughly falls under, &lt;strong&gt;Digital Humanities&lt;/strong&gt; (DH), is extremely broad; and understanding the various possibilities DH offers, as well as when and how to apply those, have their own intricate challenges. Within the scope of our brief tutorial series, however, the initial technical hurdles …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2020-04-01:/blog/2020/04/a-quick-guide-to-data-mining-textual-analysis-of-japanese-twitter/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Big Data</category><category>Digital Humanities</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Python</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Twitter</category></item><item><title>Several tips for exchange students heading to Japan / Tokyo</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/05/several-tips-for-exchange-students-living-in-japan-tokyo/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;My home university’s student circle asked me for some tips for new exchange students coming to Japan and after living in Tokyo, Japan for over 18 months I learned some things that might be useful for future exchange students, often glanced over in similar lists. Although this list is a perpetual work-in-progress, I hope it can at least offer some concrete, directly applicable tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="shopping"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#shopping"&gt;Shopping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="get-an-amazoncojp-prime-account"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#get-an-amazoncojp-prime-account"&gt;Get an Amazon.co.jp Prime account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m reluctant for promoting a company with an employment situation as terrible as Amazon. Nevertheless, students are legible for a year-long trial of Amazon Prime Student which might be quite useful for exchange students on a budget. The prime reason to do so would be free expedited shipping, but some other benefits include streaming through Prime Video and free selection of Kindle novels. Personally, I found amazon.co.jp useful for difficult to find research material and access to some other second-hand sellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="use-mercari"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#use-mercari"&gt;Use Mercari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mercari (メルカリ) is a widely used e-commerce application popular for second-hand sales and small time mom-and-pop independent stores. I used it for buying my TV and some rare-to-find records. It’s common to haggle on the price and you pay through convenience stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="get-used-to-customer-cards"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#get-used-to-customer-cards"&gt;Get used to customer cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of stores have customer cards, usually freely obtainable and immediately applicable. A card at my OK Supermarket cost 100 yen and saved me 3% on all my groceries. Places like Big Camera, the must-visit dirt-cheap second hand store Book-Off, Tully’s Coffee, etc have free customer cards. Some stores moved on to smart-phone applications, like the shoes-market chain ABC Market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="services"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#services"&gt;Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="manga-cafes"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#manga-cafes"&gt;(Manga) cafes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I loved my apartment and spent a lot of time at my university lab, I generally felt the most productive studying or reading in bakeries or the omnipresent coffee-shops like Tully’s and Renoir. Perhaps not as romantic, but another cheap option might be studying at McDonalds chains equipped with electric outlets and ordering a cheap coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I grew fond of manga cafes and particularly of the &lt;strong&gt;Kaikatsu Club&lt;/strong&gt; (快活クラブ) chain. Students get steep discounts, private booths are comfortable and equipped with both blankets and pillows for a quick nap, as well as a computer and additional screen I could attach to my laptop, and sufficient electrical outlets. All you can drink soft-ice, hot drinks and soft drinks are included, and food-service is …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2019-05-18:/blog/2019/05/several-tips-for-exchange-students-living-in-japan-tokyo/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Japan</category><category>Study abroad</category><category>tips</category></item><item><title>Japanese E-books, vocab-mining, DRM and copyright law</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/05/japanese-e-books-vocab-mining-drm-and-copyright-law/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;The E-book industry in Japan is gaining momentum. Both contemporary releases and more popular classics are seeing an increase in digital publication alongside physical distribution. Through their kindle service Amazon.co.jp has a particularly strong hold on this market, and their extensive catalog could offer good news for any intermediate or advanced Japanese language learner. It is easier to look up new vocabulary from digital media than it is to look something up from print media, and both physical Kindles as Kindle for Windows are surprisingly feature-rich, including in-built dictionaries and flashcard options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/04/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-5-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama-yomichan/"&gt;prior blogs&lt;/a&gt; I’ve described my method of reading digital texts as HTML files through a web-browser; using pop-up dictionaries such as Rikaisama or Yomichan in combination with flashcard application Anki for ‘vocab mining’&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; native materials.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This blog describes options of combining that method with kindle E-books, as well summing up several other alternative sources of E-books. Conclusively it is possible to efficiently utilize the Japanese kindle market for study purposes, but doing requires a bit of technical prowess and borders on technical illegality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="amazon-kindle"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#amazon-kindle"&gt;Amazon Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past two years or so I’ve often relied on Amazon.co.jp’s Kindle service for both academic purposes and as leisure, especially while living in Japan.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Their selection of Japanese language material is immense, with Kodansha-published E-books alone accounting for over 40.000 titles in their library. Having relied on above-mentioned study method for a while now I looked into my options of doing so with Kindle E-books as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="through-browsers"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#through-browsers"&gt;Through Browsers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first option would be to open Kindle E-books with my browser and use Rikaisama or Yomichan to import vocabulary into Anki. When purchasing an E-book on Amazon, one specifically purchases the right to read the E-book and download an amazon proprietary file through the Kindle software (the &lt;code&gt;.AZW&lt;/code&gt; format). This proprietary format is practically identical to the &lt;code&gt;.MOBI&lt;/code&gt; format (which again is basically a more highly compressed HTML file, specifically using the Ebook HTML syntax) with additional DRM-protection on commercial releases as attempt to counter copyright infringement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Chrome and Firefox have plug-ins for parsing those two formats, but these plug-ins are frankly not sufficient for our purposes, and for obvious reasons don’t support files with DRM. One option would be removing the DRM through software and converting the Kindle &lt;code&gt;.AZW&lt;/code&gt; format to a &lt;code&gt;ZHTML&lt;/code&gt; format, which is …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2019-05-14:/blog/2019/05/japanese-e-books-vocab-mining-drm-and-copyright-law/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category><category>Tutorial</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 5: an efficient vocab mining set-up with Anki and Yomichan [2021 UPDATE]</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/04/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-5-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama-yomichan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As an undergraduate student relying heavily on Anki&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for both theoretical courses and for studying Japanese, I wrote several blog-posts throughout 2016 on how I’ve personally integrated Anki in my daily life. One of those entries extensively documented how I’ve connected Anki with Firefox to vocab-mine Japanese texts in my browser with JPod101 audio-readings, example-sentences (a method crucial to my language-acquisition) and Japanese dictionary definitions. Although I’ve had little time to update my blog throughout 2018, those specific posts became somewhat high-ranking when googling things concerning Anki. Unfortunately, Firefox-updates led to Anki-integrated Firefox pop-up dictionary Rikaisama (the plug-in I’ve relied on for years) becoming obsolete. Thus it was high time to update my guide to reflect the current state of affairs on the elusive ‘browser + Anki’ integration-methods available today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s 20&lt;strong&gt;XX&lt;/strong&gt;, wasting valuable time on automatable processes bores you and you’re keen on integrating technology more efficiently in your Japanese language-acquisition. Concretely you want to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Vocab-mine Japanese texts you’re reading both on- and off-line using Chrome or Firefox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Improve your retention-rate with hidden &lt;strong&gt;furigana&lt;/strong&gt; reading-aids and crystal-clear audio-readings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Contextualize your cards with Japanese example sentences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Rely not just solely on foreign-language translations, but use Japanese dictionary definitions for optimized studying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, you want cards like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ankiexample" class="hwimportant fborder fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/ankiexample.gif" title="ankiexample"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What options are available then, sans going all the way and developing said tools yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’ve previously used the Rikaisama pop-up dictionary and followed my previous guides, you can continue doing so using a Firefox-derived browser. I still recommend this method for longer texts such as novels. Head to section &lt;a href="#rikaisama"&gt;Rikaisama&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re new to this site or method, use the Chrome / Firefox add-on Yomichan. It’s user-friendly, highly adjustable and has tons of features. Head to section &lt;a href="#yomichan"&gt;Yomichan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id="yomichan"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#yomichan"&gt;Yomichan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed by &lt;a href="https://foosoft.net/"&gt;Foosoft Productions&lt;/a&gt; - a household name amongst the Anki-utilizing on-line learning community - Yomichan originated as a stand-alone bookreader with Anki-integration,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; until it in its current form became the most complete alternative available for Rikaisama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In similar fashion to Rikaisama, we’ll use Yomichan to vocab-mine Japanese texts and generate extensive Anki-cards with Jpod101 audio-readings, example sentences, &lt;em&gt;furigana&lt;/em&gt;, and Japanese definitions. Furthermore, for ex-Rikaisama users, Yomichan definitely has the upper hand concerning user-friendliness and adaptability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit of this plug-in is that it’s cross-platform, available both on &lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/rikaisama/files/"&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/rikaisama/files/"&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. Pick your platform of choice and after installing …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2019-04-17:/blog/2019/04/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-5-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama-yomichan/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Rikaisama</category><category>Yomichan</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>織田信長とアルベール一世：我々の国民の共有している歴史</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/12/oda-nobunaga-to-aruberu-issei/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;私は先週、ブリュッセルで行われた日本語のスピーチコンテストに参加して、「ベルギー・日本友好１５０周年」のために歴史的なスピーチを発表する機会をいただきました。すると、参加者の他者が非常に高いレベルにあったし、質疑応答もやや恥ずかしくなっても、何とか第三位に入賞しました。このブログのエントリーは私が書いたスピーチの原稿です。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="_1"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#_1"&gt;スピーチ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会場にお集まりの皆様、こんにちは！ルーバン大学日本学科3年生のスティービーと申します。私は子供の頃から日本の文化と歴史に大変興味がありました。そして日本学科に入学して2年間勉強をすることで自分の知識をもっと広め、深めることができました。更に、来年日本へ留学する可能性があることや、今年が「ベルギー・日本友好150周年」の年であることから、日本の歴史だけでなく、特に独立前のベルギーと日本の400年も前に遡る両国が共有している歴史への関心も高まってきました。そのため、この発表「我々の国民の共有している歴史」では、二つの歴史的逸話を紹介して、ベルギー人と日本人の友好についてお話したいと思います。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;この共有されている歴史、すなわち、両国間の共感は、私たちの国の歴史的展開がほぼ同じように進んだからだと考えます。ベルギーも日本も強大な国々が隣接していたにもかかわらず独立することができました。ベルギーがフランスやドイツの大国に挟まれながらも何とか独立したのと同様に、日本も中国やロシア、欧米の中で、独立国として次第に世界で最大の経済大国の一つになりました。そのため、明治時代に岩倉使節団が派遣された際、「日本人と同じような独立の気概を持っているベルギー王国をモデルとしてはどうか」という記事を書いた日本人記者もいました。また、第一次世界大戦中にドイツ帝国の攻撃を受けたベルギーは「意志が強い、勇敢な国である」と日本で報道されました。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="_2"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#_2"&gt;織田信長とアルベール一世&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当日のベルギー王アルベール一世がフランスの国境近くにある村から抵抗をし続けていた間、東京と大阪の朝日新聞が協力して、ベルギーを支援するために募金キャンペーンを行いました。更に、ベルギーの国民を励ますために、ベルギーの国王の誕生日に刀を献上する企画も立てました。そのため、朝日新聞記者の杉村廣太郎がベルギーに派遣されました。１９１４年に彼がイギリスを経由した際に、そこで苦しむベルギー避難民を目撃し、戦争の深刻な状況について朝日新聞に報告しました。戦争の影響による難しい旅路を経て、やっとのことでベルギーの亡命政府にたどり着き、国王に謁見する機会を得ました。彼は、朝日新聞の社長が書いた国交の手紙を渡した後、国王に戦国時代の織田信長が用いていたという刀を献上しました。その象徴的な行為がベルギーだけではなく、世界中の報道機関によく受け入れられたのはいうまでもありません。その結果、ベルギーの国民も日本人に対して非常に友好的な印象を持つようになりました。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="_3"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#_3"&gt;関東大震災&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;１９２３年の関東大震災が起こった時、ベルギー人がためらわず、救援活動を行ったり資金集めをしたりしたのは、この友好的な日本との関係のためだと言えます。王族と、新たに設立されたベルギー国内委員会が協力して大規模な救援活動を実施しました。私の故郷アントワープを含むベルギーの全国各地でも教会と戦争の退役軍人が協力して「Japan Day」という催しを行いました。他にも、ベルギー人の芸術家達が作品を集めたり新作を発表したりして特別な貢献をしました。まずはブリュッセルで、次に日本で作品の展示発売や展覧会を開催し、売り上げや入場料の利益は全て救援活動のために寄付されました。日本の展覧会だけでも3万５千人もの観客が訪れたと報告されていて、その上、日本の皇太子様と皇后様が30点もの芸術品をご購入されたと聞いております。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;もちろん、多くの国が日本への支援に参加しましたが、ベルギーより多くの資金を集めたのは大国のイギリスとアメリカだけでした。それはベルギー人と日本人の相互の友好関係と共感の証しだと思います。私は、日本学科で学ぶベルギー人の学生として、我々の両国がこの豊かな道を共に歩き続けられるように心から願っています。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以上です。ご清聴ありがとうございました。 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="_4"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#_4"&gt;参考文献&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Japan &amp;amp; Belgium: An Itinerary of Mutual Inspiration, ed. W.F. Vande Walle, pp. 187-213. Tielt: Lannoo, 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Japan &amp;amp; Belgium: Four Centuries of Exchange. Brussels: Commissioners-General of the Belgian Government at the Universal Exposition of Aichi 2005, Japan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-12-01:/blog/2016/12/oda-nobunaga-to-aruberu-issei/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Japan</category><category>History</category><category>Belgium</category><category>Speech</category></item><item><title>Oda Nobunaga and King Albert - The shared history of our nations’ people</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/11/oda-nobunaga-and-king-albert-the-shared-history-of-our-nations-people/</link><description>

&lt;p&gt;For this year’s Japanese Speech Contest in Brussels, I had the pleasure to prepare and hold a speech in honor of Belgium and Japan’s 150&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; year of mutual friendship. Despite some hickups and an incredibly high level amongst the other candidates (meeting all these excellent Japanese learners was both an extremely humbling experience as well as a perfect motivation booster for the coming years) I was awarded 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; prize. This blog contains my speech’s English translation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="speech"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#speech"&gt;Speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! I’m Stevie, a Belgian student at the university of Leuven and currently third year student in the faculty of Japan Studies. Lately, through my studies and the realization of 150 years of amity between our two nations, I’ve gained an increased interest in our mutual history; a long shared history dating from before Belgium was even officially recognized an independent country. That’s why, through this presentation, I would like to focus on two historical anecdotes in history that show not just a friendship between our countries’ governments, but a friendship between our people as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my belief that the empathy shared between our people stems from similar historical developments. &lt;span data-pullquote="Just as Belgium found its independency while cornered between the great nations of France and Germany, Japan rose as an independent world power despite the large Chinese and Russian empires on one side, and the Western industrial powers on the other."&gt;Just as Belgium found its independency while cornered between the great nations of France and Germany, Japan rose as an independent world power despite the large Chinese and Russian empires on one side, and the Western industrial powers on the other.&lt;/span&gt; Thus, during the Meiji Period and the subsequent Iwakura Mission, Belgium was occasionally reported as a potential model nation with its people possessing a high spirit of self-reliance and independence, just as the Japanese people have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="king-albert-and-oda-nobunaga"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#king-albert-and-oda-nobunaga"&gt;King Albert and Oda Nobunaga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this logic, during the first world war, Belgium was reported on a daily base in Japanese media as a brave, strong-spirited country that fell victim to the conquering German empire, while Belgian King Albert continued resistance from a small village near the French border. Eventually, the Tokyo and Osaka Asahi Newspaper launched both a campaign to collect funds for Belgium and planned the presentation of a Japanese sword to the Belgian king on the occasion of his birthday and as a means to encourage the brave resistance of the Belgian people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sugimura Kotaro, a journalist of the Asahi Newspaper, was sent to deliver the sword and travelled through Great Britain in late 1914. Here, he witnessed a great number …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-11-28:/blog/2016/11/oda-nobunaga-and-king-albert-the-shared-history-of-our-nations-people/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Japan</category><category>History</category><category>Belgium</category><category>Speech</category></item><item><title>Anki Add-on: Japanese translations for Korean vocabulary</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/anki-add-on-japanese-translations-for-korean-vocabulary/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have recently started studying Korean as part of the minor I took up at my university. While browsing the internet for helpful resources I found that, like us, a remarkable amount of students of the Korean language have knowledge of Japanese and/or study both simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As anyone browsing my blog might have guessed, I’m pretty fond of using Anki for assisting in vocab acquisition, and thus use it for Korean vocabulary as well, using both existing sets and my own based on our textbooks.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Having a broad base in Japanese, I thought it would be more efficient having a link between the two languages in my flashcards. In order to assist myself and other learners of both Japanese and Korean, I wrote an Anki add-on that adds Japanese translations of Korean expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to my previous Anki posts, this blog post serves as a brief tutorial on setting up the add-on and adding Japanese translations to our cards. We’ll install an Anki add-on, alter our card-layout to display the Japanese expressions in a fashionable manner, and finally bulk-edit our existing cards to actually add them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="anki-korean-japanese-add-on"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#anki-korean-japanese-add-on"&gt;Anki Korean-Japanese add-on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The add-on scrapes Weblio’s online Korean-Japanese dictionary for all translations aside from the usually present character decomposition. The expression 개 (transcribed as &lt;em&gt;gae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or &lt;em&gt;kae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and means either dog or is used as a particular counter), for example, results in the &lt;a href="http://kjjk.weblio.jp/content/%EA%B0%9C"&gt;following page&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="weblio" class="fborder fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/korean/weblio.jpg" title="weblio"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(If I feel like it, or if there’s some demand for it, I’ll expand the add-on to scrape the example sentences as seen above as well)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="download"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Japanese Definitions for Korean Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt; add-on has a page on Ankiweb’s &lt;a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/553926167"&gt;plug-in page&lt;/a&gt;, but as usual we’ll install the plug-in using the Desktop Anki application. Go to &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Add-ons&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Browse &amp;amp; Install&lt;/strong&gt;, and copy-paste &lt;strong&gt;553926167&lt;/strong&gt; in the pop-up dialog. Restart the application to complete the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The add-on expects two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The field containing your Korean expression should be called: &lt;code&gt;Korean&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The note-type should contain a field called &lt;code&gt;Japanese&lt;/code&gt; which will contain the Japanese translations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Both names can be edited in the &lt;code&gt;JapaneseDefinitionsKoreanVoc.py&lt;/code&gt; file by opening it with a text-editor and changing the names listed in the beginning. The file can be found on the Anki’s add-on folder on your computer (e.g. &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\your_username\Documents\Anki\addons&lt;/code&gt;))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a new field &lt;code&gt;Japanese&lt;/code&gt;, open the …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-15:/blog/2016/10/anki-add-on-japanese-translations-for-korean-vocabulary/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Korean</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 4: Making the switch - J-J definitions in your vocab cards</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/10/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-4-making-the-switch-j-j-definitions-in-your-vocab-cards/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;You’ve been studying Japanese for a while now and reached a level of Japanese adequate enough to understand (simple) texts. Drilling new vocabulary has become a daily routine so entangled in your lifestyle you barely notice anymore. If you were to describe your current level of proficiency, you’d proudly present yourself as an intermediate level learner. Sounds familiar? Let’s take it a notch further by adding Japanese definitions&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to our Anki-sets and reduce our dependency on English definition crutches!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve followed my &lt;a href="#"&gt;previous tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on adding Japanese example sentences to your vocabulary cards, this tutorial will feel very similar: we’ll install an Anki add-on, alter our card-layout to display the definitions in a fashionable manner, and finally bulk-edit our existing cards to actually add them. (This might be my first tutorial worthy of the header &lt;strong&gt;quick&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="sanseido-add-on"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#sanseido-add-on"&gt;Sanseido add-on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various online monolingual dictionaries for Japanese vocabulary. I personally like &lt;a href="http://www.weblio.jp"&gt;Weblio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://dictionary.goo.ne.jp/"&gt;Goo&lt;/a&gt;, but for our Anki cards we’ll use &lt;a href="http://www.sanseido.net/"&gt;Sanseido&lt;/a&gt; - their definitions are usually more concise as the other dictionaries and tend to employ more comprehensible vocabulary. Luck has it someone has already written an anki add-on to serve our blog’s purpose. The result of our work will look as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="anki-gyakuten" class="border fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/anki-gyakuten.jpg" title="anki-gyakuten"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="download"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Sanseido Definitions&lt;/strong&gt; add-on has a page on Ankiweb’s &lt;a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1967553085"&gt;plug-in page&lt;/a&gt;, but as usual we’ll install the plug-in using the Desktop Anki application. Go to &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Add-ons&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Browse &amp;amp; Install&lt;/strong&gt;, and copy-paste &lt;strong&gt;1967553085&lt;/strong&gt; in the pop-up dialog. Restart the application to complete the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The note-types of the vocabulary you want Japanese definitions for will need a new field to contain the definition. On the desktop Anki application, press &lt;kbd&gt;CTRL-SHIFT-N&lt;/kbd&gt;, or click &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Manage Note Types&lt;/strong&gt;, to enter the note-type management screen. Select the note-type of the cards you’d like to contain example sentences and click &lt;strong&gt;fields&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="anki-notetype-select" class="border fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/anki-notetype-select.jpg" title="anki-notetype-select"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next screen, click &lt;strong&gt;add&lt;/strong&gt; and call the field &lt;code&gt;Sanseido&lt;/code&gt;. Now close this screen. On the previous note-type management screen, click &lt;strong&gt;cards&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ll edit our lay-out and display the new field in our cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="anki-note-lay-out"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#anki-note-lay-out"&gt;Anki Note Lay-out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lay-out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the CSS code below to the shared style screen of your note’s card-type template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="normal"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nc"&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;font-size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kt"&gt;px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mh"&gt;#999999&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Templates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the following code below the line displaying your vocabulary’s translation/English definition (eg. &lt;code&gt;{{Meaning}}&lt;/code&gt;) . You’ll do this in &lt;strong&gt;Expression&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Back Template …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-10-02:/blog/2016/10/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-4-making-the-switch-j-j-definitions-in-your-vocab-cards/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 3: contextualize your vocab cards with example sentences</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-3-contextualize-your-vocab-cards-with-example-sentences/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;So you’ve followed &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/"&gt;my previous tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and set up this wonderful environment for creating vocabulary cards with audio and &lt;em&gt;furigana&lt;/em&gt; based on all kinds of Japanese text you find online. Yet, while studying your new set, you feel this nagging feeling deep down inside… There’s something missing, still… “&lt;em&gt;Hm, could it be…?&lt;/em&gt;”, you ponder quietly. &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;. You need &lt;code&gt;Japanese example sentences for providing context to your vocab cards&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the common pitfalls of learning Japanese vocabulary through Anki cards is memorizing them loose of context. Perhaps you’ve found yourself in a situation having no particular problems recalling vocabulary whilst reviewing your cards, but less so when confronted with real-life situations. If that sounds familiar, one way to counter this common problem would be to install an additional Anki add-on, and bring our vocab cards to a next level by adding Japanese example sentences and their translations. This blog offers an easy step-by-step tutorial on setting this up. Additionally, for those who’ve followed my previous tutorial, I add some extra code to combine the example sentence functions with the instant-import features of the Firefox plug-in Rikaisama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="plug-in"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#plug-in"&gt;Plug-in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll use an existing Anki add-on called &lt;strong&gt;Japanese Example Sentences&lt;/strong&gt; to add Japanese sentences taken from &lt;a href="https://tatoeba.org/eng/"&gt;Tatoeba.org&lt;/a&gt;, a “collaborative, open, free and even addictive” community on producing example sentences. The result of our work will look as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="anki-contextcard" class="fborder fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/anki-contextcard.jpg" title="anki-contextcard"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="download"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japanese Example Sentences add-on has a page on Ankiweb’s &lt;a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/2413435972"&gt;plug-in page&lt;/a&gt;, but as usual we’ll install the plug-in using the Desktop Anki application. Go to &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Add-ons&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Browse &amp;amp; Install&lt;/strong&gt;, and copy-paste &lt;strong&gt;2413435972&lt;/strong&gt; in the pop-up dialog. Restart the application to complete the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: as user &lt;em&gt;nwt&lt;/em&gt; mentioned in the comments, this example-set is fairly outdated. Follow &lt;a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/2413435972"&gt;the instructions&lt;/a&gt; left in the plug-in’s comment section to update to the most recent set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a test Anki deck to work with, I’ve uploaded an example set, the result of my previous Anki tutorial, containing the necessary notetype and two test-notes for download: &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/xnj67hqj3cubfn2/Rikai%20vocab.apkg?dl=0"&gt;Example set Rikai &lt;i class="icon-download-alt"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="set-up"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#set-up"&gt;Set-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The note-types of the vocabulary you want sentences for will need a new field to contain these. On the desktop Anki application, press &lt;kbd&gt;CTRL-SHIFT-N&lt;/kbd&gt;, or click &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; → &lt;strong&gt;Manage Note Types&lt;/strong&gt;, to enter the note-type management screen. Select the note-type of the cards you’d like to contain example sentences and click &lt;strong&gt;fields&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="anki-notetype-select" class="border fcenter" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/anki-notetype-select.jpg" title="anki-notetype-select"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next screen …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-17:/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-3-contextualize-your-vocab-cards-with-example-sentences/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>Waarom Japanologie?</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/waarom-japanologie/</link><description>
&lt;!-- PELICAN_START_SUMMARY --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoals velen in mijn richting ontstond mijn interesse in Japan al op jonge leeftijd onder invloed van het zogenaamde &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cool_Japan"&gt;Cool Japan&lt;/a&gt;: de globale verspreiding van Japanse popcultuur (muziek, televisie, games, …) die sinds de jaren ‘80 geleidelijk aan begon door te sijpelen in ook onze nationale media. Het zou, zo blijkt, zelfs een interesse worden die zodanig groeide dat ik er jaren later mijn studiekeuze door liet beïnvloeden. Vaak krijg ik bij vermelding daarvan echter nog, zoals mijn klasgenoten ongetwijfeld kunnen beamen, een hoop verbaasde blikken toegesmeten en dus ook dé klassieke hamvraag voorgeschoteld: &lt;strong&gt;Waarom nu juist Japanologie&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Als tweedejaars werd ik eerder dit jaar gevraagd om op een opendeurdag van onze richting een kort woordje over mijn persoonlijke ervaringen met Japanologie aan de KU Leuven, waar ik aldos ook bovenstaande vraag probeerde te beantwoorden. Toch werd ik daarna door verschillende bezorgde ouders aangesproken met enkele niet geheel onterechte vragen als “&lt;em&gt;Ja maar, wat zijt ge daar nu mee?&lt;/em&gt;”, “&lt;em&gt;Leert ge dan enkel over Japan? Oeioei, is da ni héél beperkt?&lt;/em&gt;” en “&lt;em&gt;Is Japan nog wel relevant?&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Om beter de oorspronkelijke vraag “Waarom Japanologie?” te beantwoorden lijkt het mij het beste om te vertrekken vanuit juist die drie bovenstaande vragen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="vragen"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#vragen"&gt;Vragen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="japanologie-dan-leert-ge-enkel-over-japan-oeioei"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#japanologie-dan-leert-ge-enkel-over-japan-oeioei"&gt;“Japanologie? Dan leert ge enkel over Japan? Oeioei!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Als je naar &lt;a href="https://onderwijsaanbod.kuleuven.be/opleidingen/n/CQ_50268982.htm#activetab=diploma_omschrijving"&gt;de onderwijsaanbod-pagina van Japanologie&lt;/a&gt; aan de KU Leuven gaat krijg je het volgende te zien:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bachelor in de taal- en regiostudies: japanologie (Leuven)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Bachelor of Arts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In de bacheloropleiding Japanologie bestudeer je in de eerste plaats het moderne Japans op een intensieve manier. De opleiding plaatst het Japans steeds centraal tegenover de achtergrond van de Japanse cultuur, geschiedenis, filosofie, economie en politiek. Je kiest een minor, wat je de mogelijkheid geeft om je eigen interesses beter in te werken in je studie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het spreekt voor zich dat de Japanse taal en theoretische vakken gericht op Japan centraal staan in onze richting, maar bovenstaande tekst zegt toch wat meer: Japanologie aan de KU Leuven is een onderdeel van taal- en regiostudies, en levert een &lt;em&gt;Bachelor of Arts&lt;/em&gt; op: een diploma binnen de geestes- of sociale wetenschappen. &lt;span data-pullquote="Concreter betekent dat dat een student Japanologie een hoop vaardigheden onder de knie hoort te krijgen die op eerste zicht geen rechtstreeks verband met Japan lijken te houden maar de student vormt om genuanceerder en meer kritisch te kijken naar niet enkel Japan, maar de hele wereld ."&gt;Concreter betekent dat dat een student Japanologie een hoop vaardigheden onder de knie hoort te krijgen die op eerste zicht geen rechtstreeks verband met Japan lijken te houden maar de student vormt om genuanceerder en meer kritisch te kijken naar niet enkel Japan, maar de hele wereld .&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dat lijkt me ook logisch. Enkel kennis …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-14:/blog/2016/09/waarom-japanologie/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Japanologie</category><category>KU Leuven</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki 2: an efficient vocab mining set-up with Anki and Rikaisama</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 2018~: Rikaisama has been rendered obsolete since 2018 updates broke Firefox’ support of unsigned XUL-based add-ons. Nevertheless, this guide can still prove useful in two ways: further use of Rikaisama through XUL-supporting Firefox-derivatives such as Waterfox, Pale Moon and Basilisk, as well as the list of applications for Browser/Anki-integration listed in the second half of this guide. As I personally use Waterfox, I’ll refer to Waterfox as main option hereafter. Another option is to use Yomichan for Chrome, described &lt;a href="https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2019/04/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-5-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama-yomichan/"&gt;in this updated blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you want to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; read a Japanese novel without ending up crying yourself to sleep realizing you know &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;, Jon Snow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; learn Japanese by watching anime, but like, for real?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class="icon-check"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; create beautiful Anki sets filled with handpicked vocabulary, hidden &lt;em&gt;furigana&lt;/em&gt; reading-aids, AND crystal-clear audio pronunciations, all without spending days of mind-numbing copy-pasting?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the lovely world of &lt;code&gt;Integrated Anki &amp;amp; Rikaisama&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hove-over Japanese dictionary plug-in &lt;strong&gt;Rikaichan&lt;/strong&gt; and its Chrome variant &lt;strong&gt;Rikaikun&lt;/strong&gt; have already been widely established as incredibly helpful tools for reading Japanese online. Nevertheless, one major function remained missing still: a seamless integration with Anki for efficient vocabulary mining. A recent expansion of the original Rikaichan, aptly named &lt;strong&gt;Rikaisama&lt;/strong&gt; (it’s a &lt;em&gt;pun&lt;/em&gt;!), adds several new features including communication with the Anki API, &lt;em&gt;Sanseido Web Dictionary&lt;/em&gt;‘s J-J dictionary definitions, access to &lt;em&gt;J-Pod101&lt;/em&gt;‘s audio-files,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and more.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Concretely, this means audio playback of tens of thousands of words and expressions as well as easy integration of new vocab into Anki. Despite these incredibly useful features, Rikaisama remains fairly  about. To counter that, this blog serves as a brief tutorial on setting up a Rikaisama/Anki environment as well as demonstrating some useful real-life use-cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="rikaisama"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#rikaisama"&gt;Rikaisama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="download"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Rikaichan, Rikaisama is a &lt;del&gt;Firefox&lt;/del&gt; Waterfox plugin, available for download on their &lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/rikaisama/files/"&gt;sourceforge download page&lt;/a&gt; (free, of course). If you’re an avid Chrome supporter, this one might be worth switching for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="rikaisama" class="right" src="https://steviepoppe.net/images/anki/rikaisama.jpg" title="rikaisama"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After installation you’ll have two new buttons at your disposal, either already visible at the top-right of your menubar, or in &lt;del&gt;Firefox&lt;/del&gt; Waterfox’s toolbar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The left one activates Rikaisama. I just leave it permanently open. The right one switches the Rikaisama lookupbar. I don’t use this one often so I hide it in the toolbox myself, but for now we’ll need it to access Rikaisama’s settings. Open the toolbar and click the right-most icon to open …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-08:/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-2-an-efficient-vocab-mining-set-up-with-anki-and-rikaisama/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Rikaisama</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item><item><title>A Quick Guide on Using Anki (effectively) (in an academic context)</title><link>https://steviepoppe.net/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/</link><description>
&lt;p&gt;Those who know me well might accuse me of preaching popular memorization tool &lt;strong&gt;Anki&lt;/strong&gt; as a revolution in studying, and they wouldn’t be that far off. Over the past year I have extensively integrated this software in my studies, with (to me personally) remarkable results in both productivity and academic grades. There are, however, some pitfalls for the casual user to take heed of, and getting the full benefit of your time requires cultivating a proper mindset. Considering the amounts of time I mention Anki abundantly on this site, I decided to write my own  &lt;del&gt;&lt;em&gt;short&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/del&gt; guide on setting up and using Anki efficiently, as well as describe how I’ve personally integrated Anki in my studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone with an interest in studying Japanese will surely have heard of Anki. It’s covered extensively on all major learning resources on-line, and the canonical self learner’s beginner path seems to be that of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Remembering_the_Kanji_and_Remembering_the_Hanzi#Heisig.27s_method"&gt;Heisig’s Kanji method&lt;/a&gt;, Tae Kim’s online &lt;a href="http://www.guidetojapanese.org/learn/grammar"&gt;Grammar Guide&lt;/a&gt;, and Core 2K/6K/10K,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; all three heavily relying on Anki. Language acquisition certainly remains Anki’s most popular usage, although the software has become broad enough to find it’s way in various other branches (it’s become an integrated routine for medical students, for example, as well as math students thanks to LaTeX support). While it sounds like I’m being paid to advertise Anki, the application remains &lt;strong&gt;free and open source&lt;/strong&gt; (and if you don’t like synchronizing your Anki progress over Anki’s servers you could even set that up on your own as well).&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-is-anki-why-is-anki-how-is-anki"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#what-is-anki-why-is-anki-how-is-anki"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&lt;/em&gt; is Anki? &lt;em&gt;Why&lt;/em&gt; is Anki?! &lt;em&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; is Anki?!?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To recap: Anki is an extremely customizable application designed for memorization, available for free on nearly all the major devices&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; as well as being accessible online. Being able to study on the road (I commute by train, taking me up to three hours of total traveling time every day) and synchronizing your progress at home is a major boon on using your time practically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of studies on methods for efficient learning, and not surprisingly, classic late-night cramming, along passive studying methods as extensive marking and rereading of texts don’t score very high. On the other hand, &lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;active recall testing&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (questioning yourself by actively trying to come up with the answer to a question) and &lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;spaced learning&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (spreading information absorption over long …&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Stevie Poppe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:steviepoppe.net,2016-09-07:/blog/2016/09/a-quick-guide-on-using-anki-effectively-in-an-academic-context/</guid><category>Studies</category><category>Anki</category><category>Tutorial</category><category>Japanese</category><category>Studying</category></item></channel></rss>